export const vocabularies = {
  english: [
   { front: "I", back: "ich", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "to be called", back: "heißen", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "have been called", back: "haben geheißen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the name", back: "der Name", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the names", back: "die Namen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "to come", back: "kommen", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "have come", back: "sein gekommen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "Germany", back: "das Deutschland", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "to speak", back: "sprechen", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "have spoken", back: "haben gesprochen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "German (language)", back: "das Deutsch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "and", back: "und", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "a little", back: "ein bisschen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "good day", back: "guten Tag", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "hello", back: "hallo", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "goodbye", back: "auf Wiedersehen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "bye", back: "tschüs", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "the gentleman", back: "der Herr", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the gentlemen", back: "die Herren", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the child", back: "das Kind", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the children", back: "die Kinder", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "good evening", back: "guten Abend", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "the lady", back: "die Dame", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the ladies", back: "die Damen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "welcome", back: "willkommen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "at", back: "bei", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "the music", back: "die Musik", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "international", back: "international", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "good morning", back: "guten Morgen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "the woman", back: "die Frau", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the women", back: "die Frauen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "to thank", back: "danken", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "have thanked", back: "haben gedankt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "good night", back: "gute Nacht", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "the dad", back: "der Papa", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the dads", back: "die Papas", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "to be", back: "sein", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "been", back: "gewesen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the apology", back: "die Entschuldigung", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the apologies", back: "die Entschuldigungen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "how", back: "wie", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "she/they", back: "sie", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "who", back: "wer", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "yes", back: "ja", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "no", back: "nein", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "from where", back: "woher", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "from", back: "aus", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "you (informal)", back: "du", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Austria", back: "Österreich", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Switzerland", back: "die Schweiz", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "ah", back: "aha", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "great", back: "toll", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "interesting", back: "interessant", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "what", back: "was", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "also", back: "auch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "the language", back: "die Sprache", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the languages", back: "die Sprachen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the letter", back: "der Buchstabe", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the letters", back: "die Buchstaben", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the alphabet", back: "das Alphabet", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "excuse me?", back: "wie bitte?", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "to spell", back: "buchstabieren", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "have spelled", back: "haben buchstabiert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "please", back: "bitte", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "the company", back: "die Firma", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the companies", back: "die Firmen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "thank you very much", back: "vielen Dank", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "goodbye (on the phone)", back: "auf Wiederhören", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "the address", back: "die Adresse", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the addresses", back: "die Adressen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the business card", back: "die Visitenkarte", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the business cards", back: "die Visitenkarten", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the first name", back: "der Vorname", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the first names", back: "die Vornamen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the last name", back: "der Familienname", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the last names", back: "die Familiennamen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the street", back: "die Straße", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the streets", back: "die Straßen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the city", back: "die Stadt", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the cities", back: "die Städte", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the country", back: "das Land", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the countries", back: "die Länder", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the email", back: "die E-Mail", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the emails", back: "die E-Mails", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the telephone", back: "das Telefon", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the telephones", back: "die Telefone", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the form", back: "das Formular", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the forms", back: "die Formulare", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the course", back: "der Kurs", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the courses", back: "die Kurse", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the foreign language", back: "die Fremdsprache", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the foreign languages", back: "die Fremdsprachen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the registration", back: "die Anmeldung", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the registrations", back: "die Anmeldungen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "the postal code", back: "die Postleitzahl", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "the postal codes", back: "die Postleitzahlen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "learn words", back: "lernen Sie Wörter", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Turkish", back: "türkisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "German", back: "deutsch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Poland", back: "Polen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Polish", back: "polnisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Turkey", back: "die Türkei", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Spain", back: "Spanien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Hungary", back: "Ungarn", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Germany", back: "Deutschland", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Austria", back: "Österreich", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Turkish", back: "türkisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Spanish", back: "spanisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Hungarian", back: "ungarisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "German", back: "deutsch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Switzerland", back: "die Schweiz", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Romania", back: "Rumänien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Syria", back: "Syrien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Bulgaria", back: "Bulgarien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Italy", back: "Italien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Greece", back: "Griechenland", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Romanian", back: "rumänisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Arabic", back: "arabisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Bulgarian", back: "bulgarisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Italian", back: "italienisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Greek", back: "griechisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "to learn", back: "lernen", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "have learned", back: "haben gelernt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the park", back: "der Park", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the parks", back: "die Parks", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the break", back: "die Pause", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the breaks", back: "die Pausen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the family", back: "die Familie", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the families", back: "die Familien", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the father", back: "der Vater", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the fathers", back: "die Väter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the grandparents", back: "die Großeltern", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the mother", back: "die Mutter", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the mothers", back: "die Mütter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the parents", back: "die Eltern", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the brother", back: "der Bruder", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the brothers", back: "die Brüder", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the siblings", back: "die Geschwister", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the year", back: "das Jahr", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the years", back: "die Jahre", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "to live", back: "leben", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "have lived", back: "haben gelebt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "in", back: "in", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "good", back: "gut", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "super", back: "super", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "well, okay", back: "na ja", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "oh", back: "ach", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "so", back: "so", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "very", back: "sehr", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the grandson", back: "der Enkel", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the grandsons", back: "die Enkel", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the granddaughter", back: "die Enkelin", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the granddaughters", back: "die Enkelinnen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the daughter", back: "die Tochter", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the daughters", back: "die Töchter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the son", back: "der Sohn", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the sons", back: "die Söhne", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the sister", back: "die Schwester", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the sisters", back: "die Schwestern", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the grandmother", back: "die Oma", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the grandmothers", back: "die Omas", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the man", back: "der Mann", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the men", back: "die Männer", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the grandfather", back: "der Opa", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the grandfathers", back: "die Opas", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "your (informal)", back: "dein", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "my", back: "mein", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "her/its (formal)", back: "ihr", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the husband", back: "der Ehemann", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the husbands", back: "die Ehemänner", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the wife", back: "die Ehefrau", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the wives", back: "die Ehefrauen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "wrong", back: "falsch", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "she/they", back: "sie", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "together", back: "zusammen", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "they", back: "sie", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "divorced", back: "geschieden", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "he", back: "er", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "to live", back: "wohnen", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "have lived", back: "haben gewohnt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "now", back: "jetzt", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "your (plural/formal)", back: "ihr", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "we", back: "wir", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the number", back: "die Zahl", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the numbers", back: "die Zahlen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "where", back: "wo", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "born", back: "geboren", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the number", back: "die Nummer", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the numbers", back: "die Nummern", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "married", back: "verheiratet", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "to have", back: "haben", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "have had", back: "haben gehabt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the place of birth", back: "der Geburtsort", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the places of birth", back: "die Geburtsorte", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the place of residence", back: "der Wohnort", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the places of residence", back: "die Wohnorte", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "marital status", back: "der Familienstand", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "single", back: "ledig", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "widowed", back: "verwitwet", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the age", back: "das Alter", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the ages", back: "die Alter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the north", back: "der Norden", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the east", back: "der Osten", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the south", back: "der Süden", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the west", back: "der Westen", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the capital city", back: "die Hauptstadt", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the capital cities", back: "die Hauptstädte", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "south", back: "Süd", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "north", back: "Nord", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "the teacher (male)", back: "der Lehrer", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the teachers (male)", back: "die Lehrer", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the teacher (female)", back: "die Lehrerin", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the teachers (female)", back: "die Lehrerinnen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the German (male)", back: "der Deutsche", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the Germans (male)", back: "die Deutschen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the German (female)", back: "die Deutsche", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "the Germans (female)", back: "die Deutschen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "the banana", back: "die Banane", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the bananas", back: "die Bananen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the butter", back: "die Butter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the egg", back: "das Ei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the eggs", back: "die Eier", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the flour", back: "das Mehl", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the milk", back: "die Milch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the sugar", back: "der Zucker", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the pancake", back: "der Pfannkuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the pancakes", back: "die Pfannkuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the chocolate", back: "die Schokolade", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "to need / to use", back: "brauchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "have needed / have used", back: "haben gebraucht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to buy", back: "kaufen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "have bought", back: "haben gekauft", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the hunger", back: "der Hunger", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the euro", back: "der Euro", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the meat", back: "das Fleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the beer", back: "das Bier", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the cheese", back: "der Käse", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the salt", back: "das Salz", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the tea", back: "der Tee", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the teas", back: "die Tees", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the bread", back: "das Brot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the breads / loaves", back: "die Brote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the wine", back: "der Wein", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the wines", back: "die Weine", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the mineral water", back: "das Mineralwasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the rice", back: "der Reis", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the fish", back: "der Fisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the fishes", back: "die Fische", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "a / one", back: "ein", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "no / none / not any", back: "kein", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the apple", back: "der Apfel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the apples", back: "die Äpfel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the orange", back: "die Orange", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the oranges", back: "die Orangen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the cake", back: "der Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the cakes", back: "die Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the coffee", back: "der Kaffee", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the coffees", back: "die Kaffees", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the juice", back: "der Saft", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the juices", back: "die Säfte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the roll / bread roll", back: "das Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the rolls", back: "die Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the sausage (diminutive)", back: "das Würstchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the little sausages", back: "die Würstchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the pear", back: "die Birne", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the pears", back: "die Birnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the tomato", back: "die Tomate", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the tomatoes", back: "die Tomaten", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the potato", back: "die Kartoffel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the potatoes", back: "die Kartoffeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the yogurt", back: "der Joghurt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the yogurts", back: "die Joghurts", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the onion", back: "die Zwiebel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the onions", back: "die Zwiebeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the shelf / shelving", back: "das Regal", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the shelves", back: "die Regale", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the price", back: "der Preis", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the prices", back: "die Preise", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the cent", back: "der Cent", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the brochure / prospectus", back: "der Prospekt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the brochures", back: "die Prospekte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the special offer / sale", back: "das Sonderangebot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the special offers", back: "die Sonderangebote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the (single) food item / grocery", back: "das Lebensmittel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the groceries / food items", back: "die Lebensmittel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "how much / how many", back: "wie viel", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "to cost", back: "kosten", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "have cost", back: "haben gekostet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the kilo(gram)", back: "das Kilo(gramm)", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the gram", back: "das Gramm", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the pound", back: "das Pfund", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the liter", back: "der Liter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the bottle", back: "die Flasche", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the bottles", back: "die Flaschen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the can / tin / dose", back: "die Dose", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the cans / tins", back: "die Dosen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the cream", back: "die Sahne", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the sausage", back: "die Wurst", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the sausages", back: "die Würste", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the minced meat / ground meat", back: "das Hackfleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the (male) seller / vendor", back: "der Verkäufer", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the (male) sellers", back: "die Verkäufer", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the (female) seller / vendor", back: "die Verkäuferin", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the (female) sellers", back: "die Verkäuferinnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the (male) customer", back: "der Kunde", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the (male) customers", back: "die Kunden", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the (female) customer", back: "die Kundin", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the (female) customers", back: "die Kundinnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "still / yet / in addition", back: "noch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "all / every", back: "all", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "would like", back: "möchten", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "have wished / have desired", back: "haben gewünscht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to find", back: "finden", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "have found", back: "haben gefunden", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the shop / store", back: "der Laden", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the shops / stores", back: "die Läden", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the fruit", back: "das Obst", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the vegetable(s)", back: "das Gemüse", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the vegetables", back: "die Gemüse", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the bakery", back: "die Bäckerei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the bakeries", back: "die Bäckereien", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the water", back: "das Wasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the pepper", back: "der Pfeffer", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the chocolate", back: "die Schokolade", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the banana", back: "die Banane", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the bananas", back: "die Bananen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the butter", back: "die Butter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the egg", back: "das Ei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the eggs", back: "die Eier", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the milk", back: "die Milch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the bread", back: "das Brot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the breads / loaves", back: "die Brote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the fish", back: "der Fisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the fishes", back: "die Fische", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the meat", back: "das Fleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the cheese", back: "der Käse", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the apple", back: "der Apfel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the apples", back: "die Äpfel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the pear", back: "die Birne", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the pears", back: "die Birnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the roll / bread roll", back: "das Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the rolls", back: "die Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the cake", back: "der Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the cakes", back: "die Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the orange", back: "die Orange", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the oranges", back: "die Orangen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the juice", back: "der Saft", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the juices", back: "die Säfte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the yogurt", back: "der / das Joghurt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the yogurts", back: "die Joghurts", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the potato", back: "die Kartoffel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the potatoes", back: "die Kartoffeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the onion", back: "die Zwiebel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the onions", back: "die Zwiebeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the tomato", back: "die Tomate", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "the tomatoes", back: "die Tomaten", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "the mineral water", back: "das Mineralwasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "the apartment", back: "die Wohnung", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the apartments", back: "die Wohnungen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the lamp", back: "die Lampe", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the lamps", back: "die Lampen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the room", back: "das Zimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the rooms", back: "die Zimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the kitchen", back: "die Küche", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the kitchens", back: "die Küchen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the bathroom", back: "das Bad", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the bathrooms", back: "die Bäder", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "old", back: "alt", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "new", back: "neu", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "big / large", back: "groß", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "small", back: "klein", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "bright / light", back: "hell", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "dark", back: "dunkel", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "expensive", back: "teuer", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "cheap", back: "billig", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "beautiful / nice", back: "schön", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "ugly", back: "hässlich", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "to know (someone/place)", back: "kennen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "have known", back: "haben gekannt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the hallway / corridor", back: "der Flur", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the hallways", back: "die Flure", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the toilet", back: "die Toilette", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the toilets", back: "die Toiletten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the balcony", back: "der Balkon", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the balconies", back: "die Balkone", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the living room", back: "das Wohnzimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the living rooms", back: "die Wohnzimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the (m/f/n)", back: "der / das / die", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the house", back: "das Haus", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the houses", back: "die Häuser", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "here", back: "hier", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "there", back: "dort", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "but", back: "aber", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "not", back: "nicht", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the month", back: "der Monat", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the months", back: "die Monate", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "narrow", back: "schmal", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "correct / right", back: "richtig", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "wide", back: "breit", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the cupboard / closet", back: "der Schrank", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the cupboards", back: "die Schränke", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the refrigerator", back: "der Kühlschrank", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the refrigerators", back: "die Kühlschränke", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the sofa", back: "das Sofa", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the sofas", back: "die Sofas", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the table", back: "der Tisch", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the tables", back: "die Tische", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the chair", back: "der Stuhl", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the chairs", back: "die Stühle", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the bed", back: "das Bett", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the beds", back: "die Betten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the TV", back: "der Fernseher", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the TVs", back: "die Fernseher", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the shower", back: "die Dusche", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the showers", back: "die Duschen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the stove / cooker", back: "der Herd", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the stoves", back: "die Herde", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the bathtub", back: "die Badewanne", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the bathtubs", back: "die Badewannen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the carpet / rug", back: "der Teppich", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the carpets", back: "die Teppiche", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the armchair", back: "der Sessel", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the armchairs", back: "die Sessel", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the furniture", back: "die Möbel", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the device / appliance", back: "das Gerät", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the devices", back: "die Geräte", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "to please", back: "gefallen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "have pleased", back: "haben gefallen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the color", back: "die Farbe", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the colors", back: "die Farben", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "to find", back: "finden", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "have found", back: "haben gefunden", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "whole / very / quite", back: "ganz", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "modern", back: "modern", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "black", back: "schwarz", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "gray", back: "grau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "white", back: "weiß", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "green", back: "grün", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "brown", back: "braun", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "blue", back: "blau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "red", back: "rot", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "yellow", back: "gelb", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "light- (color)", back: "hell-", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "dark- (color)", back: "dunkel-", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the centimeter", back: "der Zentimeter", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the centimeters", back: "die Zentimeter", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "times (×) / once / just", back: "mal", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the mobile phone", back: "das Handy", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the mobile phones", back: "die Handys", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the work / job", back: "die Arbeit", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the advertisement", back: "die Anzeige", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the advertisements", back: "die Anzeigen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "nice / kind", back: "nett", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the married couple", back: "das Ehepaar", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the married couples", back: "die Ehepaare", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "to search / look for", back: "suchen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "have searched", back: "haben gesucht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the garden", back: "der Garten", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the gardens", back: "die Gärten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "to rent out", back: "vermieten", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "have rented out", back: "haben vermietet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the apartment", back: "das Apartment", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the apartments", back: "die Apartments", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the room / space", back: "der Raum", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the rooms / spaces", back: "die Räume", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the floor (level)", back: "der Stock", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "approximately / about", back: "circa", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "private", back: "privat", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "brown", back: "braun", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "blue", back: "blau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "red", back: "rot", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "yellow", back: "gelb", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "colors", back: "Farben", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "from / starting at", back: "ab", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "immediately / right away", back: "sofort", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "maximum", back: "maximal", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the call", back: "der Anruf", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the calls", back: "die Anrufe", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "furnished", back: "möbliert", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the TV (device)", back: "das TV", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the TVs", back: "die TVs", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the garage", back: "die Garage", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the garages", back: "die Garagen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the square meter", back: "der Quadratmeter", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the square meters", back: "die Quadratmeter", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "only", back: "nur", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the rent", back: "die Miete", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the rents", back: "die Mieten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "to pay", back: "bezahlen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "have paid", back: "haben bezahlt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to sell", back: "verkaufen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "have sold", back: "haben verkauft", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "something / some", back: "etwas", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the computer", back: "der Computer", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the computers", back: "die Computer", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "the desk", back: "der Schreibtisch", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the desks", back: "die Schreibtische", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "today", back: "heute", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "which …?", back: "welche …?", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "so / therefore / well then", back: "also", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "approximately", back: "ungefähr", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "the meter", back: "der Meter", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "the meters", back: "die Meter", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "long", back: "lang", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "exact / exactly", back: "genau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "to see", back: "sehen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "have seen", back: "haben gesehen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "high / tall", back: "hoch", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "tomorrow", back: "morgen", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "to do / to make", back: "machen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have done / made", back: "haben gemacht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the presentation", back: "die Präsentation", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the presentations", back: "die Präsentationen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "to have breakfast", back: "frühstücken", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have had breakfast", back: "haben gefrühstückt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to shop", back: "einkaufen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have shopped", back: "haben eingekauft", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to hear / to listen", back: "hören", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have heard", back: "haben gehört", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to cook", back: "kochen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have cooked", back: "haben gekocht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to go for a walk", back: "spazieren gehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have gone for a walk", back: "sein spaziert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to tidy up", back: "aufräumen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have tidied up", back: "haben aufgeräumt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to get up", back: "aufstehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have gotten up", back: "sein aufgestanden", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to go", back: "gehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have gone", back: "sein gegangen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "or", back: "oder", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "tired", back: "müde", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "to call (on the phone)", back: "anrufen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have called", back: "haben angerufen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "early", back: "früh", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the supermarket", back: "der Supermarkt", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the supermarkets", back: "die Supermärkte", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "to watch TV", back: "fernsehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have watched TV", back: "haben ferngesehen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "with", back: "mit", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "to work", back: "arbeiten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have worked", back: "haben gearbeitet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "long (time)", back: "lange", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "to play", back: "spielen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have played", back: "haben gespielt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to eat", back: "essen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have eaten", back: "haben gegessen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "gladly / like to", back: "gern", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "late", back: "spät", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "already", back: "schon", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "only / just", back: "erst", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the quarter (time or district)", back: "das Viertel", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the quarters", back: "die Viertel", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "before / to (time)", back: "vor", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "after / past (time)", back: "nach", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "half (past)", back: "halb", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the clock / o’clock", back: "die Uhr", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the clocks", back: "die Uhren", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "shortly / briefly", back: "kurz", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "soon / right away", back: "gleich", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the intensive course", back: "der Intensivkurs", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the intensive courses", back: "die Intensivkurse", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "to begin", back: "anfangen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have begun", back: "haben angefangen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "on the (with days)", back: "am", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "Monday", back: "der Montag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "Mondays", back: "die Montage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "Friday", back: "der Freitag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "Fridays", back: "die Freitage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "Thursday", back: "der Donnerstag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "Thursdays", back: "die Donnerstage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "Wednesday", back: "der Mittwoch", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "Wednesdays", back: "die Mittwoche", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "Tuesday", back: "der Dienstag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "Tuesdays", back: "die Dienstage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "when", back: "wann", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "at (with time)", back: "um", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "to end / to finish", back: "enden", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have ended", back: "haben geendet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "from … to …", back: "von … bis …", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the party", back: "die Party", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the parties", back: "die Partys", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the time", back: "die Zeit", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the times", back: "die Zeiten", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the football / soccer", back: "der Fußball", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "Saturday", back: "der Samstag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "Saturdays", back: "die Samstage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "Sunday", back: "der Sonntag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "Sundays", back: "die Sonntage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the homework", back: "die Hausaufgabe", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the homework (plural)", back: "die Hausaufgaben", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the mom", back: "die Mama", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the moms", back: "die Mamas", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "to sleep", back: "schlafen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have slept", back: "haben geschlafen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the weekend", back: "das Wochenende", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the weekends", back: "die Wochenenden", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "next", back: "nächst-", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the week", back: "die Woche", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the weeks", back: "die Wochen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the noon", back: "der Mittag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the noons", back: "die Mittage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the morning", back: "der Morgen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the mornings", back: "die Morgen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the evening", back: "der Abend", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the evenings", back: "die Abende", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the afternoon", back: "der Nachmittag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the afternoons", back: "die Nachmittage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the morning (before noon)", back: "der Vormittag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the late mornings", back: "die Vormittage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the night", back: "die Nacht", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the nights", back: "die Nächte", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the cinema", back: "das Kino", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the cinemas", back: "die Kinos", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the sport", back: "der Sport", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "to drink", back: "trinken", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have drunk", back: "haben getrunken", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the pizza", back: "die Pizza", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the pizzas", back: "die Pizzen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "to chat", back: "chatten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have chatted", back: "haben gechattet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "open / opened", back: "geöffnet", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the appointment", back: "der Termin", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the appointments", back: "die Termine", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the kindergarten", back: "der Kindergarten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the kindergartens", back: "die Kindergärten", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the store / shop / business", back: "das Geschäft", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the stores", back: "die Geschäfte", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the library", back: "die Bibliothek", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the libraries", back: "die Bibliotheken", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "closed", back: "geschlossen", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "to open", back: "öffnen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have opened", back: "haben geöffnet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to close", back: "schließen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have closed", back: "haben geschlossen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the (medical) practice / office", back: "die Praxis", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the practices", back: "die Praxen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the day", back: "der Tag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the days", back: "die Tage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "every", back: "jed-", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the daycare center", back: "die Kita", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the daycare centers", back: "die Kitas", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "to bring", back: "bringen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have brought", back: "haben gebracht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to pick up", back: "abholen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have picked up", back: "haben abgeholt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "more", back: "mehr", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the example", back: "das Beispiel", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the examples", back: "die Beispiele", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "for example", back: "zum Beispiel", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "again", back: "wieder", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the (male) friend", back: "der Freund", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the (male) friends", back: "die Freunde", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "the (female) friend", back: "die Freundin", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "the (female) friends", back: "die Freundinnen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "to ask", back: "fragen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have asked", back: "haben gefragt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to answer", back: "antworten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "have answered", back: "haben geantwortet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "totally / completely", back: "total", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "the excursion / trip", back: "der Ausflug", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the excursions / trips", back: "die Ausflüge", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the car", back: "das Auto", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the cars", back: "die Autos", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "to hike", back: "wandern", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have hiked", back: "sein gewandert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the picnic", back: "das Picknick", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the picnics", back: "die Picknicks", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the guitar", back: "die Gitarre", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the guitars", back: "die Gitarren", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "to talk on the phone", back: "telefonieren", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have talked on the phone", back: "haben telefoniert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the weather", back: "das Wetter", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the sun", back: "die Sonne", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "to shine", back: "scheinen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have shone", back: "haben geschienen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to rain", back: "regnen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have rained", back: "haben geregnet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "much / many", back: "viel-", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the cloud", back: "die Wolke", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the clouds", back: "die Wolken", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "to start / to leave", back: "los (losgehen)", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "to forget", back: "vergessen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have forgotten", back: "haben vergessen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the thirst", back: "der Durst", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the degree (temperature)", back: "das Grad", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "warm", back: "warm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "windy", back: "windig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "cold", back: "kalt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "to snow", back: "schneien", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have snowed", back: "haben geschneit", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "cloudy / overcast", back: "bewölkt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the weather report", back: "der Wetterbericht", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the weather reports", back: "die Wetterberichte", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the middle / center", back: "die Mitte", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "everywhere", back: "überall", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the temperature", back: "die Temperatur", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the temperatures", back: "die Temperaturen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "to rise", back: "steigen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have risen", back: "sein gestiegen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "sunny", back: "sonnig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "light / easy", back: "leicht", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "to stay", back: "bleiben", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have stayed", back: "sein geblieben", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the rain", back: "der Regen", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the snow", back: "der Schnee", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "plus", back: "plus", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "minus", back: "minus", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the radio", back: "das Radio", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the radios", back: "die Radios", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the internet", back: "das Internet", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the summer", back: "der Sommer", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the summers", back: "die Sommer", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "hot", back: "heiß", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the spring", back: "der Frühling", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the springs", back: "die Frühlinge", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the autumn / fall", back: "der Herbst", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the autumns", back: "die Herbste", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "bad", back: "schlecht", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the winter", back: "der Winter", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the winters", back: "die Winter", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the wind", back: "der Wind", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the winds", back: "die Winde", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "pleasant / comfortable", back: "angenehm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the menu", back: "die Speisekarte", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the menus", back: "die Speisekarten", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the hamburger", back: "der Hamburger", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the hamburgers", back: "die Hamburger", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the dish / meal", back: "die Speise", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the dishes", back: "die Speisen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the French fries", back: "die Pommes frites", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the portion / serving", back: "die Portion", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the portions", back: "die Portionen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the ketchup", back: "der Ketchup", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the ketchups", back: "die Ketchups", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the salad", back: "der Salat", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the salads", back: "die Salate", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the ham", back: "der Schinken", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the hams", back: "die Schinken", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the drink / beverage", back: "das Getränk", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the drinks", back: "die Getränke", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the cola", back: "die Cola", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the colas", back: "die Colas", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "but / however / after all", back: "doch", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "rather / prefer to", back: "lieber", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "to take", back: "nehmen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have taken", back: "haben genommen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "why", back: "warum", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the dog", back: "der Hund", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the dogs", back: "die Hunde", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the ice / ice cream", back: "das Eis", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "to dance", back: "tanzen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have danced", back: "haben getanzt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to swim", back: "schwimmen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have swum", back: "sein geschwommen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to meet", back: "treffen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have met", back: "haben getroffen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the bicycle", back: "das Fahrrad", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the bicycles", back: "die Fahrräder", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "to drive / to ride", back: "fahren", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have driven / ridden", back: "sein gefahren", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to grill / barbecue", back: "grillen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have grilled", back: "haben gegrillt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the free time", back: "die Freizeit", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the hobby", back: "das Hobby", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the hobbies", back: "die Hobbys", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "to read", back: "lesen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have read", back: "haben gelesen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the crime novel / thriller", back: "der Krimi", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the crime novels", back: "die Krimis", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "favorite- (prefix)", back: "Lieblings-", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the film / movie", back: "der Film", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the films / movies", back: "die Filme", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "important", back: "wichtig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the grill / barbecue", back: "der Grill", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the grills", back: "die Grills", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "to collect", back: "sammeln", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have collected", back: "haben gesammelt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the profession / job", back: "der Beruf", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the professions", back: "die Berufe", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the photo", back: "das Foto", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the photos", back: "die Fotos", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "especially / particularly", back: "besonders", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "to photograph", back: "fotografieren", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have photographed", back: "haben fotografiert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the fun", back: "der Spaß", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the smartphone", back: "das Smartphone", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the smartphones", back: "die Smartphones", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "stupid / silly", back: "dumm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "often", back: "oft", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "to mean / to think", back: "meinen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "have thought / meant", back: "haben gemeint", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the dice / cube", back: "der Würfel", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the dice / cubes", back: "die Würfel", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "the game", back: "das Spiel", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the games", back: "die Spiele", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "unfortunately", back: "leider", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the problem", back: "das Problem", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the problems", back: "die Probleme", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "always", back: "immer", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "maybe / perhaps", back: "vielleicht", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "simple / easy", back: "einfach", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "fast / quickly", back: "schnell", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the sun", back: "die Sonne", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the suns", back: "die Sonnen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "It is sunny.", back: "Es ist sonnig.", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the rain", back: "der Regen", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "It is raining.", back: "Es regnet.", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the cloud", back: "die Wolke", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the clouds", back: "die Wolken", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "it is cloudy", back: "es ist bewölkt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the snow", back: "der Schnee", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "it is snowing", back: "es schneit", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "the wind", back: "der Wind", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "the winds", back: "die Winde", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "it is windy", back: "es ist windig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "it is cold", back: "es ist kalt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "it is warm", back: "es ist warm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "great / excellent", back: "prima", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "the team", back: "das Team", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the teams", back: "die Teams", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to wake (someone) up", back: "wecken", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have woken (someone) up", back: "haben geweckt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the breakfast", back: "das Frühstück", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the breakfasts", back: "die Frühstücke", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "ready / finished", back: "fertig", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "to be going on", back: "los sein", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "to write", back: "schreiben", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have written", back: "haben geschrieben", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "mathematics", back: "die Mathematik", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "the test", back: "der Test", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the tests", back: "die Tests", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "punctual / on time", back: "pünktlich", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "under no/every circumstance", back: "auf keinen/jeden Fall", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "to taste", back: "schmecken", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have tasted", back: "haben geschmeckt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "(to) home", back: "nach Hause", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "the school", back: "die Schule", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the schools", back: "die Schulen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to be able to / can", back: "können", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have been able to", back: "haben gekonnt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "sick / ill", back: "krank", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "the (male) doctor", back: "der Arzt", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the doctors", back: "die Ärzte", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the (female) doctor", back: "die Ärztin", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the doctors", back: "die Ärztinnen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to bake", back: "backen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have baked", back: "haben gebacken", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to sing", back: "singen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have sung", back: "haben gesungen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to ride (a horse)", back: "reiten", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have ridden", back: "sein geritten", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the piano", back: "das Klavier", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the pianos", back: "die Klaviere", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to paint / to draw", back: "malen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have painted", back: "haben gemalt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the ski", back: "der Ski", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the skis", back: "die Skier", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "(to play) tennis", back: "das Tennis (spielen)", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "to want", back: "wollen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have wanted", back: "haben gewollt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "finally", back: "endlich", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "the song", back: "das Lied", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the songs", back: "die Lieder", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to practice", back: "üben", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have practiced", back: "haben geübt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the text", back: "der Text", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the texts", back: "die Texte", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the exercise", back: "die Übung", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the exercises", back: "die Übungen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the letter", back: "der Brief", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the letters", back: "die Briefe", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the dictation", back: "das Diktat", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the dictations", back: "die Diktate", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the book", back: "das Buch", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "the books", back: "die Bücher", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to play guitar", back: "Gitarre spielen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have played guitar", back: "haben Gitarre gespielt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to ride a bicycle", back: "Fahrrad fahren", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have ridden a bike", back: "sein Fahrrad gefahren", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to meet friends", back: "Freunde treffen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have met", back: "haben getroffen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to ski", back: "Ski fahren", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have skied", back: "sein Ski gefahren", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "to play tennis", back: "Tennis spielen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "have played tennis", back: "haben Tennis gespielt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "the story / history", back: "die Geschichte", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the stories", back: "die Geschichten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the hospital", back: "das Krankenhaus", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the hospitals", back: "die Krankenhäuser", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the interview", back: "das Interview", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the interviews", back: "die Interviews", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the newspaper", back: "die Zeitung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the newspapers", back: "die Zeitungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the television / TV", back: "das Fernsehen", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the training / education", back: "die Ausbildung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the trainings", back: "die Ausbildungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) boss", back: "der Chef", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the bosses", back: "die Chefs", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) boss", back: "die Chefin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the bosses", back: "die Chefinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) patient", back: "der Patient", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the patients", back: "die Patienten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) patient", back: "die Patientin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the patients", back: "die Patientinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) janitor / caretaker", back: "der Hausmeister", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the caretakers", back: "die Hausmeister", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) janitor", back: "die Hausmeisterin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the caretakers", back: "die Hausmeisterinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) journalist", back: "der Journalist", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the journalists", back: "die Journalisten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) journalist", back: "die Journalistin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the journalists", back: "die Journalistinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the topic / theme", back: "das Thema", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the topics", back: "die Themen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) mechatronic technician", back: "der Mechatroniker", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the technicians", back: "die Mechatroniker", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) mechatronic technician", back: "die Mechatronikerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the technicians", back: "die Mechatronikerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the househusband", back: "der Hausmann", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the househusbands", back: "die Hausmänner", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the housewife", back: "die Hausfrau", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the housewives", back: "die Hausfrauen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) police officer", back: "der Polizist", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the officers", back: "die Polizisten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) police officer", back: "die Polizistin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the officers", back: "die Polizistinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) nurse", back: "der Krankenpfleger", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the nurses", back: "die Krankenschwestern", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) nurse", back: "die Krankenschwester", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the nurses", back: "die Krankenschwestern", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "professionally", back: "beruflich", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the (male) pupil", back: "der Schüler", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the pupils", back: "die Schüler", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) pupil", back: "die Schülerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the pupils", back: "die Schülerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) student", back: "der Student", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the students", back: "die Studenten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) student", back: "die Studentin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the students", back: "die Studentinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "to study (university)", back: "studieren", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "have studied", back: "haben studiert", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the job", back: "der Job", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the jobs", back: "die Jobs", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the position / job", back: "die Stelle", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the positions", back: "die Stellen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "self-employed", back: "selbstständig", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "employed", back: "berufstätig", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "unemployed", back: "arbeitslos", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "currently / at the moment", back: "zurzeit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the (male) taxi driver", back: "der Taxifahrer", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the drivers", back: "die Taxifahrer", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) taxi driver", back: "die Taxifahrerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the drivers", back: "die Taxifahrerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "to last / to take (time)", back: "dauern", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "have lasted", back: "haben gedauert", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "since", back: "seit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the application", back: "die Bewerbung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the applications", back: "die Bewerbungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the internship", back: "das Praktikum", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the internships", back: "die Praktika", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the department", back: "die Abteilung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the departments", back: "die Abteilungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) manager", back: "der Leiter", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the managers", back: "die Leiter", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) manager", back: "die Leiterin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the managers", back: "die Leiterinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "honored / respected", back: "geehrt", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the economy", back: "die Wirtschaft", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the diploma / degree", back: "das Diplom", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the diplomas", back: "die Diplome", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "just / right now", back: "gerade", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the office", back: "das Büro", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the offices", back: "die Büros", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the information", back: "die Information", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the information (plural)", back: "die Informationen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the greeting", back: "der Gruß", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the greetings", back: "die Grüße", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "to marry", back: "heiraten", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "have married", back: "haben geheiratet", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "actually / really", back: "eigentlich", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "later", back: "später", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the (male) tour guide", back: "der Reiseführer", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the guides", back: "die Reiseführer", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) tour guide", back: "die Reiseführerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the guides", back: "die Reiseführerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) tourist", back: "der Tourist", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the tourists", back: "die Touristen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) tourist", back: "die Touristin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the tourists", back: "die Touristinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "to show", back: "zeigen", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "have shown", back: "haben gezeigt", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the work experience", back: "die Berufserfahrung", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the café", back: "das Café", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the cafés", back: "die Cafés", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the stress", back: "der Stress", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "sometimes", back: "manchmal", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the (male) waiter", back: "der Kellner", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the waiters", back: "die Kellner", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) waitress", back: "die Kellnerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the waitresses", back: "die Kellnerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the restaurant", back: "das Restaurant", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the restaurants", back: "die Restaurants", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) architect", back: "der Architekt", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the architects", back: "die Architekten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) architect", back: "die Architektin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the architects", back: "die Architektinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) cook", back: "der Koch", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the cooks", back: "die Köche", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) cook", back: "die Köchin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the cooks", back: "die Köchinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) worker", back: "der Arbeiter", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the workers", back: "die Arbeiter", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) worker", back: "die Arbeiterin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the workers", back: "die Arbeiterinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "little / few", back: "wenig", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the (male) colleague", back: "der Kollege", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the colleagues", back: "die Kollegen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) colleague", back: "die Kollegin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the colleagues", back: "die Kolleginnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the foreign countries / abroad", back: "das Ausland", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "other / different", back: "ander-", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the workplace", back: "der Arbeitsplatz", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the workplaces", back: "die Arbeitsplätze", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the dream", back: "der Traum", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the dreams", back: "die Träume", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "dream- (prefix, e.g. dream job)", back: "traum-", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "during the day", back: "tagsüber", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "three times", back: "dreimal", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "to receive / get", back: "bekommen", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "have received", back: "haben bekommen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (male) secretary", back: "der Sekretär", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the secretaries", back: "die Sekretäre", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the (female) secretary", back: "die Sekretärin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the secretaries", back: "die Sekretärinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the university", back: "die Universität", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the universities", back: "die Universitäten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "temporary / fixed-term", back: "befristet", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "full-time work", back: "die Vollzeit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "part-time work", back: "die Teilzeit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "all day / full-time", back: "ganztags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "half-day / part-time", back: "halbtags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "in the mornings", back: "vormittags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "in the afternoons", back: "nachmittags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "private tutoring", back: "die Nachhilfe", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "on Mondays", back: "montags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "on Thursdays", back: "donnerstags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the (male) senior / elderly person", back: "der Senior", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the seniors", back: "die Senioren", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "senior- (prefix, e.g. Seniorenheim)", back: "senioren-", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the temporary help / assistant", back: "die Aushilfe", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the assistants", back: "die Aushilfen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "urgent(ly)", back: "dringend", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the service", back: "der Service", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "in the evenings", back: "abends", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "on Tuesdays", back: "dienstags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "on Wednesdays", back: "mittwochs", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "on Fridays", back: "freitags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "on Sundays", back: "sonntags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "to pay", back: "zahlen", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "have paid", back: "haben gezahlt", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "per / for each", back: "pro", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the hour", back: "die Stunde", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the hours", back: "die Stunden", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "the demand / inquiry", back: "die Nachfrage", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "the inquiries / demands", back: "die Nachfragen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "free / available", back: "frei", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "each / respectively", back: "jeweils", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "on Saturdays", back: "samstags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "the driver's license", back: "der Führerschein", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the driver's licenses", back: "die Führerscheine", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the ticket", back: "das Ticket", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the tickets", back: "die Tickets", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the office, the authority", back: "das Amt", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the offices, the authorities", back: "die Ämter", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "valid", back: "gültig", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "to rent", back: "mieten", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have rented", back: "haben gemietet", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "foreign", back: "ausländisch", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "European", back: "europäisch", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the European Union", back: "die Europäische Union", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "young", back: "jung", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the trip", back: "die Fahrt", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the trips", back: "die Fahrten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the ticket", back: "die Fahrkarte", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the tickets", back: "die Fahrkarten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the application", back: "der Antrag", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the applications", back: "die Anträge", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "must, to have to", back: "müssen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have had to", back: "haben gemusst", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to fill out", back: "ausfüllen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have filled out", back: "haben ausgefüllt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the ID card", back: "der Ausweis", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the ID cards", back: "die Ausweise", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to bring along", back: "mitbringen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have brought along", back: "haben mitgebracht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the paper", back: "das Papier", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the papers", back: "die Papiere", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to sign", back: "unterschreiben", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have signed", back: "haben unterschrieben", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "cash", back: "bar", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the machine", back: "der Automat", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the machines", back: "die Automaten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to function, to work", back: "funktionieren", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have functioned", back: "haben funktioniert", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the goal, the destination", back: "das Ziel", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the goals, the destinations", back: "die Ziele", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to choose", back: "wählen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have chosen", back: "haben gewählt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the adult", back: "der Erwachsene / die Erwachsene", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the adults", back: "die Erwachsenen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to select, to choose", back: "auswählen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have selected, have chosen", back: "haben ausgewählt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "one, you (general)", back: "man", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "first", back: "zuerst", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "after that, then", back: "danach", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "then", back: "dann", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the end, the conclusion", back: "der Schluss", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "quiet, soft", back: "leise", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "to explain", back: "erklären", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have explained", back: "haben erklärt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "loud", back: "laut", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "to turn off, to agree", back: "ausmachen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have agreed", back: "haben ausgemacht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to listen", back: "zuhören", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have listened", back: "haben zugehört", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to get up, to stand up", back: "aufstehen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "has gotten up", back: "ist aufgestanden", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to wait", back: "warten", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have waited", back: "haben gewartet", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the fee", back: "die Gebühr", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the fees", back: "die Gebühren", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the cashier, the checkout", back: "die Kasse", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the cashiers, the checkouts", back: "die Kassen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to laugh", back: "lachen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have laughed", back: "haben gelacht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the moment", back: "der Moment", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the moments", back: "die Momente", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to apply for", back: "beantragen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have applied for", back: "haben beantragt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to be allowed, may", back: "dürfen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have been allowed", back: "haben gedurft", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "attention, caution", back: "Achtung", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the cigarette", back: "die Zigarette", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the cigarettes", back: "die Zigaretten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to smoke", back: "rauchen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have smoked", back: "haben geraucht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "slow", back: "langsam", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the parking lot", back: "der Parkplatz", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the parking lots", back: "die Parkplätze", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to park", back: "parken", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have parked", back: "haben geparkt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "allowed, permitted", back: "erlaubt", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "forbidden", back: "verboten", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the luggage", back: "das Gepäck", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "to hand in, to submit", back: "abgeben", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have handed in, have submitted", back: "haben abgegeben", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to take along, to carry", back: "mitnehmen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have taken along, have carried", back: "haben mitgenommen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "alone", back: "allein", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the authority, the agency", back: "die Behörde", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the authorities, the agencies", back: "die Behörden", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the person", back: "die Person", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the people", back: "die Personen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the birth name", back: "der Geburtsname", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the birth names", back: "die Geburtsnamen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the gender", back: "das Geschlecht", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the genders", back: "die Geschlechter", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the foreigner", back: "der Ausländer", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the foreigners", back: "die Ausländer", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the foreign woman", back: "die Ausländerin", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the foreign women", back: "die Ausländerinnen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to live separately", back: "getrennt leben", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "male", back: "männlich", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "female", back: "weiblich", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the relative", back: "der Angehörige / die Angehörige", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the relatives", back: "die Angehörigen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to mean, to signify", back: "bedeuten", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have meant", back: "haben bedeutet", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to repeat", back: "wiederholen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have repeated", back: "haben wiederholt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to understand", back: "verstehen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have understood", back: "haben verstanden", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the language school", back: "die Sprachenschule", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the language schools", back: "die Sprachenschulen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to visit, to attend", back: "besuchen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have visited, have attended", back: "haben besucht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to help", back: "helfen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have helped", back: "haben geholfen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the information, the inquiry", back: "die Auskunft", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the information, the inquiries", back: "die Auskünfte", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the permission", back: "die Erlaubnis", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the explanation", back: "die Erklärung", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the explanations", back: "die Erklärungen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the document", back: "das Dokument", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the documents", back: "die Dokumente", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the money", back: "das Geld", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "enough", back: "genug", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the income", back: "das Einkommen", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "the trip, the journey", back: "die Reise", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the trips, the journeys", back: "die Reisen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the insurance", back: "die Versicherung", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the insurances", back: "die Versicherungen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the embassy", back: "die Botschaft", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the embassies", back: "die Botschaften", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the visa", back: "das Visum", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the visas", back: "die Visa", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to get, to fetch", back: "holen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have gotten, have fetched", back: "haben geholt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the employee (male)", back: "der Mitarbeiter", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the employees (male)", back: "die Mitarbeiter", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the employee (female)", back: "die Mitarbeiterin", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the employees (female)", back: "die Mitarbeiterinnen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the civil servant (male)", back: "der Beamte", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the civil servants (male)", back: "die Beamten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the civil servant (female)", back: "die Beamtin", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the civil servants (female)", back: "die Beamtinnen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to earn", back: "verdienen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "have earned", back: "haben verdient", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the passport", back: "der Pass", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "the passports", back: "die Pässe", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "to travel", back: "reisen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "has traveled", back: "sein gereist", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "the club", back: "der Klub", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the clubs", back: "die Klubs", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "emergency room / A&E", back: "die Notaufnahme", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "emergency rooms", back: "die Notaufnahmen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the area / field / sector", back: "der Bereich", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the areas", back: "die Bereiche", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the tablet / pill", back: "die Tablette", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the tablets", back: "die Tabletten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the eye", back: "das Auge", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the eyes", back: "die Augen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "to hurt", back: "weh tun", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "have hurt", back: "haben wehgetan", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the accident", back: "der Unfall", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the accidents", back: "die Unfälle", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the doctor", back: "der Doktor", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the doctors", back: "die Doktoren", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the pain", back: "der Schmerz", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the pains", back: "die Schmerzen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "should / to be supposed to", back: "sollen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "have been supposed to", back: "haben gesollt", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "both", back: "beide", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "funny", back: "lustig", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "bad / serious", back: "schlimm", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "to give", back: "geben", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "have given", back: "haben gegeben", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the idea", back: "die Idee", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the ideas", back: "die Ideen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the leg", back: "das Bein", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the legs", back: "die Beine", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the hair", back: "das Haar", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the hairs", back: "die Haare", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the ear", back: "das Ohr", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the ears", back: "die Ohren", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the arm", back: "der Arm", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the arms", back: "die Arme", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the stomach / belly", back: "der Bauch", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the stomachs", back: "die Bäuche", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the finger", back: "der Finger", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the fingers", back: "die Finger", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the foot", back: "der Fuß", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the feet", back: "die Füße", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the neck / throat", back: "der Hals", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the necks / throats", back: "die Hälse", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the head", back: "der Kopf", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the heads", back: "die Köpfe", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the back", back: "der Rücken", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "the chest / breast", back: "die Brust", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the chests / breasts", back: "die Brüste", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the hand", back: "die Hand", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the hands", back: "die Hände", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the nose", back: "die Nase", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the noses", back: "die Nasen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the mouth", back: "der Mund", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the mouths", back: "die Münder", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "to be", back: "sein", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "her / their", back: "ihr", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "the tooth", back: "der Zahn", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the teeth", back: "die Zähne", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "to inform", back: "informieren", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "have informed", back: "haben informiert", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "our", back: "unser", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "to be cancelled / to fail", back: "ausfallen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "has failed / been cancelled", back: "ist ausgefallen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the message / news", back: "die Nachricht", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the messages / news", back: "die Nachrichten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the kiss", back: "der Kuss", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the kisses", back: "die Küsse", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "your (plural, informal)", back: "euer", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "healthy", back: "gesund", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "hopefully", back: "hoffentlich", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "the (male/female) acquaintance", back: "der Bekannte / die Bekannte", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the acquaintances", back: "die Bekannten / die Bekannten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the step", back: "der Schritt", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the steps", back: "die Schritte", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "a few / some", back: "ein paar", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "the medicine", back: "die Medizin", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "calm / quiet", back: "ruhig", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "the pharmacy", back: "die Apotheke", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the pharmacies", back: "die Apotheken", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the fever", back: "das Fieber", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "the cough", back: "der Husten", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "the ointment / cream", back: "die Salbe", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the ointments", back: "die Salben", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "to use", back: "verwenden", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "have used", back: "haben verwendet", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the health", back: "die Gesundheit", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "the cold / runny nose", back: "der Schnupfen", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "to do", back: "tun", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "have done", back: "haben getan", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the sender", back: "der Absender", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the senders", back: "die Absender", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the place / location", back: "der Ort", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the places", back: "die Orte", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the recipient", back: "der Empfänger", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the recipients", back: "die Empfänger", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the salutation / form of address", back: "die Anrede", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the salutations", back: "die Anreden", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the date", back: "das Datum", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the dates / data", back: "die Daten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the signature", back: "die Unterschrift", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the signatures", back: "die Unterschriften", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "to send", back: "schicken", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "have sent", back: "haben geschickt", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the consultation hour", back: "die Sprechstunde", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the consultation hours", back: "die Sprechstunden", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the emergency", back: "der Notfall", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the emergencies", back: "die Notfälle", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "nearby / in the vicinity", back: "in der Nähe", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "the minute", back: "die Minute", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the minutes", back: "die Minuten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "okay / all right", back: "in Ordnung", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "to come by / drop by", back: "vorbeikommen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "has come by", back: "ist vorbeigekommen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the insurance card", back: "die Versichertenkarte", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the insurance cards", back: "die Versichertenkarten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the floor / ground", back: "der Boden", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the floors", back: "die Böden", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "to lie (down)", back: "liegen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "have lain", back: "haben gelegen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the emergency doctor", back: "der Notarzt", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the emergency doctors", back: "die Notärzte", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "strong / severe", back: "stark", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "the help / aid", back: "die Hilfe", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "suddenly", back: "plötzlich", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "to happen", back: "passieren", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "has happened", back: "ist passiert", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the medicine / drug", back: "das Medikament", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the medicines", back: "die Medikamente", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the motorcycle", back: "das Motorrad", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the motorcycles", back: "die Motorräder", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the injury", back: "die Verletzung", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "the injuries", back: "die Verletzungen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "the workshop / garage", back: "die Werkstatt", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the workshops / garages", back: "die Werkstätten", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the key", back: "der Schlüssel", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the keys", back: "die Schlüssel", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the highway / motorway", back: "die Autobahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the highways / motorways", back: "die Autobahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the bridge", back: "die Brücke", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the bridges", back: "die Brücken", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "right (direction)", back: "rechts", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "straight ahead", back: "geradeaus", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "left (direction)", back: "links", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "the way / path", back: "der Weg", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the ways / paths", back: "die Wege", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the train station", back: "der Bahnhof", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the train stations", back: "die Bahnhöfe", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the butcher shop", back: "die Metzgerei", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the butcher shops", back: "die Metzgereien", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the post office / mail", back: "die Post", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "the hotel", back: "das Hotel", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the hotels", back: "die Hotels", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the museum", back: "das Museum", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the museums", back: "die Museen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the traffic light", back: "die Ampel", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the traffic lights", back: "die Ampeln", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the gas station / petrol station", back: "die Tankstelle", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the gas stations", back: "die Tankstellen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the city map", back: "der Stadtplan", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the city maps", back: "die Stadtpläne", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "foreign / unfamiliar", back: "fremd", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "to fly", back: "fliegen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "has flown", back: "ist geflogen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the airplane", back: "das Flugzeug", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the airplanes", back: "die Flugzeuge", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the tram / streetcar", back: "die Straßenbahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the trams", back: "die Straßenbahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the train", back: "der Zug", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the trains", back: "die Züge", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the subway / underground", back: "die U-Bahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the subways", back: "die U-Bahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the bus", back: "der Bus", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the buses", back: "die Busse", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the suburban train", back: "die S-Bahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the suburban trains", back: "die S-Bahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "where to", back: "wohin", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "the station / stop", back: "die Station", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the stations", back: "die Stationen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the truck / lorry", back: "der Lkw", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the trucks", back: "die Lkws", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the kiosk / small shop", back: "der Kiosk", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the kiosks", back: "die Kioske", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the (bus/tram) stop", back: "die Haltestelle", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the stops", back: "die Haltestellen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the bookstore", back: "die Buchhandlung", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the bookstores", back: "die Buchhandlungen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "to sit", back: "sitzen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "have sat", back: "haben gesessen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the library", back: "die Bücherei", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the libraries", back: "die Büchereien", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the tree", back: "der Baum", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the trees", back: "die Bäume", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the bank / bench", back: "die Bank", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the banks", back: "die Banken", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "at / on (vertical)", back: "an", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "on / onto (horizontal)", back: "auf", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "behind", back: "hinter", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "next to / beside", back: "neben", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "over / above", back: "über", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "under / below", back: "unter", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "between", back: "zwischen", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "the pedestrian zone", back: "die Fußgängerzone", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the pedestrian zones", back: "die Fußgängerzonen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the concert", back: "das Konzert", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the concerts", back: "die Konzerte", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "to borrow / lend", back: "ausleihen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "have borrowed", back: "haben ausgeliehen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "to copy", back: "kopieren", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "have copied", back: "haben kopiert", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "(over) there in front", back: "(da) vorne", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "(over) there / across", back: "(da) drüben", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "the corner", back: "die Ecke", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the corners", back: "die Ecken", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "(over) there in the back", back: "(da) hinten", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "to depart (by vehicle)", back: "abfahren", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "has departed", back: "ist abgefahren", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the platform / track", back: "das Gleis", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the platforms / tracks", back: "die Gleise", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "to get in / board", back: "einsteigen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "has boarded", back: "ist eingestiegen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the delay", back: "die Verspätung", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the delays", back: "die Verspätungen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "to arrive", back: "ankommen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "has arrived", back: "ist angekommen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "to transfer / change (trains etc.)", back: "umsteigen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "has transferred", back: "ist umgestiegen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "to get out / disembark", back: "aussteigen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "has gotten off", back: "ist ausgestiegen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the departure", back: "die Abfahrt", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the departures", back: "die Abfahrten", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the arrival", back: "die Ankunft", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the arrivals", back: "die Ankünfte", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the connection (transport)", back: "der Anschluss", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the connections", back: "die Anschlüsse", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the platform (at a station)", back: "der Bahnsteig", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the platforms", back: "die Bahnsteige", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "direct(ly)", back: "direkt", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "the announcement", back: "die Durchsage", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the announcements", back: "die Durchsagen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the counter / ticket window", back: "der Schalter", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the counters", back: "die Schalter", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "there and back / round trip", back: "hin und zurück", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "the timetable / schedule", back: "der Fahrplan", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "the timetables", back: "die Fahrpläne", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "the bag", back: "die Tasche", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the bags", back: "die Taschen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the bag / sack (plastic/paper)", back: "die Tüte", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the bags", back: "die Tüten", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the bill / invoice", back: "die Rechnung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the bills / invoices", back: "die Rechnungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "broken", back: "kaputt", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "to repair", back: "reparieren", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have repaired", back: "haben repariert", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "angry / sour", back: "sauer", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "unfriendly", back: "unfreundlich", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "normal", back: "normal", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "the home country", back: "das Heimatland", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the home countries", back: "die Heimatländer", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "training / workout", back: "Training", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "the clothes", back: "die Kleider", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "to sew", back: "nähen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have sewn", back: "haben genäht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the repair", back: "die Reparatur", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the repairs", back: "die Reparaturen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to shower", back: "duschen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have showered", back: "haben geduscht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the statement", back: "die Aussage", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the statements", back: "die Aussagen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the technician (male)", back: "der Techniker", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the technicians", back: "die Techniker", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the heater / heating", back: "die Heizung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the heaters", back: "die Heizungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the printer", back: "der Drucker", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the printers", back: "die Drucker", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the model / version", back: "das Modell", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the models", back: "die Modelle", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the warranty / guarantee", back: "die Garantie", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the warranties", back: "die Garantien", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "over / past (prefix)", back: "vorbei-", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "to bring over / drop off", back: "vorbeibringen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have brought over", back: "haben vorbeigebracht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to turn on", back: "anmachen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have turned on", back: "haben angemacht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the door", back: "die Tür", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the doors", back: "die Türen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to close", back: "zumachen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have closed", back: "haben zugemacht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the window", back: "das Fenster", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the windows", back: "die Fenster", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to open", back: "aufmachen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have opened", back: "haben aufgemacht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the paper", back: "das Papier", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the papers", back: "die Papiere", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the light", back: "das Licht", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the lights", back: "die Lichter", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the dishwasher", back: "die Spülmaschine", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the dishwashers", back: "die Spülmaschinen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to recommend", back: "empfehlen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have recommended", back: "haben empfohlen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to reserve / book", back: "reservieren", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have reserved", back: "haben reserviert", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the reception / front desk", back: "die Rezeption", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the receptions", back: "die Rezeptionen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the announcement / message", back: "die Ansage", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the announcements", back: "die Ansagen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to press / push", back: "drücken", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have pressed", back: "haben gedrückt", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to register / sign up", back: "anmelden", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have registered", back: "haben angemeldet", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to connect / transfer (a call)", back: "verbinden", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have connected", back: "haben verbunden", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to leave (a message)", back: "hinterlassen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have left", back: "haben hinterlassen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to call back", back: "zurückrufen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have called back", back: "haben zurückgerufen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to look / appear", back: "aussehen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "have looked", back: "haben ausgesehen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the vacation / holiday", back: "der Urlaub", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the vacations", back: "die Urlaube", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "outside", back: "draußen", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "gone / away", back: "weg", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "the coffee machine", back: "die Kaffeemaschine", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the coffee machines", back: "die Kaffeemaschinen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the hairdresser (male)", back: "der Friseur", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the hairdressers", back: "die Friseure", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the hairdresser (female)", back: "die Friseurin", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the hairdressers", back: "die Friseurinnen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to order", back: "bestellen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "has ordered", back: "hat bestellt", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the offer / deal", back: "das Angebot", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the offers", back: "die Angebote", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to offer", back: "anbieten", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "has offered", back: "hat angeboten", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the young person (m/f)", back: "der Jugendliche / die Jugendliche", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the young people", back: "die Jugendlichen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the instructions / manual", back: "die Gebrauchsanweisung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the instruction manuals", back: "die Gebrauchsanweisungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the cleaning / dry cleaner’s", back: "die Reinigung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the cleanings / cleaners", back: "die Reinigungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the plug", back: "der Stecker", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the plugs", back: "die Stecker", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the socket / outlet", back: "die Steckdose", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the sockets", back: "die Steckdosen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "to pull", back: "ziehen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "has pulled", back: "hat gezogen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "above / upstairs / top", back: "oben", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "the vinegar", back: "der Essig", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "the key / button (keyboard, machine)", back: "die Taste", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the keys / buttons", back: "die Tasten", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the second", back: "die Sekunde", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "the seconds", back: "die Sekunden", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "the jacket", back: "die Jacke", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the jackets", back: "die Jacken", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the coat", back: "der Mantel", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the coats", back: "die Mäntel", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "thin", back: "dünn", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "to fit", back: "passen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "has fit", back: "hat gepasst", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "wide / loose", back: "weit", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the clothing", back: "die Kleidung", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the blouse", back: "die Bluse", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the blouses", back: "die Blusen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the T-shirt", back: "das T-Shirt", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the T-shirts", back: "die T-Shirts", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the shoe", back: "der Schuh", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the shoes", back: "die Schuhe", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the pants / trousers", back: "die Hose", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the pants", back: "die Hosen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the skirt", back: "der Rock", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the skirts", back: "die Röcke", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the dress", back: "das Kleid", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the dresses", back: "die Kleider", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the boot", back: "der Stiefel", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the boots", back: "die Stiefel", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the sweater", back: "der Pullover", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the sweaters", back: "die Pullover", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the sock", back: "die Socke", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the socks", back: "die Socken", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the stocking", back: "der Strumpf", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the stockings", back: "die Strümpfe", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the jeans", back: "die Jeans", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the jeans (plural)", back: "die Jeans", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the scarf / cloth", back: "das Tuch", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the scarves / cloths", back: "die Tücher", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the shirt", back: "das Hemd", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the shirts", back: "die Hemden", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the suit", back: "der Anzug", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the suits", back: "die Anzüge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the glasses", back: "die Brille", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the glasses (plural)", back: "die Brillen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "boring", back: "langweilig", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the (rain) umbrella", back: "der (Regen-)Schirm", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the umbrellas", back: "die (Regen-)Schirme", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "affordable / cheap", back: "günstig", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "perfect", back: "perfekt", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "to suit / look good on", back: "stehen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "has suited", back: "hat gestanden", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the grilled sausage", back: "die Bratwurst", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the grilled sausages", back: "die Bratwürste", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the landscape", back: "die Landschaft", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the landscapes", back: "die Landschaften", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the mountain", back: "der Berg", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the mountains", back: "die Berge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the village", back: "das Dorf", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the villages", back: "die Dörfer", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the forest", back: "der Wald", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the forests", back: "die Wälder", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the North Sea", back: "die Nordsee", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the beach", back: "der Strand", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the beaches", back: "die Strände", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the sea", back: "das Meer", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the seas", back: "die Meere", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the harbor / port", back: "der Hafen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the harbors", back: "die Häfen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "never", back: "nie", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "better", back: "besser", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "best / the best", back: "am besten", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "backwards", back: "rückwärts", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "forwards", back: "vorwärts", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "present / with it", back: "dabei", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "heavy / difficult", back: "schwer", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the musician (male)", back: "der Musiker", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the musicians", back: "die Musiker", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the musician (female)", back: "die Musikerin", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the musicians", back: "die Musikerinnen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "to train / work out", back: "trainieren", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "has trained", back: "hat trainiert", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "to ride a bike", back: "rad fahren", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "has ridden a bike", back: "ist rad gefahren", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the record", back: "der Rekord", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the records", back: "die Rekorde", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "preferably / favorite", back: "am liebsten", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "most of all", back: "am meisten", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "satisfied / content", back: "zufrieden", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the joke", back: "der Witz", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the jokes", back: "die Witze", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "this", back: "dies-", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "which", back: "welch-", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the suitcase", back: "der Koffer", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the suitcases", back: "die Koffer", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "to belong to", back: "gehören", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "has belonged", back: "hat gehört", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "to like", back: "mögen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "has liked", back: "hat gemocht", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the weekday", back: "der Wochentag", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the weekdays", back: "die Wochentage", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the ground floor", back: "das Erdgeschoss", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the ground floors", back: "die Erdgeschosse", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the upper floor", back: "das Obergeschoss", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the upper floors", back: "die Obergeschosse", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the basement / lower floor", back: "das Untergeschoss", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the basements", back: "die Untergeschosse", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the exit", back: "der Ausgang", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the exits", back: "die Ausgänge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the drugstore", back: "die Drogerie", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the drugstores", back: "die Drogerien", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the cosmetics", back: "die Kosmetik", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the jewelry", back: "der Schmuck", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the dishes / crockery", back: "das Geschirr", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the glass", back: "das Glas", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the glasses", back: "die Gläser", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the fashion", back: "die Mode", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the fashions", back: "die Moden", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the entrance", back: "der Eingang", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the entrances", back: "die Eingänge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "to apologize", back: "entschuldigen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "has apologized", back: "hat entschuldigt", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "to know", back: "wissen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "has known", back: "hat gewusst", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the soap", back: "die Seife", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the soaps", back: "die Seifen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the toothbrush", back: "die Zahnbürste", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the toothbrushes", back: "die Zahnbürsten", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the toothpaste", back: "die Zahnpasta", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "the size", back: "die Größe", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "the sizes", back: "die Größen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "to put on (clothes)", back: "anziehen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "has put on", back: "hat angezogen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "to try on", back: "anprobieren", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "has tried on", back: "hat anprobiert", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "the birthday", back: "der Geburtstag", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the birthdays", back: "die Geburtstage", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the tire", back: "der Reifen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the tires", back: "die Reifen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to tell / narrate", back: "erzählen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has told", back: "hat erzählt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to celebrate", back: "feiern", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has celebrated", back: "hat gefeiert", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the farewell / goodbye", back: "der Abschied", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the farewells", back: "die Abschiede", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "soon", back: "bald", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "to begin", back: "beginnen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has begun", back: "hat begonnen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the job / workplace", back: "die Arbeitsstelle", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the jobs / workplaces", back: "die Arbeitsstellen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "luck / happiness", back: "das Glück", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "joy / pleasure", back: "die Freude", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "to wish (for oneself)", back: "(sich) wünschen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has wished", back: "hat gewünscht", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to congratulate", back: "gratulieren", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has congratulated", back: "hat gratuliert", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the congratulation", back: "der Glückwunsch", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the congratulations", back: "die Glückwünsche", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to believe", back: "glauben", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has believed", back: "hat geglaubt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to visit", back: "besuchen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has visited", back: "hat besucht", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "November", back: "der November", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "January", back: "der Januar", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "first", back: "erste", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "second", back: "zweite", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "third", back: "dritte", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "February", back: "der Februar", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "March", back: "der März", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "April", back: "der April", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "May", back: "der Mai", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "June", back: "der Juni", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "July", back: "der Juli", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "August", back: "der August", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "September", back: "der September", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "October", back: "der Oktober", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "December", back: "der Dezember", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "the flower", back: "die Blume", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the flowers", back: "die Blumen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the carnival", back: "der Karneval", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "last / previous", back: "letzt-", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "to participate", back: "mitmachen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has participated", back: "hat mitgemacht", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the public holiday", back: "der Feiertag", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the holidays", back: "die Feiertage", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the present / gift", back: "das Geschenk", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the presents", back: "die Geschenke", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to love (each other)", back: "(sich) lieben", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has loved", back: "hat geliebt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "wonderful", back: "wunderbar", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "the dessert", back: "der Nachtisch", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the desserts", back: "die Nachtische", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to clean", back: "putzen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has cleaned", back: "hat geputzt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the laptop", back: "der Laptop", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the laptops", back: "die Laptops", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "dirty", back: "schmutzig", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "to wash", back: "waschen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has washed", back: "hat gewaschen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the grandfather", back: "der Großvater", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the grandfathers", back: "die Großväter", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the grandmother", back: "die Großmutter", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the grandmothers", back: "die Großmütter", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the celebration / party", back: "die Feier", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the celebrations", back: "die Feiern", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to organize", back: "organisieren", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has organized", back: "hat organisiert", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to inform / give notice", back: "Bescheid geben", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has informed", back: "hat Bescheid gegeben", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the invitation", back: "die Einladung", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the invitations", back: "die Einladungen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the flight", back: "der Flug", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the flights", back: "die Flüge", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to become", back: "werden", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has become", back: "ist geworden", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to invite", back: "einladen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has invited", back: "hat eingeladen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to be happy / look forward", back: "sich freuen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has been happy / looked forward", back: "hat sich gefreut", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the festival / party", back: "das Fest", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the festivals / parties", back: "die Feste", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "cordial / heartfelt", back: "herzlich", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "the guest", back: "der Gast", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the guests", back: "die Gäste", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the reason", back: "der Grund", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the reasons", back: "die Gründe", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the answer", back: "die Antwort", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the answers", back: "die Antworten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "to ask / request", back: "bitten", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has asked", back: "hat gebeten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "Christmas", back: "das Weihnachten", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "Easter", back: "das Ostern", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "New Year's Eve", back: "das Silvester", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "New Year", back: "das Neujahr", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "to win", back: "gewinnen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "has won", back: "hat gewonnen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the relative (m/f)", back: "der Verwandte / die Verwandte", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the relatives", back: "die Verwandten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the card / ticket", back: "die Karte", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the cards / tickets", back: "die Karten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "the wedding", back: "die Hochzeit", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "the weddings", back: "die Hochzeiten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "happy", back: "glücklich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "to look at / watch", back: "ansehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has looked at / watched", back: "hat angesehen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the neighbor (male)", back: "der Nachbar", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the neighbors (male or mixed)", back: "die Nachbarn", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the neighbor (female)", back: "die Nachbarin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the neighbors (female)", back: "die Nachbarinnen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the shopping / purchase", back: "der Einkauf", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the shoppings / purchases", back: "die Einkäufe", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to work out / succeed", back: "klappen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has worked out / succeeded", back: "hat geklappt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the center", back: "das Zentrum", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the centers", back: "die Zentren", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the feeling", back: "das Gefühl", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the feelings", back: "die Gefühle", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the beginning", back: "der Anfang", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the beginnings", back: "die Anfänge", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to miss (someone)", back: "vermissen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has missed", back: "hat vermisst", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "because", back: "weil", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "the person / human", back: "der Mensch", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the people", back: "die Menschen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the employer (male)", back: "der Arbeitgeber", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the employers (male or mixed)", back: "die Arbeitgeber", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the employer (female)", back: "die Arbeitgeberin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the employers (female)", back: "die Arbeitgeberinnen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to move (house)", back: "umziehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has moved", back: "ist umgezogen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to get to know each other", back: "(sich) kennenlernen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has gotten to know each other", back: "hat kennengelernt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "yesterday", back: "gestern", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "the move / relocation", back: "der Umzug", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the moves / relocations", back: "die Umzüge", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the things / stuff", back: "die Sachen", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "to unpack", back: "auspacken", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has unpacked", back: "hat ausgepackt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to fall asleep", back: "einschlafen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has fallen asleep", back: "ist eingeschlafen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the alarm clock", back: "der Wecker", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the alarm clocks", back: "die Wecker", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to remember / notice", back: "(sich) merken", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has remembered / noticed", back: "hat gemerkt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "finally / after all", back: "schließlich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "even", back: "sogar", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "the working day", back: "der Arbeitstag", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the working days", back: "die Arbeitstage", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to sound", back: "klingen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has sounded", back: "hat geklungen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to experience", back: "erleben", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has experienced", back: "hat erlebt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the breakdown / malfunction", back: "die Panne", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the breakdowns", back: "die Pannen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the everyday life", back: "der Alltag", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "to miss (an event)", back: "verpassen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has missed", back: "hat verpasst", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to notice", back: "bemerken", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has noticed", back: "hat bemerkt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to find out / experience", back: "erfahren", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has found out / experienced", back: "hat erfahren", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to imagine / introduce oneself", back: "(sich) vorstellen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has imagined / introduced oneself", back: "hat vorgestellt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the wallet", back: "die Geldbörse", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the wallets", back: "die Geldbörsen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to lose", back: "verlieren", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has lost", back: "hat verloren", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "bad luck", back: "das Pech", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "the credit card", back: "die Kreditkarte", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the credit cards", back: "die Kreditkarten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to bump / push", back: "stoßen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has bumped / pushed", back: "hat/ist gestoßen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "embarrassing", back: "peinlich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "the uncle", back: "der Onkel", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the uncles", back: "die Onkel", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the aunt", back: "die Tante", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the aunts", back: "die Tanten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the cousin (male)", back: "der Cousin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the cousins (male or mixed)", back: "die Cousins", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the cousin (female)", back: "die Cousine", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the cousins (female)", back: "die Cousinen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the nephew", back: "der Neffe", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the nephews", back: "die Neffen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the niece", back: "die Nichte", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the nieces", back: "die Nichten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "likeable / nice", back: "sympathisch", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "the member", back: "das Mitglied", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the members", back: "die Mitglieder", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the shared flat / flatshare", back: "die Wohngemeinschaft", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the shared flats", back: "die Wohngemeinschaften", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "probably", back: "wahrscheinlich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "the roof", back: "das Dach", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the roofs", back: "die Dächer", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "until now / so far", back: "bisher", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "different / various", back: "verschieden", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "the quarter / district", back: "das Viertel", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the quarters", back: "die Viertel", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the tenant (male)", back: "der Mieter", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the tenants (male or mixed)", back: "die Mieter", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the tenant (female)", back: "die Mieterin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the tenants (female)", back: "die Mieterinnen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to move in", back: "einziehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has moved in", back: "ist eingezogen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the time / occurrence", back: "das Mal", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the times / occurrences", back: "die Male", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "funny / strange", back: "komisch", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "someone / somebody", back: "jemand", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "to be enough / to reach", back: "reichen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has been enough", back: "hat gereicht", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to share", back: "teilen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has shared", back: "hat geteilt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "to move out / take off clothes", back: "ausziehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has moved out / taken off clothes", back: "ist ausgezogen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the place / square", back: "der Platz", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the places / squares", back: "die Plätze", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "every / each", back: "jeder", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "to use", back: "benutzen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "has used", back: "hat benutzt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "together", back: "gemeinsam", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "otherwise / else", back: "sonst", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "now", back: "nun", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "normally / usually", back: "normalerweise", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "pregnant", back: "schwanger", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "the father-in-law", back: "der Schwiegervater", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the fathers-in-law", back: "die Schwiegerväter", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the mother-in-law", back: "die Schwiegermutter", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the mothers-in-law", back: "die Schwiegermütter", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the household", back: "der Haushalt", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the households", back: "die Haushalte", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "the pension / retirement", back: "die Rente", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "the pensions", back: "die Renten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "energy", back: "die Energie", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "oneself / self / by oneself", back: "selbst", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "to change / switch", back: "wechseln", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has changed / switched", back: "hat gewechselt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "ceiling / blanket", back: "die Decke", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "the ceilings / blankets", back: "die Decken", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to hang", back: "hängen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has hung (transitive) / has been hanging (intransitive)", back: "hat gehängt / hat gehangen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "thanks / gratitude", back: "der Dank", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "nothing", back: "nichts", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "amount / quantity / crowd", back: "die Menge", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "the amounts / quantities / crowds", back: "die Mengen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "ballpoint pen", back: "der Kugelschreiber", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "ballpoint pens", back: "die Kugelschreiber", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to stick / put (in)", back: "stecken", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has stuck / put (in)", back: "hat gesteckt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "lock / castle", back: "das Schloss", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "locks / castles", back: "die Schlösser", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to stand", back: "stehen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has stood / been standing", back: "hat gestanden", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "picture / image", back: "das Bild", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "pictures / images", back: "die Bilder", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "wall", back: "die Wand", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "walls", back: "die Wände", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "cat", back: "die Katze", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "cats", back: "die Katzen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to lay / put (horizontal)", back: "legen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has laid / put", back: "hat gelegt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "peace / quiet", back: "die Ruhe", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "sign / shield", back: "das Schild", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "signs / shields", back: "die Schilder", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to disturb", back: "stören", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has disturbed", back: "hat gestört", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to put / place (vertical)", back: "stellen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has put / placed", back: "hat gestellt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "pen / pencil", back: "der Stift", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "pens / pencils", back: "die Stifte", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to build", back: "bauen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has built", back: "hat gebaut", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "there / to there", back: "dahin", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "plant", back: "die Pflanze", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "plants", back: "die Pflanzen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "there / to there (directional)", back: "dorthin", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "caution / care", back: "die Vorsicht", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "to fall down", back: "runterfallen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has fallen down", back: "ist gefallen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "in / inside", back: "rein", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "garbage / trash", back: "der Müll", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "out / outside", back: "raus", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "to come in", back: "reinkommen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has come in", back: "ist reingekommen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "message / notification", back: "die Mitteilung", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "messages / notifications", back: "die Mitteilungen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "resident (male)", back: "der Bewohner", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "residents (male or mixed)", back: "die Bewohner", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "resident (female)", back: "die Bewohnerin", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "residents (female)", back: "die Bewohnerinnen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to separate / split", back: "trennen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has separated", back: "hat getrennt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "bio- / organic", back: "bio-", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "waste / garbage", back: "der Abfall", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "wastes / garbages", back: "die Abfälle", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "plastic", back: "das Plastik", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "to observe / take note of", back: "beachten", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has observed / taken note of", back: "hat beachtet", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "garbage collection", back: "die Müllabfuhr", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "garbage collections", back: "die Müllabfuhren", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "garbage bin", back: "die Mülltonne", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "garbage bins", back: "die Mülltonnen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to put down / park", back: "abstellen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has put down / parked", back: "hat abgestellt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "driveway / entrance for vehicles", back: "die Einfahrt", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "driveways", back: "die Einfahrten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "courtyard / yard", back: "der Hof", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "courtyards / yards", back: "die Höfe", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to cancel / terminate (contract)", back: "kündigen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has canceled / terminated", back: "hat gekündigt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "contract / agreement", back: "der Vertrag", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "contracts / agreements", back: "die Verträge", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to hope", back: "hoffen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has hoped", back: "hat gehofft", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "understanding", back: "das Verständnis", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "to conclude / complete / lock", back: "abschließen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has concluded / completed / locked", back: "hat abgeschlossen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "low", back: "niedrig", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "costs / expenses", back: "die Kosten", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "to increase (oneself)", back: "(sich) erhöhen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has increased", back: "hat erhöht", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to remove", back: "entfernen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has removed", back: "hat entfernt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "object / item", back: "der Gegenstand", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "objects / items", back: "die Gegenstände", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to heat", back: "heizen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has heated", back: "hat geheizt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "baby stroller", back: "der Kinderwagen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "baby strollers", back: "die Kinderwagen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "elevator / lift", back: "der Aufzug", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "elevators", back: "die Aufzüge", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "stairs", back: "die Treppe", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "stairs", back: "die Treppen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "mailbox", back: "der Briefkasten", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "mailboxes", back: "die Briefkästen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "solution", back: "die Lösung", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "solutions", back: "die Lösungen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "quite / rather", back: "ziemlich", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "to be right", back: "recht haben", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has been right", back: "hat recht gehabt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "question", back: "die Frage", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "questions", back: "die Fragen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "request / favor", back: "die Bitte", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "requests / favors", back: "die Bitten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "intention / purpose", back: "die Absicht", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "intentions / purposes", back: "die Absichten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "shift (work), layer", back: "die Schicht", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "shifts / layers", back: "die Schichten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to let / leave", back: "lassen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has let / left", back: "hat gelassen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to throw", back: "werfen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has thrown", back: "hat geworfen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to pay attention / watch out", back: "aufpassen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has paid attention / watched out", back: "hat aufgepasst", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to pour / water", back: "gießen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has poured / watered", back: "hat gegossen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "really / truly", back: "wirklich", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "to ring (bell)", back: "klingeln", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has rung", back: "hat geklingelt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to discuss", back: "besprechen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has discussed", back: "hat besprochen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "to feed", back: "füttern", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "has fed", back: "hat gefüttert", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "craftsman / handyman", back: "der Handwerker", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "craftsmen / handymen", back: "die Handwerker", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "organic waste", back: "der Biomüll", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "dessert", back: "die Nachspeise", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "desserts", back: "die Nachspeisen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "honey", back: "der Honig", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "mostly / usually", back: "meistens", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "seldom / rarely", back: "selten", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "to be correct / agree", back: "stimmen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "has been correct / agreed", back: "hat gestimmt", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "on the way / traveling", back: "unterwegs", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "meal", back: "die Mahlzeit", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "meals", back: "die Mahlzeiten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "at noon / midday", back: "mittags", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "in the morning", back: "morgens", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "cup", back: "die Tasse", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "cups", back: "die Tassen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "certainly / definitely", back: "bestimmt", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "food / meal", back: "das Essen", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "lunch", back: "das Mittagessen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "lunches", back: "die Mittagessen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "canteen / cafeteria", back: "die Kantine", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "canteens / cafeterias", back: "die Kantinen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "almost / nearly", back: "fast", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "vegetarian", back: "vegetarisch", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "dish / course", back: "das Gericht", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "dishes / courses", back: "die Gerichte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "habit", back: "die Gewohnheit", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "habits", back: "die Gewohnheiten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "to take over", back: "übernehmen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "has taken over", back: "hat übernommen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "jam / marmalade", back: "die Marmelade", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "jams / marmalades", back: "die Marmeladen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "German", back: "deutsch", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "pig / pork", back: "das Schwein", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "pigs / pork", back: "die Schweine", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "alcohol", back: "der Alkohol", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "twice", back: "zweimal", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "spoon", back: "der Löffel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "spoons", back: "die Löffel", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "knife", back: "das Messer", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "knives", back: "die Messer", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "plate", back: "der Teller", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "plates", back: "die Teller", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "fork", back: "die Gabel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "forks", back: "die Gabeln", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "quartet", back: "das Quartett", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "quartets", back: "die Quartette", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "pot", back: "der Topf", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "pots", back: "die Töpfe", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "jug / pot", back: "die Kanne", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "jugs / pots", back: "die Kannen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "bowl", back: "die Schüssel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "bowls", back: "die Schüsseln", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "pan", back: "die Pfanne", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "pans", back: "die Pfannen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "appetite", back: "der Appetit", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "to smell", back: "riechen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "has smelled", back: "hat gerochen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "to undress / take off clothes", back: "(sich) ausziehen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "has undressed / taken off clothes", back: "hat ausgezogen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "full", back: "voll", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "okay", back: "okay", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "before / previously", back: "vorher", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "polite", back: "höflich", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "diet", back: "die Diät", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "diets", back: "die Diäten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "full (after eating)", back: "satt", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "different / otherwise", back: "anders", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "just as / equally", back: "genauso", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "to surprise", back: "überraschen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "has surprised", back: "hat überrascht", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "strange / odd", back: "seltsam", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "spicy / sharp", back: "scharf", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "sweet", back: "süß", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "salty", back: "salzig", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "fat / greasy", back: "fett", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "to lead / manage", back: "leiten", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "has led / managed", back: "hat geleitet", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "fresh", back: "frisch", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "round", back: "rund", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "different / various", back: "unterschiedlich", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "type / kind", back: "die Art", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "types / kinds", back: "die Arten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "muesli / cereal", back: "das Müsli", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "mueslis / cereals", back: "die Müslis", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "fruit", back: "die Frucht", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "fruits", back: "die Früchte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "appetizer / starter", back: "die Vorspeise", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "appetizers / starters", back: "die Vorspeisen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "main- (prefix)", back: "Haupt-", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "percent", back: "das Prozent", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "percents", back: "die Prozente", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "market", back: "der Markt", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "markets", back: "die Märkte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "regional", back: "regional", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "product", back: "das Produkt", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "products", back: "die Produkte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "surroundings / environment", back: "die Umgebung", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "surroundings / environments", back: "die Umgebungen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "steak", back: "das Steak", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "steaks", back: "die Steaks", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "factory", back: "die Fabrik", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "factories", back: "die Fabriken", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "against", back: "gegen", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "to plan", back: "planen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "has planned", back: "hat geplant", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "daily", back: "täglich", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "schnitzel (breaded cutlet)", back: "das Schnitzel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "schnitzels", back: "die Schnitzel", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "soup", back: "die Suppe", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "soups", back: "die Suppen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "piece", back: "das Stück", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "pieces", back: "die Stücke", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "lemon", back: "die Zitrone", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "lemons", back: "die Zitronen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "clean", back: "sauber", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "beef / cattle", back: "das Rind", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "beef / cattle", back: "die Rinder", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "roast", back: "der Braten", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "roasts", back: "die Braten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "occupied / taken", back: "besetzt", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "tip (money)", back: "das Trinkgeld", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "tips", back: "die Trinkgelder", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "glass / jar", back: "das Glas", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "glasses / jars", back: "die Gläser", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "reservation", back: "die Reservierung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "reservations", back: "die Reservierungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "confirmation", back: "die Bestätigung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "confirmations", back: "die Bestätigungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to note / write down", back: "notieren", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has noted / written down", back: "hat notiert", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "online", back: "online", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "difficult / hard", back: "schwierig", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "meeting / discussion", back: "die Besprechung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "meetings / discussions", back: "die Besprechungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "namely / that is", back: "nämlich", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "friendly", back: "freundlich", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "clever / smart", back: "klug", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "mistake / error", back: "der Fehler", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "mistakes / errors", back: "die Fehler", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "if / when", back: "wenn", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "sure / safe", back: "sicher", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "material", back: "das Material", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "materials", back: "die Materialien", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "participant (male)", back: "der Teilnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "participants (male)", back: "die Teilnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "participant (female)", back: "die Teilnehmerin", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "participants (female)", back: "die Teilnehmerinnen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "tip / advice", back: "der Tipp", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "tips / advices", back: "die Tipps", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "regularly", back: "regelmäßig", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "to pay attention to", back: "achten auf", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has paid attention to", back: "hat geachtet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "note / slip", back: "der Zettel", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "notes / slips", back: "die Zettel", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "department store", back: "das Kaufhaus", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "department stores", back: "die Kaufhäuser", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to use", back: "nutzen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has used", back: "hat genutzt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "platform", back: "die Plattform", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "platforms", back: "die Plattformen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "forum", back: "das Forum", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "forums", back: "die Foren", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "agency", back: "die Agentur", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "agencies", back: "die Agenturen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "temporary work", back: "die Zeitarbeit", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "temporary works", back: "die Zeitarbeiten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "trainee / apprentice (m/f)", back: "der Auszubildende / die Auszubildende", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "trainees / apprentices", back: "die Auszubildenden", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to switch off / turn off", back: "ausschalten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has switched off / turned off", back: "hat ausgeschaltet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "labor union", back: "die Gewerkschaft", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "labor unions", back: "die Gewerkschaften", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "safety / security", back: "die Sicherheit", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "protection", back: "der Schutz", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "business / company", back: "der Betrieb", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "businesses / companies", back: "die Betriebe", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "assembly / meeting", back: "die Versammlung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "assemblies / meetings", back: "die Versammlungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "deadline", back: "die Frist", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "deadlines", back: "die Fristen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "further training", back: "die Weiterbildung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "further trainings", back: "die Weiterbildungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "interest", back: "das Interesse", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "to retire", back: "in Rente gehen", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "life", back: "das Leben", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "retiree (male)", back: "der Rentner", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "retirees (male)", back: "die Rentner", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "retiree (female)", back: "die Rentnerin", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "retirees (female)", back: "die Rentnerinnen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "event / function", back: "die Veranstaltung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "events / functions", back: "die Veranstaltungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to turn / address", back: "wenden", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has turned / addressed", back: "hat gewandt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to take place", back: "stattfinden", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has taken place", back: "hat stattgefunden", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "workers’ council", back: "der Betriebsrat", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "workers’ councils", back: "die Betriebsräte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to report", back: "berichten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has reported", back: "hat berichtet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to advise", back: "beraten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has advised", back: "hat beraten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "tariff / rate", back: "der Tarif", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "tariffs / rates", back: "die Tarife", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "right / law", back: "das Recht", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "rights / laws", back: "die Rechte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "termination / resignation", back: "die Kündigung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "terminations / resignations", back: "die Kündigungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "dismissal", back: "die Entlassung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "dismissals", back: "die Entlassungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "regulation / rule", back: "die Vorschrift", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "regulations / rules", back: "die Vorschriften", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "without", back: "ohne", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "to dismiss / release", back: "entlassen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has dismissed / released", back: "hat entlassen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to protect", back: "schützen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has protected", back: "hat geschützt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to thank", back: "(sich) bedanken", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has thanked", back: "hat bedankt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to pass on (a message)", back: "ausrichten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has passed on", back: "hat ausgerichtet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "export", back: "der Export", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "exports", back: "die Exporte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to try", back: "versuchen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has tried", back: "hat versucht", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "nobody / no one", back: "niemand", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "end of workday", back: "der Feierabend", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "ends of workday", back: "die Feierabende", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "import", back: "der Import", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "imports", back: "die Importe", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "employee (male)", back: "der Arbeitnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "employees (male)", back: "die Arbeitnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "employee (female)", back: "die Arbeitnehmerin", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "employees (female)", back: "die Arbeitnehmerinnen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "average", back: "durchschnittlich", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "idea / notion", back: "die Ahnung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "ideas / notions", back: "die Ahnungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "national holiday", back: "der Nationalfeiertag", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "national holidays", back: "die Nationalfeiertage", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "overtime (work)", back: "die Überstunde", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "overtime hours", back: "die Überstunden", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "wage / salary", back: "der Lohn", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "wages / salaries", back: "die Löhne", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "to offer", back: "bieten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has offered", back: "hat geboten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "rule", back: "die Regel", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "rules", back: "die Regeln", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "industry", back: "die Industrie", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "average", back: "der Durchschnitt", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "averages", back: "die Durchschnitte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "most (people)", back: "die meisten", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "altogether / in total", back: "insgesamt", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "to apply / be valid", back: "gelten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "has applied / been valid", back: "hat gegolten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "at least", back: "mindestens", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "to move (oneself)", back: "(sich) bewegen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has moved (oneself)", back: "hat bewegt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to be interested in", back: "(sich) interessieren für", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has been interested in", back: "hat interessiert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "dance", back: "der Tanz", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "dances", back: "die Tänze", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "basketball", back: "der Basketball", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to feel (oneself)", back: "(sich) fühlen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has felt (oneself)", back: "hat gefühlt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "too little / too few", back: "zu wenig", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "video", back: "das Video", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "videos", back: "die Videos", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to fall down", back: "hinfallen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has fallen down", back: "ist hingefallen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "desire / appetite", back: "die Lust", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "club / association", back: "der Verein", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "clubs / associations", back: "die Vereine", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "attempt", back: "der Versuch", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "attempts", back: "die Versuche", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "champion / master", back: "der Meister", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "champions / masters", back: "die Meister", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "sport discipline", back: "die Sportart", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "sport disciplines", back: "die Sportarten", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "relaxation", back: "die Entspannung", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "nutrition", back: "die Ernährung", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "movement", back: "die Bewegung", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "movements", back: "die Bewegungen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "fit", back: "fit", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "walk / stroll", back: "der Spaziergang", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "walks / strolls", back: "die Spaziergänge", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to arrange to meet with", back: "(sich) verabreden mit", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has arranged to meet with", back: "hat verabredet", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to rest (oneself)", back: "(sich) ausruhen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has rested (oneself)", back: "hat ausgeruht", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to feed / nourish oneself", back: "(sich) ernähren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has fed / nourished oneself", back: "hat ernährt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to get annoyed (about)", back: "(sich) ärgern (über)", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has gotten annoyed (about)", back: "hat geärgert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to put on makeup", back: "(sich) schminken", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has put on makeup", back: "hat geschminkt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to shave (oneself)", back: "(sich) rasieren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has shaved (oneself)", back: "hat rasiert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to change clothes", back: "(sich) umziehen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has changed clothes", back: "hat umgezogen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to comb (oneself)", back: "(sich) kämmen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has combed (oneself)", back: "hat gekämmt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to wash (oneself)", back: "(sich) waschen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has washed (oneself)", back: "hat gewaschen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to hurry (oneself)", back: "(sich) beeilen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has hurried (oneself)", back: "hat beeilt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to concentrate (on)", back: "(sich) konzentrieren (auf)", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has concentrated (on)", back: "hat konzentriert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to complain (about)", back: "(sich) beschweren (über)", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has complained (about)", back: "hat beschwert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "at all / generally", back: "überhaupt", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "magazine", back: "die Zeitschrift", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "magazines", back: "die Zeitschriften", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "history / story", back: "die Geschichte", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "theater", back: "das Theater", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "theaters", back: "die Theater", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "news", back: "die Nachrichten", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "world championship", back: "die Weltmeisterschaft", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "world championships", back: "die Weltmeisterschaften", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "weather forecast", back: "die Wettervorhersage", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "weather forecasts", back: "die Wettervorhersagen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "team", back: "die Mannschaft", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "teams", back: "die Mannschaften", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "visit", back: "der Besuch", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "visits", back: "die Besuche", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to take care of", back: "(sich) kümmern um", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has taken care of", back: "hat gekümmert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to dream of", back: "träumen von", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has dreamed of", back: "hat geträumt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "fear / anxiety", back: "die Angst", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "fears / anxieties", back: "die Ängste", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "honest", back: "ehrlich", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "gold", back: "das Gold", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "season", back: "die Saison", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "seasons", back: "die Saisons", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to remember / recall", back: "(sich) erinnern an", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has remembered / recalled", back: "hat erinnert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to think of", back: "denken an", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has thought of", back: "hat gedacht", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "vacation / holidays", back: "die Ferien", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "gymnastics", back: "die Gymnastik", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "table tennis", back: "das Tischtennis", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "volleyball", back: "der Volleyball", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "fitness", back: "die Fitness", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "contribution / post", back: "der Beitrag", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "contributions / posts", back: "die Beiträge", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to amount to / total", back: "betragen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has amounted to / totaled", back: "hat betragen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "group", back: "die Gruppe", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "groups", back: "die Gruppen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "reduction / discount", back: "die Ermäßigung", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "reductions / discounts", back: "die Ermäßigungen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "free of charge", back: "kostenlos", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "trainee / apprentice", back: "der Azubi", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "trainees / apprentices", back: "die Azubis", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "additional", back: "zusätzlich", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "active", back: "aktiv", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to jog", back: "joggen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has jogged", back: "ist gejoggt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to hold (oneself)", back: "(sich) halten", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has held", back: "hat gehalten", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "frequent", back: "häufig", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "the cause", back: "die Ursache", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "the causes", back: "die Ursachen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "the illness", back: "die Krankheit", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "the illnesses", back: "die Krankheiten", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "the screen", back: "der Bildschirm", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "the screens", back: "die Bildschirme", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "the body", back: "der Körper", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "the bodies", back: "die Körper", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "besides/also", back: "außerdem", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "the air", back: "die Luft", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "the examination/investigation", back: "die Untersuchung", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "the examinations/investigations", back: "die Untersuchungen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to manage/accomplish", back: "schaffen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has managed/accomplished", back: "hat geschafft", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "inexpensive", back: "preiswert", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to run", back: "laufen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has run", back: "ist gelaufen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "the trend", back: "der Trend", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "the trends", back: "die Trends", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "the playground", back: "der Spielplatz", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "the playgrounds", back: "die Spielplätze", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "extra", back: "extra", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "flexible", back: "flexibel", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "the environment", back: "die Umwelt", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "the health insurance fund", back: "die Krankenkasse", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "the health insurance funds", back: "die Krankenkassen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "popular", back: "beliebt", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "the route/distance", back: "die Strecke", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "the routes/distances", back: "die Strecken", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "clear", back: "klar", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to exaggerate", back: "übertreiben", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has exaggerated", back: "hat übertrieben", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "of course/natural", back: "selbstverständlich", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to play tennis", back: "tennis spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to ski", back: "ski fahren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has skied", back: "ist gefahren", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to play basketball", back: "basketball spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to do gymnastics", back: "gymnastik machen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to play table tennis", back: "tischtennis spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to play volleyball", back: "volleyball spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to do fitness training", back: "fitnesstraining machen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to play ice hockey", back: "eishockey spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to swim", back: "schwimmen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has swum", back: "ist geschwommen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to ride a bike", back: "fahrrad fahren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has ridden a bike", back: "ist gefahren", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to play soccer", back: "fußball spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "to hike", back: "wandern", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has hiked", back: "ist gewandert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "to dance", back: "tanzen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "has danced", back: "hat getanzt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "the report card/certificate", back: "das Zeugnis", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the report cards/certificates", back: "die Zeugnisse", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the subject/field", back: "das Fach", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the subjects/fields", back: "die Fächer", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the grade/mark", back: "die Note", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the grades/marks", back: "die Noten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the high school (academic)", back: "das Gymnasium", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the high schools (academic)", back: "die Gymnasien", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the presentation/report", back: "das Referat", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the presentations/reports", back: "die Referate", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the high school diploma", back: "das Abitur", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the graduation/completion", back: "der Abschluss", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the graduations/completions", back: "die Abschlüsse", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the exam", back: "die Prüfung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the exams", back: "die Prüfungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "lazy", back: "faul", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "terrible", back: "schrecklich", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "hardworking", back: "fleißig", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "intelligent", back: "intelligent", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "to argue", back: "streiten", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has argued", back: "hat gestritten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "that", back: "dass", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "to improve", back: "verbessern", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has improved", back: "hat verbessert", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the behavior", back: "das Verhalten", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "strict", back: "streng", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the wish", back: "der Wunsch", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the wishes", back: "die Wünsche", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the plan", back: "der Plan", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the plans", back: "die Pläne", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the astronaut (male)", back: "der Astronaut", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the astronauts (male)", back: "die Astronauten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the astronaut (female)", back: "die Astronautin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the astronauts (female)", back: "die Astronautinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "earlier/just now", back: "vorhin", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "middle/intermediate", back: "mittler-", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the activity", back: "die Aktivität", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the activities", back: "die Aktivitäten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the system", back: "das System", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the systems", back: "die Systeme", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the (technical) college", back: "die (Fach-)Hochschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the (technical) colleges", back: "die (Fach-)Hochschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the university", back: "die Universität", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the universities", back: "die Universitäten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the comprehensive school", back: "die Gesamtschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the comprehensive schools", back: "die Gesamtschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the secondary school", back: "die Realschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the secondary schools", back: "die Realschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the general secondary school", back: "die Hauptschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the general secondary schools", back: "die Hauptschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the middle school", back: "die Mittelschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the middle schools", back: "die Mittelschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the vocational school", back: "die Berufsschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the vocational schools", back: "die Berufsschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "voluntary", back: "freiwillig", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the daycare nursery", back: "die Krippe", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the daycare nurseries", back: "die Krippen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "physics", back: "die Physik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "social studies", back: "die Sozialkunde", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "biology", back: "die Biologie", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "chemistry", back: "die Chemie", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "geography", back: "die Geografie", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "art", back: "die Kunst", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "history", back: "die Geschichte", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "to hate", back: "hassen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has hated", back: "hat gehasst", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the spring (season)", back: "das Frühjahr", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the beginning", back: "der Beginn", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the theory", back: "die Theorie", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the theories", back: "die Theorien", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the introduction", back: "die Einführung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the introductions", back: "die Einführungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "to save (data)", back: "speichern", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has saved", back: "hat gespeichert", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the migrant (male)", back: "der Migrant", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the migrants (male)", back: "die Migranten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the migrant (female)", back: "die Migrantin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the migrants (female)", back: "die Migrantinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "social", back: "sozial", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the lecture/presentation", back: "der Vortrag", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the lectures/presentations", back: "die Vorträge", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "to apply (for a job)", back: "(sich) bewerben", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has applied", back: "hat beworben", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "to present", back: "präsentieren", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has presented", back: "hat präsentiert", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the expert (male)", back: "der Experte", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the experts (male)", back: "die Experten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the expert (female)", back: "die Expertin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the experts (female)", back: "die Expertinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the preparation", back: "die Vorbereitung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the preparations", back: "die Vorbereitungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the certificate", back: "das Zertifikat", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the certificates", back: "die Zertifikate", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the support/funding", back: "die Förderung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the supports/fundings", back: "die Förderungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "possible", back: "möglich", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the consultation/advice", back: "die Beratung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the consultations/advice", back: "die Beratungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "to injure oneself", back: "sich verletzen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has injured oneself", back: "hat verletzt", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "to bleed", back: "bluten", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has bled", back: "hat geblutet", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the studies (at university)", back: "das Studium", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the daily routine", back: "der Tagesablauf", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the daily routines", back: "die Tagesabläufe", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "to pass (an exam)", back: "bestehen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has passed", back: "hat bestanden", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "migration background", back: "der Migrationshintergrund", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "proud", back: "stolz", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "electric", back: "elektrisch", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the technology/technique", back: "die Technik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the contact", back: "der Kontakt", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the contacts", back: "die Kontakte", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "to recognize/acknowledge", back: "anerkennen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has recognized/acknowledged", back: "hat anerkannt", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "to check/examine", back: "prüfen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "has checked/examined", back: "hat geprüft", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "complicated", back: "kompliziert", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the baker (male)", back: "der Bäcker", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the bakers (male)", back: "die Bäcker", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the baker (female)", back: "die Bäckerin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the bakers (female)", back: "die Bäckerinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the actor (male)", back: "der Schauspieler", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the actors (male)", back: "die Schauspieler", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the actress (female)", back: "die Schauspielerin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "the actresses (female)", back: "die Schauspielerinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "the music", back: "die Musik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the mathematics", back: "die Mathematik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "the sport", back: "der Sport", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "unknown", back: "unbekannt", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "to prepare", back: "vorbereiten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has prepared", back: "hat vorbereitet", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "to do crafts/craft", back: "basteln", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has done crafts", back: "hat gebastelt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "to decide", back: "entscheiden", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has decided", back: "hat entschieden", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "to give (a gift)", back: "schenken", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has given (a gift)", back: "hat geschenkt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the baby", back: "das Baby", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the babies", back: "die Babys", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the necklace/chain", back: "die Kette", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the necklaces/chains", back: "die Ketten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "to guess/advice", back: "raten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has guessed/advised", back: "hat geraten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the doll", back: "die Puppe", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the dolls", back: "die Puppen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the DVD", back: "die DVD", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the DVDs", back: "die DVDs", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the perfume", back: "das Parfüm", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the perfumes", back: "die Parfüms", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the cream", back: "die Creme", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the creams", back: "die Cremes", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the wallet", back: "der Geldbeutel", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the wallets", back: "die Geldbeutel", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "to try/taste", back: "probieren", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has tried/tasted", back: "hat probiert", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the noodle", back: "die Nudel", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the noodles", back: "die Nudeln", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "to deliver", back: "liefern", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has delivered", back: "hat geliefert", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "reliable", back: "zuverlässig", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "special/premium", back: "Sonder-", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "to name/call", back: "nennen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has named/called", back: "hat genannt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the box", back: "die Schachtel", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the boxes", back: "die Schachteln", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "to print out", back: "ausdrucken", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has printed out", back: "hat ausgedruckt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the postage stamp", back: "die Briefmarke", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the postage stamps", back: "die Briefmarken", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the people", back: "die Leute", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "the church", back: "die Kirche", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the churches", back: "die Kirchen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the wedding/ceremony", back: "die Trauung", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the weddings/ceremonies", back: "die Trauungen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "crazy/insane", back: "wahnsinnig", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "the mood/atmosphere", back: "die Stimmung", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "stupid/dumb", back: "blöd", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "to greet", back: "grüßen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has greeted", back: "hat gegrüßt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "wonderful/beautiful", back: "wunderschön", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "to cry", back: "weinen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has cried", back: "hat geweint", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "typical", back: "typisch", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "the cake (layer cake)", back: "die Torte", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the cakes", back: "die Torten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "by the way", back: "übrigens", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "to step/kick", back: "treten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has stepped/kicked", back: "ist getreten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "probably/well", back: "wohl", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "nervous", back: "nervös", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "at least", back: "wenigstens", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "awake", back: "wach", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "wild", back: "wild", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "to wear/carry", back: "tragen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has worn/carried", back: "hat getragen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "personal", back: "persönlich", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "the heart", back: "das Herz", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the hearts", back: "die Herzen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the death", back: "der Tod", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "to spend (money)", back: "ausgeben", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has spent", back: "hat ausgegeben", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the homeland", back: "die Heimat", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "via/by", back: "per", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "the SMS/text message", back: "die SMS", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the SMS/text messages", back: "die SMS", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "to converse/talk", back: "sich unterhalten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has conversed/talked", back: "hat unterhalten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "to decorate", back: "dekorieren", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has decorated", back: "hat dekoriert", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the entertainment/conversation", back: "die Unterhaltung", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the entertainments/conversations", back: "die Unterhaltungen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "to convince", back: "überzeugen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "has convinced", back: "hat überzeugt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the praline (chocolate)", back: "die Praline", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the pralines", back: "die Pralinen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the chocolate", back: "die Schokolade", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the chocolates", back: "die Schokoladen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the book", back: "das Buch", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "the books", back: "die Bücher", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "the wood", back: "das Holz", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the woods", back: "die Hölzer", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the hammer", back: "der Hammer", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the hammers", back: "die Hämmer", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the tool", back: "das Werkzeug", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the tools", back: "die Werkzeuge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "to play along", back: "mitspielen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "has played along", back: "hat mitgespielt", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the disco / discotheque", back: "die Disko / die Diskothek", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the discos / discotheques", back: "die Diskos / die Diskotheken", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "to go out", back: "ausgehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "has gone out", back: "ist ausgegangen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "to spend (time)", back: "verbringen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "has spent (time)", back: "hat verbracht", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the laundry", back: "die Wäsche", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to undertake/do", back: "unternehmen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "has undertaken/done", back: "hat unternommen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the thing", back: "das Ding", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the things", back: "die Dinge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the lake", back: "der See", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the lakes", back: "die Seen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "nevertheless/still", back: "trotzdem", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the bike tour", back: "die Radtour", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the bike tours", back: "die Radtouren", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the flea market", back: "der Flohmarkt", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the flea markets", back: "die Flohmärkte", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "to have a cold", back: "erkältet sein", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "constant/constantly", back: "ständig", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the proposal/suggestion", back: "der Vorschlag", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the proposals/suggestions", back: "die Vorschläge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the sightseeing tour", back: "die Rundfahrt", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the sightseeing tours", back: "die Rundfahrten", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "agreed/okay", back: "einverstanden", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "positive", back: "positiv", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to react", back: "reagieren", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "has reacted", back: "hat reagiert", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "negative", back: "negativ", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the bar", back: "die Bar", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the bars", back: "die Bars", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the culture", back: "die Kultur", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the nature", back: "die Natur", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the opera", back: "die Oper", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the operas", back: "die Opern", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the meeting point", back: "der Treffpunkt", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the meeting points", back: "die Treffpunkte", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the town hall", back: "das Rathaus", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the town halls", back: "die Rathäuser", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the participation", back: "die Teilnahme", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to perform/appear", back: "auftreten", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "has performed/appeared", back: "ist aufgetreten", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the jazz", back: "der Jazz", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the train", back: "die Bahn", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the trains", back: "die Bahnen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "open", back: "offen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the adult education center", back: "die Volkshochschule", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the adult education centers", back: "die Volkshochschulen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the politics", back: "die Politik", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the photography", back: "die Fotografie", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "required/necessary", back: "erforderlich", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "free entry", back: "Eintritt frei", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "no registration required", back: "keine Anmeldung erforderlich", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the semester", back: "das Semester", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the semesters", back: "die Semester", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the hike", back: "die Wanderung", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the hikes", back: "die Wanderungen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the program", back: "das Programm", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the programs", back: "die Programme", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the fan", back: "der Fan", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the fans", back: "die Fans", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the artist (male)", back: "der Künstler", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the artists (male)", back: "die Künstler", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the artist (female)", back: "die Künstlerin", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the artists (female)", back: "die Künstlerinnen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "Europe", back: "Europa", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the toy", back: "das Spielzeug", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the toys", back: "die Spielzeuge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the CD", back: "die CD", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the CDs", back: "die CDs", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "on weekdays", back: "wochentags", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "the admission ticket", back: "die Eintrittskarte", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the admission tickets", back: "die Eintrittskarten", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "the broadcaster/channel", back: "der Sender", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "the broadcasters/channels", back: "die Sender", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "to go for a hike", back: "eine Wanderung machen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to do/make", back: "machen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "has done/made", back: "hat gemacht", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "to go to the opera", back: "in die Oper gehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to go to a bar", back: "in eine Bar", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to take a sightseeing tour", back: "eine Rundfahrt machen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a bike tour", back: "eine Radtour", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to go to a flea market", back: "auf einen Flohmarkt gehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to go to the disco", back: "in die Disko gehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to go to the lake", back: "an den See fahren", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to set up, to arrange", back: "einrichten", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "has set up, has arranged", back: "hat eingerichtet", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the poster", back: "das Poster", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the posters", back: "die Poster", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the candle", back: "die Kerze", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the candles", back: "die Kerzen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "awful, hideous, horrible", back: "scheußlich", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "colorful, multicolored", back: "bunt", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "to look, to watch", back: "gucken", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "has looked, has watched", back: "hat geguckt", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the wallet, the purse", back: "die Brieftasche", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the wallets, the purses", back: "die Brieftaschen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the lighter", back: "das Feuerzeug", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the lighters", back: "die Feuerzeuge", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the camera", back: "die Kamera", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the cameras", back: "die Kameras", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the bikini", back: "der Bikini", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the bikinis", back: "die Bikinis", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "practical", back: "praktisch", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "pretty, lovely", back: "hübsch", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "thick, fat", back: "dick", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the plate", back: "die Platte", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the plates", back: "die Platten", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the height", back: "die Höhe", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the heights", back: "die Höhen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the condition, the state", back: "der Zustand", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the conditions, the states", back: "die Zustände", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the quality", back: "die Qualität", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the qualities", back: "die Qualitäten", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the cutlery", back: "das Besteck", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the cutleries", back: "die Bestecke", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the metal", back: "das Metall", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the metals", back: "die Metalle", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the fabric, the material", back: "der Stoff", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the fabrics, the materials", back: "die Stoffe", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the backpack", back: "der Rucksack", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the backpacks", back: "die Rucksäcke", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the hat", back: "der Hut", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the hats", back: "die Hüte", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the love", back: "die Liebe", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the novel", back: "der Roman", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the novels", back: "die Romane", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "exciting, thrilling", back: "spannend", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "than, as", back: "als", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the stadium", back: "das Stadion", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the stadiums", back: "die Stadien", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the PC, the personal computer", back: "der PC", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the PCs", back: "die PCs", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the pudding", back: "der Pudding", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the puddings", back: "die Puddings", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the shop window", back: "das Schaufenster", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the shop windows", back: "die Schaufenster", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "to suggest", back: "vorschlagen", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "has suggested", back: "hat vorgeschlagen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "distant, removed", back: "entfernt", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the statistics", back: "die Statistik", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the statistics", back: "die Statistiken", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the foodstuff", back: "das Nahrungsmittel", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the foodstuffs", back: "die Nahrungsmittel", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the gas", back: "das Gas", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the gases", back: "die Gase", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the credit", back: "der Kredit", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the credits", back: "die Kredite", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "to record, to admit, to take", back: "aufnehmen", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "has recorded, has admitted", back: "hat aufgenommen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "to save", back: "sparen", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "has saved", back: "hat gespart", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "some, many", back: "manch-", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the memory", back: "die Erinnerung", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the memories", back: "die Erinnerungen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the thought", back: "der Gedanke", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the thoughts", back: "die Gedanken", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "valuable", back: "wertvoll", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "back then, at that time", back: "damals", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "dear, sweet", back: "lieb", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "therefore, that's why", back: "deshalb", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "inside, in there", back: "drin", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the hammer", back: "der Hammer", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the hammers", back: "die Hämmer", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the wood", back: "das Holz", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the woods", back: "die Hölzer", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the lamp", back: "die Lampe", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the lamps", back: "die Lampen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the glass", back: "das Glas", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the glasses", back: "die Gläser", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the cutlery", back: "das Besteck", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the cutleries", back: "die Bestecke", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the metal", back: "das Metall", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the metals", back: "die Metalle", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the (salad) bowl", back: "die (Salat-) Schüssel", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the (salad) bowls", back: "die (Salat-) Schüsseln", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the plastic", back: "das Plastik", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the entrance ticket", back: "die Eintrittskarte", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the entrance tickets", back: "die Eintrittskarten", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the paper", back: "das Papier", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the papers", back: "die Papiere", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the package", back: "das Paket", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the packages", back: "die Pakete", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the envelope", back: "der Briefumschlag", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the envelopes", back: "die Briefumschläge", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the postcard", back: "die Postkarte", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the postcards", back: "die Postkarten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the scissors", back: "die Schere", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the scissors", back: "die Scheren", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to send, to dispatch", back: "verschicken", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has sent, has dispatched", back: "hat verschickt", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to send, to mail", back: "versenden", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has sent, has mailed", back: "hat versendet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "neat, orderly", back: "ordentlich", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the shipment, the broadcast", back: "die Sendung", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the shipments, the broadcasts", back: "die Sendungen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to transport", back: "transportieren", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has transported", back: "hat transportiert", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "hard", back: "hart", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "to weigh", back: "wiegen", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has weighed", back: "hat gewogen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to pack", back: "verpacken", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has packed", back: "hat verpackt", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the ship", back: "das Schiff", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the ships", back: "die Schiffe", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the harvest", back: "die Ernte", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the harvests", back: "die Ernten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "ripe", back: "reif", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "soft", back: "weich", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the imagination, the fantasy", back: "die Fantasie", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the imaginations, the fantasies", back: "die Fantasien", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "what kind of, what a", back: "was für ein-", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the possibility", back: "die Möglichkeit", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the possibilities", back: "die Möglichkeiten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "then, actually, because", back: "denn", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the registered letter", back: "das Einschreiben", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the registered letters", back: "die Einschreiben", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to send", back: "senden", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has sent", back: "hat gesendet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the small package", back: "das Päckchen", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the small packages", back: "die Päckchen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the customs", back: "der Zoll", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the customs", back: "die Zölle", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "valuable, worth", back: "wert", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "absolutely, necessarily", back: "unbedingt", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the worry, the concern", back: "die Sorge", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the worries, the concerns", back: "die Sorgen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to freeze", back: "frieren", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has frozen", back: "hat gefroren", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the railway", back: "die Eisenbahn", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the railways", back: "die Eisenbahnen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the leaf", back: "das Blatt", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the leaves", back: "die Blätter", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the bear", back: "der Bär", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the bears", back: "die Bären", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the coin", back: "die Münze", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the coins", back: "die Münzen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the duck", back: "die Ente", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the ducks", back: "die Enten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the souvenir", back: "das Souvenir", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the souvenirs", back: "die Souvenirs", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the animal", back: "das Tier", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the animals", back: "die Tiere", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the bird", back: "der Vogel", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the birds", back: "die Vögel", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "un-, not", back: "un-", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the point", back: "der Punkt", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the points", back: "die Punkte", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the elephant", back: "der Elefant", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the elephants", back: "die Elefanten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the rose", back: "die Rose", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the roses", back: "die Rosen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the star", back: "der Stern", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the stars", back: "die Sterne", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the sky", back: "der Himmel", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the skies", back: "die Himmel", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "orange", back: "orange", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the network", back: "das Netzwerk", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the networks", back: "die Netzwerke", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to test", back: "testen", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has tested", back: "hat getestet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the knowledge", back: "das Wissen", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the quiz", back: "das Quiz", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the mobile phone", back: "das Mobiltelefon", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the mobile phones", back: "die Mobiltelefone", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the mail, the email", back: "die Mail", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the mails", back: "die Mails", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "worldwide", back: "weltweit", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the mailbox", back: "die Mailbox", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the mailboxes", back: "die Mailboxen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the success", back: "der Erfolg", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the successes", back: "die Erfolge", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the pub, the tavern", back: "die Kneipe", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the pubs, the taverns", back: "die Kneipen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to report, to get in touch", back: "melden (sich)", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has reported, has gotten in touch", back: "hat sich gemeldet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the parent council", back: "der Elternbeirat", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the parent councils", back: "die Elternbeiräte", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the flu", back: "die Grippe", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the vaccination", back: "die Impfung", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the vaccinations", back: "die Impfungen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the consulate", back: "das Konsulat", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the consulates", back: "die Konsulate", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "general", back: "allgemein", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the letter", back: "der Brief", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the letters", back: "die Briefe", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the mailbox", back: "der Briefkasten", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the mailboxes", back: "die Briefkästen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the email", back: "die E-Mail", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the emails", back: "die E-Mails", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the mobile phone", back: "das Handy", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the mobile phones", back: "die Handys", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the chat", back: "der Chat", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the chats", back: "die Chats", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the zoo", back: "der Zoo", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the zoos", back: "die Zoos", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the tiger", back: "der Tiger", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the tigers", back: "die Tiger", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the zebra", back: "das Zebra", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the zebras", back: "die Zebras", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to look at, to watch", back: "anschauen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has looked at, has watched", back: "hat angeschaut", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to leave, to depart", back: "wegfahren", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has left, has departed", back: "ist weggefahren", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to jump", back: "springen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has jumped", back: "ist gesprungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to refuel", back: "tanken", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has refueled", back: "hat getankt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "along", back: "entlang", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "past … at", back: "vorbei … an", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "opposite, across from", back: "gegenüber", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the direction", back: "die Richtung", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the directions", back: "die Richtungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the river", back: "der Fluss", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the rivers", back: "die Flüsse", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the intersection", back: "die Kreuzung", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the intersections", back: "die Kreuzungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to turn (off)", back: "abbiegen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has turned", back: "ist abgebogen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the exit", back: "die Ausfahrt", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the exits", back: "die Ausfahrten", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the copier", back: "der Kopierer", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the copiers", back: "die Kopierer", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the cafeteria", back: "die Cafeteria", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the cafeterias", back: "die Cafeterien", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the traffic jam", back: "der Stau", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the traffic jams", back: "die Staus", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the sidewalk", back: "der Bürgersteig", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the sidewalks", back: "die Bürgersteige", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to fall, to tumble", back: "stürzen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has fallen", back: "ist gestürzt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the cyclist", back: "der Radfahrer", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the cyclists", back: "die Radfahrer", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the knee", back: "das Knie", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the knees", back: "die Knie", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to stick, to glue", back: "kleben", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has stuck, has glued", back: "hat geklebt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the band-aid, plaster", back: "das Pflaster", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the band-aids, plasters", back: "die Pflaster", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the bike, the wheel", back: "das Rad", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the bikes, the wheels", back: "die Räder", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the darling, the favorite", back: "der Liebling", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the darlings, the favorites", back: "die Lieblinge", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to stop, to remain standing", back: "stehen bleiben", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has stopped, has remained standing", back: "ist stehen geblieben", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the gasoline, petrol", back: "das Benzin", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the battery", back: "die Batterie", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the batteries", back: "die Batterien", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "empty", back: "leer", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "on time, punctual", back: "rechtzeitig", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the traffic", back: "der Verkehr", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the construction site", back: "die Baustelle", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the construction sites", back: "die Baustellen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the lane, the track", back: "die Spur", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the lanes, the tracks", back: "die Spuren", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to overtake", back: "überholen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has overtaken", back: "hat überholt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the roadway", back: "die Fahrbahn", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the roadways", back: "die Fahrbahnen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "careful, cautious", back: "vorsichtig", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "because of, due to", back: "wegen", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the ice", back: "das Eis", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the fog", back: "der Nebel", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the fogs", back: "die Nebel", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the storm", back: "der Sturm", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the storms", back: "die Stürme", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the thunderstorm", back: "das Gewitter", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the thunderstorms", back: "die Gewitter", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "foggy", back: "neblig", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the chaos", back: "das Chaos", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "to worry, to care for", back: "sorgen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has worried, has cared for", back: "hat gesorgt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the situation", back: "die Situation", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the situations", back: "die Situationen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "complete", back: "komplett", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "for hours", back: "stundenlang", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the car", back: "der Wagen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the cars", back: "die Wagen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the region", back: "die Region", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the regions", back: "die Regionen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the heat", back: "die Hitze", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the part", back: "das Teil", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the parts", back: "die Teile", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "strong, vigorous", back: "kräftig", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "to avoid", back: "vermeiden", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has avoided", back: "hat vermieden", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the danger", back: "die Gefahr", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the dangers", back: "die Gefahren", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the citizen", back: "der Bürger", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the citizens", back: "die Bürger", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the female citizen", back: "die Bürgerin", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the female citizens", back: "die Bürgerinnen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the view", back: "die Aussicht", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the views", back: "die Aussichten", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to promise", back: "versprechen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has promised", back: "hat versprochen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "summery, hot", back: "sommerlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "dense, close, tight", back: "dicht", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "to prevent", back: "verhindern", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has prevented", back: "hat verhindert", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the start", back: "der Start", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the starts", back: "die Starts", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the landing", back: "die Landung", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the landings", back: "die Landungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the airport", back: "der Flughafen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the airports", back: "die Flughäfen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to start, to take off", back: "starten", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has started, has taken off", back: "ist gestartet", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to land", back: "landen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has landed", back: "ist gelandet", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "expected, likely", back: "voraussichtlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the departure", back: "der Abflug", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the departures", back: "die Abflüge", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "dangerous", back: "gefährlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "to stand out, to be noticeable", back: "auffallen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has stood out, has been noticeable", back: "ist aufgefallen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the moped", back: "das Moped", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the mopeds", back: "die Mopeds", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the means of transport", back: "das Verkehrsmittel", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the means of transport", back: "die Verkehrsmittel", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to honk, to beep", back: "hupen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has honked, has beeped", back: "hat gehupt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to brake", back: "bremsen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has braked", back: "hat gebremst", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the pedestrian", back: "der Fußgänger", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the pedestrians", back: "die Fußgänger", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the female pedestrian", back: "die Fußgängerin", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the female pedestrians", back: "die Fußgängerinnen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the fine, the ticket", back: "der Strafzettel", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the fines, the tickets", back: "die Strafzettel", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the penalty, the punishment", back: "die Strafe", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the penalties, the punishments", back: "die Strafen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "exhausting, strenuous", back: "anstrengend", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "terrible, awful", back: "furchtbar", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "public", back: "öffentlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "to talk, to speak", back: "reden", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has talked, has spoken", back: "hat geredet", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the difference", back: "der Unterschied", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the differences", back: "die Unterschiede", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the country", back: "das Land", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the speed, the pace", back: "das Tempo", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the Baltic Sea", back: "die Ostsee", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the choice, election", back: "die Wahl", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "to visit, to tour", back: "besichtigen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has visited, has toured", back: "hat besichtigt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "against, on the other hand", back: "dagegen", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "enthusiastic", back: "begeistert", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the accommodation", back: "die Unterkunft", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the accommodations", back: "die Unterkünfte", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the dream", back: "der Traum", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the dreams", back: "die Träume", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the coast", back: "die Küste", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the coasts", back: "die Küsten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the island", back: "die Insel", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the islands", back: "die Inseln", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the mountain range", back: "das Gebirge", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "Luxembourg", back: "Luxemburg", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "to bathe, to swim", back: "baden", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has bathed", back: "hat gebadet", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the sand", back: "der Sand", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "further, more", back: "weiter", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "cool", back: "kühl", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the farm", back: "der Bauernhof", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the farms", back: "die Bauernhöfe", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the cow", back: "die Kuh", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the cows", back: "die Kühe", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the horse", back: "das Pferd", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the horses", back: "die Pferde", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the sheep", back: "das Schaf", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the sheep", back: "die Schafe", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the boat", back: "das Boot", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the boats", back: "die Boote", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the festival", back: "das Festival", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the festivals", back: "die Festivals", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the sight, the landmark", back: "die Sehenswürdigkeit", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the sights, the landmarks", back: "die Sehenswürdigkeiten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "above all, especially", back: "vor allem", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "real, genuine", back: "echt", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the guesthouse, the boarding house", back: "die Pension", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the guesthouses, the boarding houses", back: "die Pensionen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the view", back: "der Blick", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the views", back: "die Blicke", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the single room", back: "das Einzelzimmer", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the double room", back: "das Doppelzimmer", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the toilet", back: "das WC", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the toilets", back: "die WCs", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "half board", back: "die Halbpension", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "camping", back: "das Camping", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the tour", back: "die Tour", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the tours", back: "die Touren", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the valley", back: "das Tal", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the valleys", back: "die Täler", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the meadow, the field", back: "die Wiese", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the meadows, the fields", back: "die Wiesen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "romantic", back: "romantisch", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the location", back: "die Lage", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the locations", back: "die Lagen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the castle", back: "das Schloss", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the castles", back: "die Schlösser", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "historical", back: "historisch", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "numerous, many", back: "zahlreich", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the overnight stay", back: "die Übernachtung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the overnight stays", back: "die Übernachtungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "famous", back: "berühmt", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the cathedral", back: "der Dom", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the cathedrals", back: "die Dome", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the youth hostel", back: "die Jugendherberge", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the youth hostels", back: "die Jugendherbergen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "inclusive", back: "inklusive", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the stay", back: "der Aufenthalt", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the stays", back: "die Aufenthalte", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to book", back: "buchen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has booked", back: "hat gebucht", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the travel agency", back: "das Reisebüro", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the travel agencies", back: "die Reisebüros", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the specialist", back: "der Spezialist", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the specialists", back: "die Spezialisten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the employee", back: "der Angestellte", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the employees", back: "die Angestellten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the female employee", back: "die Angestellte", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the female employees", back: "die Angestellten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the connection, the link", back: "die Verbindung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the connections, the links", back: "die Verbindungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "of course, naturally", back: "natürlich", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "to surf", back: "surfen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has surfed", back: "ist gesurft", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the tour, the leadership", back: "die Führung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the tours, the leaderships", back: "die Führungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the old town", back: "die Altstadt", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the old towns", back: "die Altstädte", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the exhibition", back: "die Ausstellung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the exhibitions", back: "die Ausstellungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "known, famous", back: "bekannt", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "nowhere", back: "nirgends", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "to pack", back: "einpacken", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has packed", back: "hat eingepackt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to agree", back: "einigen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has agreed", back: "hat geeinigt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to spend the night, to stay overnight", back: "übernachten", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has stayed overnight", back: "hat übernachtet", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to be against", back: "dagegen sein", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has been against", back: "ist dagegen gewesen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to be in favor", back: "dafür sein", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has been in favor", back: "ist dafür gewesen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to accept", back: "annehmen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has accepted", back: "hat angenommen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to decline", back: "ablehnen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has declined", back: "hat abgelehnt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to laze around, to be lazy", back: "faulenzen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has lazed around", back: "hat gefaulenzt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the travel destination", back: "das Reiseziel", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the travel destinations", back: "die Reiseziele", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the activities", back: "die Aktivitäten", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "to see the sights, to visit landmarks", back: "Sehenswürdigkeiten ansehen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has seen the sights, has visited landmarks", back: "hat Sehenswürdigkeiten angesehen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to visit the old town", back: "die Altstadt besichtigen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has visited the old town", back: "hat die Altstadt besichtigt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to view an exhibition", back: "eine Ausstellung ansehen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has viewed an exhibition", back: "hat eine Ausstellung angesehen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "to take a city tour", back: "eine Stadtführung machen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has taken a city tour", back: "hat eine Stadtführung gemacht", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "at the travel agency", back: "im Reisebüro", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "to book a trip", back: "eine Reise buchen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "has booked a trip", back: "hat eine Reise gebucht", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the information", back: "die Auskunft", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the trip", back: "die Reise", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the trips", back: "die Reisen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the office", back: "das Büro", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the offices", back: "die Büros", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the ice", back: "das Eis", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "the egg", back: "das Ei", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the eggs", back: "die Eier", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the amount", back: "der Betrag", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "the amounts", back: "die Beträge", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "the account", back: "das Konto", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the accounts", back: "die Konten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to open", back: "eröffnen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has opened", back: "hat eröffnet", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to answer", back: "beantworten", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has answered", back: "hat beantwortet", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to get, to procure", back: "besorgen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has procured", back: "hat besorgt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to postpone", back: "verschieben", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has postponed", back: "hat verschoben", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the EC card", back: "die EC-Karte", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the EC cards", back: "die EC-Karten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to withdraw", back: "abheben", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has withdrawn", back: "hat abgehoben", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to get, to receive", back: "kriegen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has gotten", back: "hat gekriegt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the ATM", back: "der Geldautomat", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the ATMs", back: "die Geldautomaten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the checking account", back: "das Girokonto", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the checking accounts", back: "die Girokonten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "whether, if", back: "ob", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "the cash", back: "das Bargeld", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "the sum", back: "die Summe", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the sums", back: "die Summen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "but rather, but", back: "sondern", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "monthly", back: "monatlich", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "the interest", back: "die Zinsen", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "to accept", back: "akzeptieren", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has accepted", back: "hat akzeptiert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the pocket money", back: "das Taschengeld", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "to complete, to finish", back: "erledigen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has completed", back: "hat erledigt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to check, to control", back: "kontrollieren", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has controlled", back: "hat kontrolliert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the control", back: "die Kontrolle", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the controls", back: "die Kontrollen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to break down (to be broken)", back: "kaputtgehen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has broken down", back: "ist kaputtgegangen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to recognize", back: "erkennen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has recognized", back: "hat erkannt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the manufacturer", back: "der Hersteller", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the manufacturers", back: "die Hersteller", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the oil", back: "das Öl", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "the brake", back: "die Bremse", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the brakes", back: "die Bremsen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to check, to verify", back: "überprüfen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has checked", back: "hat überprüft", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to renovate", back: "renovieren", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has renovated", back: "hat renoviert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to change", back: "ändern", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has changed", back: "hat geändert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to cut (oneself)", back: "schneiden (sich)", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has cut (oneself)", back: "hat geschnitten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to deposit", back: "einzahlen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has deposited", back: "hat eingezahlt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the brochure", back: "die Broschüre", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the brochures", back: "die Broschüren", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the salary", back: "das Gehalt", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the salaries", back: "die Gehälter", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the payslip", back: "der Gehaltsnachweis", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the payslips", back: "die Gehaltsnachweise", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to type", back: "tippen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has typed", back: "hat getippt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to transfer", back: "überweisen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has transferred", back: "hat überwiesen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the menu", back: "das Menü", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the menus", back: "die Menüs", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the waiter", back: "der Ober", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the waiters", back: "die Ober", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the police", back: "die Polizei", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "angry, evil", back: "böse", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "the mood", back: "die Laune", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the moods", back: "die Launen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the increase", back: "die Erhöhung", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the increases", back: "die Erhöhungen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the bank statement", back: "der Kontoauszug", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "the bank statements", back: "die Kontoauszüge", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "to withdraw money", back: "Geld abheben", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "has withdrawn", back: "hat abgehoben", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "the survey", back: "die Umfrage", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the surveys", back: "die Umfragen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "hardly, scarcely", back: "kaum", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "the future", back: "die Zukunft", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "the decision", back: "die Entscheidung", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the decisions", back: "die Entscheidungen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "to die", back: "sterben", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "has died", back: "ist gestorben", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the childhood", back: "die Kindheit", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the childhoods", back: "die Kindheiten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "next door", back: "nebenan", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "to fall in love", back: "verlieben (sich)", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "has fallen in love", back: "hat sich verliebt", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "nonsense", back: "der Quatsch", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "the teaching, the apprenticeship", back: "die Lehre", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the teachings, the apprenticeships", back: "die Lehren", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "accidental, coincidental", back: "zufällig", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "the restaurant, the venue", back: "das Lokal", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the restaurants, the venues", back: "die Lokale", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "since then", back: "seitdem", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "only, single", back: "einzig-", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "the opposite", back: "das Gegenteil", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the opposites", back: "die Gegenteile", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "doesn't matter, indifferent", back: "egal", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "the argument, the fight", back: "der Streit", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the arguments, the fights", back: "die Streite", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the couple", back: "das Paar", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the couples", back: "die Paare", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the education, upbringing", back: "die Erziehung", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "the opinion", back: "die Meinung", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the opinions", back: "die Meinungen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the advice", back: "der Ratschlag", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the pieces of advice", back: "die Ratschläge", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the mouse", back: "die Maus", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the mice", back: "die Mäuse", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "rather, sooner", back: "eher", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "popular", back: "populär", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "the smoker", back: "der Raucher", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the smokers", back: "die Raucher", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the female smoker", back: "die Raucherin", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the female smokers", back: "die Raucherinnen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the fairy tale", back: "das Märchen", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the fairy tales", back: "die Märchen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "to address, to speak to", back: "ansprechen", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "has addressed, spoken to", back: "hat angesprochen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "to thank", back: "danken", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "has thanked", back: "hat gedankt", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the idea, the thought", back: "der Einfall", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the ideas, the thoughts", back: "die Einfälle", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the world", back: "die Welt", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the worlds", back: "die Welten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the pet", back: "das Haustier", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the pets", back: "die Haustiere", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "serious", back: "ernst", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "comfortable", back: "bequem", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "the childhood", back: "die Kindheit", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the childhoods", back: "die Kindheiten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the couple", back: "das Paar", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the couples", back: "die Paare", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the decision", back: "die Entscheidung", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the decisions", back: "die Entscheidungen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the survey", back: "die Umfrage", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the surveys", back: "die Umfragen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the world", back: "die Welt", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "the worlds", back: "die Welten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "the experience", back: "das Erlebnis", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the experiences", back: "die Erlebnisse", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the article", back: "der Artikel", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "to be (infinitive)", back: "sein", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "been gone (perfect)", back: "sein weg gewesen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the religion", back: "die Religion", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the religions", back: "die Religionen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the surprise", back: "die Überraschung", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the surprises", back: "die Überraschungen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "crazy", back: "verrückt", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the profit/win", back: "der Gewinn", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the profits/wins", back: "die Gewinne", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the tax", back: "die Steuer", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the voice", back: "die Stimme", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the voices", back: "die Stimmen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to sit down", back: "sich setzen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has sat down", back: "hat sich gesetzt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "brave", back: "mutig", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the report/message", back: "die Meldung", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the reports/messages", back: "die Meldungen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the headline", back: "die Überschrift", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the headlines", back: "die Überschriften", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "during/while", back: "während", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "to disappear", back: "verschwinden", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has disappeared", back: "ist verschwunden", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "several/multiple (prefix)", back: "mehrer-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "in vain", back: "vergeblich", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "to climb/rise", back: "steigen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has climbed/risen", back: "ist gestiegen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to wonder/to be surprised", back: "sich wundern", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has wondered/been surprised", back: "hat sich gewundert", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "indeed/namely", back: "zwar", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the courage", back: "der Mut", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "both (prefix)", back: "beid-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "to reach", back: "erreichen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has reached", back: "hat erreicht", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "deep", back: "tief", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "to confuse/mistake", back: "verwechseln", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has confused/mistaken", back: "hat verwechselt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the means/medium", back: "das Mittel", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "united/some (prefix)", back: "einig-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "to be located/to find oneself", back: "sich befinden", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has been located/found oneself", back: "hat sich befunden", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to reflect/think about", back: "nachdenken", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has reflected/thought about", back: "hat nachgedacht", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the information/detail", back: "die Angabe", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the informations/details", back: "die Angaben", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to save", back: "retten", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has saved", back: "hat gerettet", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to suffice/be enough", back: "ausreichen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has sufficed/been enough", back: "hat ausgereicht", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the annoyance/anger", back: "der Ärger", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "to follow", back: "folgen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has followed", back: "ist gefolgt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "at least", back: "zumindest", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "to cancel", back: "absagen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has cancelled", back: "hat abgesagt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to call/shout", back: "rufen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has called/shouted", back: "hat gerufen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to block/cordon off", back: "absperren", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has blocked/cordoned off", back: "hat abgesperrt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to arrest", back: "festnehmen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has arrested", back: "hat festgenommen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "drunk", back: "betrunken", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the burglar", back: "der Einbrecher", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "exciting", back: "aufregend", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "funny", back: "witzig", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the motor scooter", back: "der Motorroller", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "to be (infinitive)", back: "sein", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has been in love", back: "ist verliebt gewesen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to break", back: "brechen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has broken", back: "ist/hat gebrochen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the (male) coach", back: "der Trainer", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the (female) coach", back: "die Trainerin", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the (female) coaches", back: "die Trainerinnen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the field", back: "das Feld", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the fields", back: "die Felder", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "all (prefix)", back: "aller-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the goal/gate", back: "das Tor", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the goals/gates", back: "die Tore", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to flee", back: "fliehen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has fled", back: "ist geflohen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "best (prefix)", back: "best-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the registry office", back: "das Standesamt", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the registry offices", back: "die Standesämter", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to shoot", back: "schießen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has shot", back: "hat geschossen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the damage", back: "der Schaden", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the damages", back: "die Schäden", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the curtain", back: "der Vorhang", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the curtains", back: "die Vorhänge", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "immediate/momentary", back: "augenblicklich", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "to bite", back: "beißen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has bitten", back: "hat gebissen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "to frighten/startle", back: "erschrecken", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "has been startled", back: "ist erschrocken", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the contact", back: "der Kontakt", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the contacts", back: "die Kontakte", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the data", back: "die Daten", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the conversation", back: "das Gespräch", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the conversations", back: "die Gespräche", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the report", back: "der Bericht", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the reports", back: "die Berichte", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the midnight", back: "die Mitternacht", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the stone", back: "der Stein", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the stones", back: "die Steine", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the lion", back: "der Löwe", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the lions", back: "die Löwen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the report/message", back: "die Meldung", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the reports/messages", back: "die Meldungen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the headline", back: "die Überschrift", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the headlines", back: "die Überschriften", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the article", back: "der Artikel", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "the report", back: "der Bericht", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the reports", back: "die Berichte", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the interview", back: "das Interview", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the interviews", back: "die Interviews", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the information", back: "die Information", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the informations", back: "die Informationen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the advertisement/notice", back: "die Anzeige", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "the advertisements/notices", back: "die Anzeigen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "the series", back: "die Serie", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the series (plural)", back: "die Serien", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the episode", back: "die Folge", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the episodes", back: "die Folgen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the character", back: "der Charakter", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the characters", back: "die Charaktere", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "although", back: "obwohl", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "constantly/continuously", back: "dauernd", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "the loser", back: "der Verlierer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the losers", back: "die Verlierer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the guy/type", back: "der Typ", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the guys/types", back: "die Typen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "optimistic", back: "optimistisch", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "the figure/character", back: "die Figur", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the figures/characters", back: "die Figuren", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "unbelievable", back: "unglaublich", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "to invent", back: "erfinden", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has invented", back: "hat erfunden", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the operation", back: "die Operation", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the operations", back: "die Operationen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the blood", back: "das Blut", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "crime/criminal (adj.)", back: "Kriminal", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "to publish", back: "veröffentlichen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has published", back: "hat veröffentlicht", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the case", back: "der Fall", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the cases", back: "die Fälle", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the vocabulary (learning)", back: "der Lernwortschatz", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "today’s/current", back: "heutig", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "to act/trade", back: "handeln", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has acted/traded", back: "hat gehandelt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the past", back: "die Vergangenheit", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "the (female) singer", back: "die Sängerin", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the (female) singers", back: "die Sängerinnen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the band", back: "die Band", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the bands", back: "die Bands", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "to arise/come into being", back: "entstehen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has arisen/come into being", back: "ist entstanden", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "electronic", back: "elektronisch", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "to produce", back: "produzieren", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has produced", back: "hat produziert", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the big city", back: "die Großstadt", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the big cities", back: "die Großstädte", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "meanwhile/in the meantime", back: "inzwischen", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "initially/at the beginning", back: "anfangs", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "so-called", back: "sogenannt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "the song", back: "der Song", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the songs", back: "die Songs", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the hit", back: "der Hit", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the hits", back: "die Hits", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "completely/fully", back: "völlig", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "the humor", back: "der Humor", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "everyday/common", back: "alltäglich", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "the violence", back: "die Gewalt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "to criticize", back: "kritisieren", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has criticized", back: "hat kritisiert", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the star", back: "der Star", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the stars", back: "die Stars", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the scene", back: "die Szene", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "successful", back: "erfolgreich", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "to be occupied with", back: "sich beschäftigen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has been occupied with", back: "hat sich beschäftigt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the unemployment", back: "die Arbeitslosigkeit", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "the camp/warehouse", back: "das Lager", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the camps/warehouses", back: "die Lager", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the relationship/ratio", back: "das Verhältnis", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the relationships/ratios", back: "die Verhältnisse", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "to succeed", back: "gelingen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has succeeded", back: "ist gelungen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the advice/council", back: "der Rat", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "finally/lastly", back: "zuletzt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "to leave", back: "verlassen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has left", back: "hat verlassen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "to accompany", back: "begleiten", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has accompanied", back: "hat begleitet", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the box", back: "die Kiste", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the boxes", back: "die Kisten", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the shore/bank", back: "das Ufer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the shores/banks", back: "die Ufer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "to wash/dishwash", back: "spülen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has washed/dishwashed", back: "hat gespült", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "outside", back: "außen", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "inside", back: "innen", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "to meet/encounter", back: "begegnen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has met/encountered", back: "ist begegnet", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the adventure", back: "das Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the adventures", back: "die Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "to come true/fulfill", back: "sich erfüllen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has come true/fulfilled", back: "hat sich erfüllt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "for that", back: "dafür", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "to agree", back: "zustimmen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "has agreed", back: "hat zugestimmt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the media", back: "die Medien", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the media", back: "die Medien", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the broadcasting/radio", back: "der Rundfunk", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "tight/scarce", back: "knapp", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "double", back: "doppelt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "relative", back: "relativ", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "the series", back: "die Serie", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the series (plural)", back: "die Serien", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the episode", back: "die Folge", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the episodes", back: "die Folgen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the figure/character", back: "die Figur", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the figures/characters", back: "die Figuren", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the character", back: "der Charakter", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the characters", back: "die Charaktere", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "crime/criminal (adj.)", back: "Kriminal", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "the broadcasting/radio", back: "der Rundfunk", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "the adventure", back: "das Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the adventures", back: "die Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the cinema/movie theater", back: "das Kino", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "the cinemas/movie theaters", back: "die Kinos", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "the stomach", back: "der Magen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the stomachs", back: "die Mägen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to persuade", back: "überreden", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has persuaded", back: "hat überredet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to arrange/agree", back: "vereinbaren", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has arranged/agreed", back: "hat vereinbart", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the means/remedy", back: "das Mittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the means/remedies", back: "die Mittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the sleep", back: "der Schlaf", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "the factor", back: "der Faktor", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the factors", back: "die Faktoren", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "at night", back: "nachts", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "the basis/foundation", back: "die Grundlage", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the bases/foundations", back: "die Grundlagen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "sufficient/enough", back: "ausreichend", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "to pay attention/watch", back: "achten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has paid attention/watched", back: "hat geachtet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the fat", back: "das Fett", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the fats", back: "die Fette", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "ideal", back: "ideal", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "likewise/also", back: "ebenfalls", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "to breathe", back: "atmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has breathed", back: "hat geatmet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "flat/shallow", back: "flach", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "the effect", back: "die Wirkung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the effects", back: "die Wirkungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "more often/frequently", back: "öfter", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "the strength/power", back: "die Kraft", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the strengths/powers", back: "die Kräfte", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "simultaneously", back: "gleichzeitig", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "exhausted", back: "erschöpft", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "the result", back: "das Ergebnis", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the results", back: "die Ergebnisse", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to handle/deal with", back: "umgehen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has handled/dealt with", back: "ist umgegangen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to wake up", back: "aufwachen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "have woken up", back: "bist aufgewacht", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the lack/deficiency", back: "der Mangel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the lacks/deficiencies", back: "die Mängel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "extreme", back: "extrem", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "to measure", back: "messen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has measured", back: "hat gemessen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to lose weight", back: "abnehmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has lost weight", back: "hat abgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the weight", back: "das Gewicht", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "to examine/investigate", back: "untersuchen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has examined/investigated", back: "hat untersucht", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the trash bin", back: "der Abfalleimer", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the trash bins", back: "die Abfalleimer", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the improvement", back: "die Verbesserung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the improvements", back: "die Verbesserungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the intake (e.g. medicine)", back: "die Einnahme", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "such", back: "solch", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "the expert/professional", back: "der Fachmann", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the experts/professionals", back: "die Fachmänner", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the shoulder", back: "die Schulter", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the shoulders", back: "die Schultern", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "at first/initially", back: "zunächst", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "to suppose/assume", back: "vermuten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has supposed/assumed", back: "hat vermutet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the disturbance/disorder", back: "die Störung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the disturbances/disorders", back: "die Störungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the painkiller", back: "das Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the painkillers", back: "die Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to lead", back: "führen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has led", back: "hat geführt", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to prescribe", back: "verschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has prescribed", back: "hat verschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to receive/get", back: "erhalten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has received/get", back: "hat erhalten", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to take off/remove/lose weight", back: "abnehmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has taken off/removed/lost weight", back: "hat abgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the well-being", back: "das Wohl", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "for free/in vain", back: "umsonst", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "to participate", back: "teilnehmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has participated", back: "hat teilgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the performance/achievement", back: "die Leistung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the performances/achievements", back: "die Leistungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to vaccinate", back: "impfen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has vaccinated", back: "hat geimpft", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to do/engage in (sports etc.)", back: "treiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has done/engaged in", back: "hat getrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the half", back: "die Hälfte", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the halves", back: "die Hälften", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the quarter", back: "das Viertel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the quarters", back: "die Viertel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the third", back: "das Drittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the thirds", back: "die Drittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "basically/fundamentally", back: "grundsätzlich", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "the fruit", back: "die Frucht", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the fruits", back: "die Früchte", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to do without/renounce", back: "verzichten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has done without/renounced", back: "hat verzichtet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the curd/quark", back: "der Quark", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "the vitamin", back: "das Vitamin", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the vitamins", back: "die Vitamine", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to report sick", back: "krankmelden", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has reported sick", back: "hat krankgemeldet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to certify sick leave", back: "krankschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has certified sick leave", back: "hat krankgeschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the conference", back: "die Konferenz", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the conferences", back: "die Konferenzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the writing pad/notepad", back: "der Schreibblock", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the writing pads/notepads", back: "die Schreibblöcke", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the lab", back: "das Labor", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the labs", back: "die Labors / die Labore", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the bandage/association", back: "der Verband", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the bandages/associations", back: "die Verbände", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the syringe/injection", back: "die Spritze", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the syringes/injections", back: "die Spritzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to examine (someone/something)", back: "untersuchen (jemanden/etwas)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has examined", back: "hat untersucht", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to vaccinate (someone)", back: "impfen (jemanden)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has vaccinated", back: "hat geimpft", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the medication", back: "das Medikament", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the medications", back: "die Medikamente", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to prescribe", back: "verschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has prescribed", back: "hat verschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "someone", back: "jemanden", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "to certify sick leave", back: "krankschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has certified sick leave", back: "hat krankgeschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the syringe/injection", back: "die Spritze", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the syringes/injections", back: "die Spritzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the bandage/association", back: "der Verband", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the bandages/associations", back: "die Verbände", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the painkiller", back: "das Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the painkillers", back: "die Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the ointment/salve", back: "die Salbe", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the ointments/salves", back: "die Salben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the pain", back: "der Schmerz", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the pains", back: "die Schmerzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the cold (illness)", back: "der Schnupfen", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "to measure (blood pressure)", back: "messen (den Blutdruck)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has measured", back: "hat gemessen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to take (blood)", back: "abnehmen (Blut)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has taken", back: "hat abgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "to check (the weight)", back: "prüfen (das Gewicht)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "has checked", back: "hat geprüft", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the belly/stomach", back: "der Bauch", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "the bellies/stomachs", back: "die Bäuche", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "the fever", back: "das Fieber", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "the cough", back: "der Husten", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "about what/over what", back: "worüber", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "the hurry/rush", back: "die Eile", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "the cellar/basement", back: "der Keller", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the cellars/basements", back: "die Keller", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "there/then/because", back: "da", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "the sentence/phrase", back: "der Satz", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the sentences/phrases", back: "die Sätze", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "that/there (prefix)", back: "da(r)-", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "really/at all", back: "gar", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "in any case/anyway", back: "jedenfalls", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "to smile", back: "lächeln", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has smiled", back: "hat gelächelt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "just/simply", back: "halt", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "clear/distinct", back: "deutlich", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "so much", back: "so viel", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "to plan/intend", back: "vorhaben", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has planned/intended", back: "hat vorgehabt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the truth", back: "die Wahrheit", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the truths", back: "die Wahrheiten", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "to lie", back: "lügen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has lied", back: "hat gelogen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "to end/finish", back: "beenden", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has ended/finished", back: "hat beendet", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the training/apprenticeship place", back: "der Ausbildungsplatz", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the training/apprenticeship places", back: "die Ausbildungsplätze", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "to choose/select", back: "aussuchen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has chosen/selected", back: "hat ausgesucht", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the president (m/f)", back: "der Präsident / die Präsidentin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the presidents (m/f)", back: "die Präsidenten / die Präsidentinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the wallet/purse", back: "das Portemonnaie", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the wallets/purses", back: "die Portemonnaies", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "fluent", back: "fließend", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "therefore/that's why", back: "deswegen", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "sometime/eventually", back: "irgendwann", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "to translate", back: "übersetzen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has translated", back: "hat übersetzt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "therefore/from there", back: "daher", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "the mother tongue", back: "die Muttersprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the mother tongues", back: "die Muttersprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the pronunciation", back: "die Aussprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "therefore/about that", back: "darum", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "to write down", back: "aufschreiben", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has written down", back: "hat aufgeschrieben", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the expression/phrase", back: "der Ausdruck", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the expressions/phrases", back: "die Ausdrücke", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "once again/again", back: "noch mal", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "the mechanic (male)", back: "der Mechaniker", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the mechanics (male)", back: "die Mechaniker", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the mechanic (female)", back: "die Mechanikerin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the mechanics (female)", back: "die Mechanikerinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the repetition/review", back: "die Wiederholung", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the repetitions/reviews", back: "die Wiederholungen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the cafeteria/canteen", back: "die Mensa", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the cafeterias/canteens", back: "die Mensen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the integration course", back: "der Integrationskurs", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the integration courses", back: "die Integrationskurse", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the origin/background", back: "die Herkunft", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the origins/backgrounds", back: "die Herkünfte", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "to hide oneself", back: "sich verstecken", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has hidden oneself", back: "hat sich versteckt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "cool", back: "cool", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "the Greek language", back: "das Griechisch", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "the Greek (male)", back: "der Grieche", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the Greeks (male)", back: "die Griechen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the Greek (female)", back: "die Griechin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the Greeks (female)", back: "die Griechinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "confused/mixed up", back: "durcheinander", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "at the latest/by", back: "spätestens", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "to choose/vote", back: "wählen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has chosen/voted", back: "hat gewählt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "to originate/come from", back: "stammen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has originated/came from", back: "hat gestammt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the sauce", back: "die Soße", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the sauces", back: "die Soßen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "gradually", back: "allmählich", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "the nerve", back: "der Nerv", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the nerves", back: "die Nerven", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "strange/odd", back: "merkwürdig", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "correct", back: "korrekt", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "on the other hand", back: "andererseits", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "likewise/as well", back: "ebenso", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "the forehead", back: "die Stirn", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the foreheads", back: "die Stirnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "to suffer", back: "leiden", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has suffered", back: "hat gelitten", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "to mix", back: "mischen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has mixed", back: "hat gemischt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "however", back: "allerdings", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "to pass/exist", back: "bestehen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has passed/existed", back: "hat bestanden", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the author (male)", back: "der Autor", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the authors (male)", back: "die Autoren", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the author (female)", back: "die Autorin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the authors (female)", back: "die Autorinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the knowledge/skills", back: "die Kenntnisse", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the knowledge/skills", back: "die Kenntnisse", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "to compare", back: "vergleichen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has compared", back: "hat verglichen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the partner (male)", back: "der Partner", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the partners (male)", back: "die Partner", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the partner (female)", back: "die Partnerin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the partners (female)", back: "die Partnerinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "to scold/complain", back: "schimpfen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has scolded/complained", back: "hat geschimpft", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the script/writing", back: "die Schrift", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the scripts/writings", back: "die Schriften", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the mother tongue", back: "die Muttersprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the mother tongues", back: "die Muttersprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the foreign language", back: "die Fremdsprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the foreign languages", back: "die Fremdsprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the language school", back: "die Sprachenschule", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the language schools", back: "die Sprachenschulen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the pronunciation", back: "die Aussprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the pronunciations", back: "die Aussprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "the script/writing", back: "die Schrift", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "the scripts/writings", back: "die Schriften", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "fluent", back: "fließend", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "to translate", back: "übersetzen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "has translated", back: "hat übersetzt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "to/at/by", back: "zu", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "the talent", back: "das Talent", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the talents", back: "die Talente", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "about/approximately", back: "etwa", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "to suffice/be enough", back: "genügen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has sufficed/been enough", back: "hat genügt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "to stop/cease", back: "aufhören", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has stopped/ceased", back: "hat aufgehört", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the trade/business", back: "der Handel", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "the advantage/benefit", back: "der Vorteil", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the advantages/benefits", back: "die Vorteile", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "to expect", back: "erwarten", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has expected", back: "hat erwartet", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the prerequisite/condition", back: "die Voraussetzung", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the prerequisites/conditions", back: "die Voraussetzungen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the service employee (male)", back: "der Serviceangestellte", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the service employees (male/mixed)", back: "die Serviceangestellten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the service employee (female)", back: "die Serviceangestellte", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the service employees (female)", back: "die Serviceangestellten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the documents/material", back: "die Unterlagen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the documents/materials", back: "die Unterlagen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the task/job", back: "die Aufgabe", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the tasks/jobs", back: "die Aufgaben", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the support", back: "die Unterstützung", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the supports", back: "die Unterstützungen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "in writing/written", back: "schriftlich", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "to determine/ascertain", back: "feststellen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has determined/ascertained", back: "hat festgestellt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "accustomed/used to", back: "gewohnt", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "usual/common", back: "üblich", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "the facility/attachment", back: "die Anlage", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the facilities/attachments", back: "die Anlagen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the CV/resume", back: "der Lebenslauf", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the CVs/resumes", back: "die Lebensläufe", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "to develop", back: "entwickeln", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has developed", back: "hat entwickelt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "to produce/manufacture", back: "herstellen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has produced/manufactured", back: "hat hergestellt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the activity/occupation", back: "die Tätigkeit", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the activities/occupations", back: "die Tätigkeiten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "outside/of", back: "außerhalb", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "inside/within", back: "innerhalb", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "the point in time/moment", back: "der Zeitpunkt", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the points in time/moments", back: "die Zeitpunkte", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "to calculate/count", back: "rechnen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has calculated/counted", back: "hat gerechnet", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the mirror", back: "der Spiegel", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the mirrors", back: "die Spiegel", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "to calm down", back: "sich beruhigen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has calmed down", back: "hat sich beruhigt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "technical", back: "technisch", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "responsible", back: "zuständig", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "together", back: "zusammen-", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "the responsibility", back: "die Verantwortung", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "the painter (male)", back: "der Maler", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the painters (male)", back: "die Maler", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the painter (female)", back: "die Malerin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the painters (female)", back: "die Malerinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the order/assignment", back: "der Auftrag", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the orders/assignments", back: "die Aufträge", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the translator (male)", back: "der Übersetzer", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the translators (male)", back: "die Übersetzer", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the translator (female)", back: "die Übersetzerin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the translators (female)", back: "die Übersetzerinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "to think over/consider", back: "sich überlegen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has thought over/considered", back: "hat überlegt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the competition", back: "die Konkurrenz", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "on the side/by the way", back: "nebenbei", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "to do casual jobs/side jobs", back: "jobben", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has done casual/side jobs", back: "hat gejobbt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "to manage/get along", back: "zurechtkommen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has managed/gotten along", back: "ist zurechtgekommen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the zoo/animal park", back: "der Tierpark", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the zoos/animal parks", back: "die Tierparks", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the further training", back: "die Fortbildung", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the further trainings", back: "die Fortbildungen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "to represent", back: "vertreten", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "has represented", back: "hat vertreten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the teacher (male)", back: "der Lehrer", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the teachers (male)", back: "die Lehrer", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the teacher (female)", back: "die Lehrerin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the teachers (female)", back: "die Lehrerinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the janitor/caretaker (male)", back: "der Hausmeister", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the janitors/caretakers (male)", back: "die Hausmeister", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the janitor/caretaker (female)", back: "die Hausmeisterin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the janitors/caretakers (female)", back: "die Hausmeisterinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the doctor (male)", back: "der Arzt", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the doctors (male)", back: "die Ärzte", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the doctor (female)", back: "die Ärztin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the doctors (female)", back: "die Ärztinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the architect (male)", back: "der Architekt", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the architects (male)", back: "die Architekten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the architect (female)", back: "die Architektin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the architects (female)", back: "die Architektinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the hairdresser (male)", back: "der Friseur", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the hairdressers (male)", back: "die Friseure", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the hairdresser (female)", back: "die Friseurin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the hairdressers (female)", back: "die Friseurinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the journalist (male)", back: "der Journalist", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the journalists (male)", back: "die Journalisten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the nurse (male)", back: "der Krankenpfleger", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the nurses (male)", back: "die Krankenpfleger", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the journalist (female)", back: "die Journalistin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the journalists (female)", back: "die Journalistinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the nurse (female)", back: "die Krankenschwester", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the nurses (female)", back: "die Krankenschwestern", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the police officer (male)", back: "der Polizist", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the police officers (male)", back: "die Polizisten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the police officer (female)", back: "die Polizistin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the police officers (female)", back: "die Polizistinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the salesperson (male)", back: "der Verkäufer", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the salespersons (male)", back: "die Verkäufer", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "the salesperson (female)", back: "die Verkäuferin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "the salespersons (female)", back: "die Verkäuferinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "instead of", back: "statt", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "first- (prefix)", back: "erst-", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the production", back: "die Produktion", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the productions", back: "die Produktionen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the replacement", back: "der Ersatz", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "certain/specific", back: "bestimmt", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "to solve/release", back: "lösen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has solved/released", back: "hat gelöst", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the secret", back: "das Geheimnis", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the secrets", back: "die Geheimnisse", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the risk", back: "das Risiko", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the risks", back: "die Risiken", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the change", back: "die Änderung", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the changes", back: "die Änderungen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the sense/meaning", back: "der Sinn", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "to be worth it", back: "sich lohnen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has been worth it", back: "hat gelohnt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the season", back: "die Jahreszeit", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the seasons", back: "die Jahreszeiten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to own/possess", back: "besitzen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has owned/possessed", back: "hat besessen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to be born", back: "geboren werden", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has been born", back: "ist geboren worden", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to decide", back: "sich entschließen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has decided", back: "hat entschlossen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the homesickness", back: "das Heimweh", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the competition", back: "der Wettbewerb", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the competitions", back: "die Wettbewerbe", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the spice", back: "das Gewürz", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the spices", back: "die Gewürze", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "meanwhile/by now", back: "mittlerweile", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the consideration/respect", back: "die Rücksicht", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the considerations/respects", back: "die Rücksichten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "intercultural", back: "interkulturell", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "to found/establish", back: "gründen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has founded/established", back: "hat gegründet", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to look after/supervise", back: "betreuen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has looked after/supervised", back: "hat betreut", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to get used to", back: "sich gewöhnen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has gotten used to", back: "hat gewöhnt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to care for/maintain", back: "pflegen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has cared for/maintained", back: "hat gepflegt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "for years", back: "jahrelang", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the businessman (male)", back: "der Kaufmann", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the businessmen", back: "die Kaufleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the businesswoman (female)", back: "die Kauffrau", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the businesswomen", back: "die Kauffrauen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the experiment", back: "das Experiment", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the experiments", back: "die Experimente", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "financial", back: "finanziell", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the businesspeople", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the businesspeople", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "exclusively", back: "ausschließlich", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the ingredient", back: "die Zutat", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the ingredients", back: "die Zutaten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "at most/maximum", back: "höchstens", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the studio", back: "das Studio", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the studios", back: "die Studios", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "in order to", back: "um … zu", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "as … as possible", back: "möglichst", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the speech", back: "die Rede", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the speeches", back: "die Reden", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the compromise", back: "der Kompromiss", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the compromises", back: "die Kompromisse", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the air conditioning", back: "die Klimaanlage", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the air conditioning units", back: "die Klimaanlagen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the software", back: "die Software", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the softwares (rare plural)", back: "die Softwares", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to come back/return", back: "wiederkommen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has come back/returned", back: "ist wiedergekommen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the effort/trouble", back: "die Mühe", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the efforts/troubles", back: "die Mühen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the toothpaste", back: "die Zahncreme", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the toothpastes", back: "die Zahncremes", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the detergent", back: "das Waschmittel", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the brush", back: "die Bürste", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the brushes", back: "die Bürsten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to greet", back: "begrüßen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has greeted", back: "hat begrüßt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to say goodbye", back: "sich verabschieden", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has said goodbye", back: "hat verabschiedet", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the role", back: "die Rolle", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the roles", back: "die Rollen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the claim/demand", back: "der Anspruch", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the claims/demands", back: "die Ansprüche", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to confirm", back: "bestätigen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has confirmed", back: "hat bestätigt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the copy", back: "die Kopie", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the copies", back: "die Kopien", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to damage", back: "beschädigen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has damaged", back: "hat beschädigt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "annoying/irritating", back: "ärgerlich", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the user manual/instruction", back: "die Bedienungsanleitung", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the user manuals/instructions", back: "die Bedienungsanleitungen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to exchange/return", back: "umtauschen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has exchanged/returned", back: "hat umgetauscht", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "however/yet", back: "jedoch", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "already", back: "bereits", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "to demand/require", back: "fordern", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has demanded/required", back: "hat gefordert", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to disappoint", back: "enttäuschen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has disappointed", back: "hat enttäuscht", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to request/urge", back: "auffordern", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has requested/urged", back: "hat aufgefordert", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the business/operation", back: "der Betrieb", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the businesses/operations", back: "die Betriebe", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the company/firm", back: "die Firma", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the companies/firms", back: "die Firmen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the production", back: "die Produktion", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the productions", back: "die Produktionen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the trade/business", back: "der Handel", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "the risk", back: "das Risiko", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the risks", back: "die Risiken", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the businesspeople", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the businesspeople", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the businessman (male)", back: "der Kaufmann", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the businessmen", back: "die Kaufleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the businesswoman (female)", back: "die Kauffrau", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "the businesswomen", back: "die Kauffrauen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "to found/establish", back: "gründen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "has founded/established", back: "hat gegründet", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "the court/dish", back: "das Gericht", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the courts/dishes", back: "die Gerichte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the trial/process", back: "der Prozess", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the trials/processes", back: "die Prozesse", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "to burn", back: "brennen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "has burned", back: "hat gebrannt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the noise", back: "der Lärm", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the lawyer (male)", back: "der Rechtsanwalt", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the lawyers (male)", back: "die Rechtsanwälte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the lawyer (female)", back: "die Rechtsanwältin", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the lawyers (female)", back: "die Rechtsanwältinnen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the property/plot", back: "das Grundstück", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the properties/plots", back: "die Grundstücke", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "to suspect", back: "verdächtigen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "has suspected", back: "hat verdächtigt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the peace", back: "der Frieden", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the reality", back: "die Wirklichkeit", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the realities", back: "die Wirklichkeiten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the lawn", back: "der Rasen", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the federal state", back: "das Bundesland", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the federal states", back: "die Bundesländer", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "each other (suffix)", back: "-einander", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the lawyer (male)", back: "der Anwalt", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the lawyers (male)", back: "die Anwälte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the lawyer (female)", back: "die Anwältin", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the lawyers (female)", back: "die Anwältinnen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "either ... or", back: "entweder ... oder", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "central", back: "zentral", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the duty/obligation", back: "die Pflicht", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the duties/obligations", back: "die Pflichten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the property/ownership", back: "das Eigentum", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the owners", back: "die Eigentümer", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "to scream/shout", back: "schreien", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "has screamed/shouted", back: "hat geschrien", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "with each other", back: "miteinander", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the eraser", back: "der Radiergummi", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the erasers", back: "die Radiergummis", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the pencil", back: "der Bleistift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the pencils", back: "die Bleistifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the colored pencil", back: "der Farbstift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the colored pencils", back: "die Farbstifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "to discover", back: "entdecken", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "has discovered", back: "hat entdeckt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "angry", back: "wütend", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the puzzle", back: "das Puzzle", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the puzzles", back: "die Puzzles", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the ban/prohibition", back: "das Verbot", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the bans/prohibitions", back: "die Verbote", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "just/only", back: "bloß", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "here (to this place)", back: "hierher", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "attentive/alert", back: "aufmerksam", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "to agree/detach", back: "abmachen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "has agreed/detached", back: "hat abgemacht", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "indeed/actually", back: "tatsächlich", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the cheek/impudence", back: "die Frechheit", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the cheekiness/impudences", back: "die Frechheiten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "for my sake/as far as I am concerned", back: "meinetwegen", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "to concern/start", back: "angehen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "has concerned/started", back: "ist angegangen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the elevator", back: "der Lift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the elevators", back: "die Lifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the terrace", back: "die Terrasse", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the terraces", back: "die Terrassen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "any-/some- (prefix)", back: "irgend-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the city center", back: "die Innenstadt", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the city centers", back: "die Innenstädte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the cross street", back: "die Querstraße", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the cross streets", back: "die Querstraßen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "essential/significant", back: "wesentlich", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the alternative", back: "die Alternative", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the alternatives", back: "die Alternativen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the edge/border", back: "der Rand", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the edges/borders", back: "die Ränder", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the link", back: "der Link", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the links", back: "die Links", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "where- (prefix)", back: "wo(r)-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "to be missing/lack", back: "fehlen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "has been missing/lacked", back: "hat gefehlt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the state", back: "der Staat", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the states", back: "die Staaten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "east- (prefix)", back: "Ost-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "west- (prefix)", back: "West-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the wall", back: "die Mauer", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the walls", back: "die Mauern", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the government", back: "die Regierung", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the governments", back: "die Regierungen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "to reign/rule", back: "herrschen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "has reigned/ruled", back: "hat geherrscht", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the step/level", back: "die Stufe", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the steps/levels", back: "die Stufen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "in the middle", back: "mitten", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "angular/edgy", back: "eckig", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "northern", back: "nördlich", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the earth/soil", back: "die Erde", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the earths/soils", back: "die Erden", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the chance/opportunity", back: "die Chance", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the chances/opportunities", back: "die Chancen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "to enlarge", back: "vergrößern", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "has enlarged", back: "hat vergrößert", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "long ago/already", back: "längst", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "despite/in spite of", back: "trotz", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the building/construction", back: "der Bau", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the buildings/constructions", back: "die Bauten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the permission/approval", back: "die Genehmigung", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the permissions/approvals", back: "die Genehmigungen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the tourism", back: "der Tourismus", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "same- (prefix)", back: "gleich-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the building", back: "das Gebäude", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the roof", back: "das Dach", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the roofs", back: "die Dächer", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the house", back: "das Haus", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the houses", back: "die Häuser", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the wall", back: "die Mauer", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the walls", back: "die Mauern", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the property/plot", back: "das Grundstück", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the properties/plots", back: "die Grundstücke", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the staircase", back: "die Treppe", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the staircases", back: "die Treppen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the step/level", back: "die Stufe", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the steps/levels", back: "die Stufen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the door", back: "die Tür", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the doors", back: "die Türen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the window", back: "das Fenster", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the cellar/basement", back: "der Keller", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "the elevator", back: "der Lift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the elevators", back: "die Lifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the terrace", back: "die Terrasse", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the terraces", back: "die Terrassen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the garden", back: "der Garten", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the gardens", back: "die Gärten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the balcony", back: "der Balkon", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "the balconies", back: "die Balkone", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "the lawn", back: "der Rasen", lesson: "B1.7" }
  ],
  russian: [
  { front: "я", back: "ich", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "называться", back: "heißen", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "имели название", back: "haben geheißen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "имя", back: "der Name", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "имена", back: "die Namen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "приходить", back: "kommen", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "пришли", back: "sein gekommen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "Германия", back: "das Deutschland", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "говорить", back: "sprechen", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "говорили", back: "haben gesprochen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "немецкий (язык)", back: "das Deutsch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "и", back: "und", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "немного", back: "ein bisschen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "добрый день", back: "guten Tag", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "привет", back: "hallo", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "до свидания", back: "auf Wiedersehen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "пока", back: "tschüs", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "господин", back: "der Herr", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "господа", back: "die Herren", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "ребёнок", back: "das Kind", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "дети", back: "die Kinder", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "добрый вечер", back: "guten Abend", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "дама", back: "die Dame", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "дамы", back: "die Damen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "добро пожаловать", back: "willkommen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "у/при", back: "bei", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "музыка", back: "die Musik", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "международный", back: "international", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "доброе утро", back: "guten Morgen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "женщина", back: "die Frau", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "женщины", back: "die Frauen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "благодарить", back: "danken", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "благодарили", back: "haben gedankt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "спокойной ночи", back: "gute Nacht", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "папа", back: "der Papa", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "папы", back: "die Papas", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "быть", back: "sein", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "был/были", back: "gewesen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "извинение", back: "die Entschuldigung", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "извинения", back: "die Entschuldigungen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "как", back: "wie", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "она/они", back: "sie", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "кто", back: "wer", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "да", back: "ja", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "нет", back: "nein", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "откуда", back: "woher", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "из", back: "aus", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "ты", back: "du", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Австрия", back: "Österreich", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Швейцария", back: "die Schweiz", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "ага", back: "aha", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "классно", back: "toll", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "интересно", back: "interessant", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "что", back: "was", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "тоже", back: "auch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "язык", back: "die Sprache", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "языки", back: "die Sprachen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "буква", back: "der Buchstabe", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "буквы", back: "die Buchstaben", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "алфавит", back: "das Alphabet", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "что, простите?", back: "wie bitte?", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "произносить по буквам", back: "buchstabieren", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "произносили по буквам", back: "haben buchstabiert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "пожалуйста", back: "bitte", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "фирма", back: "die Firma", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "фирмы", back: "die Firmen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "большое спасибо", back: "vielen Dank", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "до свидания (по телефону)", back: "auf Wiederhören", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "адрес", back: "die Adresse", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "адреса", back: "die Adressen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "визитная карточка", back: "die Visitenkarte", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "визитные карточки", back: "die Visitenkarten", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "имя (личное)", back: "der Vorname", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "имена (личные)", back: "die Vornamen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "фамилия", back: "der Familienname", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "фамилии", back: "die Familiennamen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "улица", back: "die Straße", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "улицы", back: "die Straßen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "город", back: "die Stadt", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "города", back: "die Städte", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "страна", back: "das Land", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "страны", back: "die Länder", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "электронная почта", back: "die E-Mail", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "электронные письма", back: "die E-Mails", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "телефон", back: "das Telefon", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "телефоны", back: "die Telefone", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "форма (документ)", back: "das Formular", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "формы", back: "die Formulare", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "курс", back: "der Kurs", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "курсы", back: "die Kurse", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "иностранный язык", back: "die Fremdsprache", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "иностранные языки", back: "die Fremdsprachen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "регистрация", back: "die Anmeldung", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "регистрации", back: "die Anmeldungen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "почтовый индекс", back: "die Postleitzahl", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "почтовые индексы", back: "die Postleitzahlen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "учите слова", back: "lernen Sie Wörter", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "турецкий", back: "türkisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "немецкий", back: "deutsch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Польша", back: "Polen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "польский", back: "polnisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Турция", back: "die Türkei", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Испания", back: "Spanien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Венгрия", back: "Ungarn", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Германия", back: "Deutschland", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Австрия", back: "Österreich", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "турецкий", back: "türkisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "испанский", back: "spanisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "венгерский", back: "ungarisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "немецкий", back: "deutsch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Швейцария", back: "die Schweiz", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Румыния", back: "Rumänien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Сирия", back: "Syrien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Болгария", back: "Bulgarien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Италия", back: "Italien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Греция", back: "Griechenland", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "румынский", back: "rumänisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "арабский", back: "arabisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "болгарский", back: "bulgarisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "итальянский", back: "italienisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "греческий", back: "griechisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "учить", back: "lernen", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "учили", back: "haben gelernt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "парк", back: "der Park", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "парки", back: "die Parks", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "пауза", back: "die Pause", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "паузы", back: "die Pausen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "семья", back: "die Familie", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "семьи", back: "die Familien", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "отец", back: "der Vater", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "отцы", back: "die Väter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "бабушка и дедушка", back: "die Großeltern", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "мать", back: "die Mutter", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "матери", back: "die Mütter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "родители", back: "die Eltern", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "брат", back: "der Bruder", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "братья", back: "die Brüder", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "братья и сестры", back: "die Geschwister", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "год", back: "das Jahr", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "годы", back: "die Jahre", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "жить", back: "leben", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "жили", back: "haben gelebt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "в", back: "in", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "хороший", back: "gut", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "супер", back: "super", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "ну да", back: "na ja", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "ах", back: "ach", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "так", back: "so", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "очень", back: "sehr", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "внук", back: "der Enkel", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "внуки", back: "die Enkel", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "внучка", back: "die Enkelin", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "внучки", back: "die Enkelinnen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "дочь", back: "die Tochter", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "дочери", back: "die Töchter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "сын", back: "der Sohn", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "сыновья", back: "die Söhne", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "сестра", back: "die Schwester", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "сёстры", back: "die Schwestern", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "бабушка", back: "die Oma", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "бабушки", back: "die Omas", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "мужчина, муж", back: "der Mann", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "мужчины", back: "die Männer", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "дедушка", back: "der Opa", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "дедушки", back: "die Opas", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "твой", back: "dein", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "мой", back: "mein", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "её / их / ваш", back: "ihr", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "муж", back: "der Ehemann", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "мужья", back: "die Ehemänner", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "жена", back: "die Ehefrau", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "жены", back: "die Ehefrauen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "неправильный", back: "falsch", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "она / они", back: "sie", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "вместе", back: "zusammen", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "она / они", back: "sie", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "разведённый", back: "geschieden", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "он", back: "er", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "жить (где-то)", back: "wohnen", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "жили", back: "haben gewohnt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "сейчас", back: "jetzt", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "вы (мн.ч.)", back: "ihr", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "мы", back: "wir", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "число", back: "die Zahl", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "числа", back: "die Zahlen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "где", back: "wo", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "рожденный", back: "geboren", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "номер", back: "die Nummer", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "номера", back: "die Nummern", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "женатый / замужняя", back: "verheiratet", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "иметь", back: "haben", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "имели", back: "haben gehabt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "место рождения", back: "der Geburtsort", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "места рождения", back: "die Geburtsorte", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "место жительства", back: "der Wohnort", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "места жительства", back: "die Wohnorte", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "семейное положение", back: "der Familienstand", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "неженатый / незамужняя", back: "ledig", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "вдовец / вдова", back: "verwitwet", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "возраст", back: "das Alter", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "возраста", back: "die Alter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "север", back: "der Norden", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "восток", back: "der Osten", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "юг", back: "der Süden", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "запад", back: "der Westen", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "столица", back: "die Hauptstadt", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "столицы", back: "die Hauptstädte", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "юг", back: "Süd", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "север", back: "Nord", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "учитель", back: "der Lehrer", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "учителя", back: "die Lehrer", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "учительница", back: "die Lehrerin", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "учительницы", back: "die Lehrerinnen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "немец (мужчина)", back: "der Deutsche", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "немцы (мужчины)", back: "die Deutschen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "немка", back: "die Deutsche", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "немки / немцы (женщины/мужчины)", back: "die Deutschen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "банан", back: "die Banane", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "бананы", back: "die Bananen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "масло", back: "die Butter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "яйцо", back: "das Ei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "яйца", back: "die Eier", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "мука", back: "das Mehl", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "молоко", back: "die Milch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "сахар", back: "der Zucker", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "блин", back: "der Pfannkuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "блины", back: "die Pfannkuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "шоколад", back: "die Schokolade", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "нуждаться", back: "brauchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "нуждались", back: "haben gebraucht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "покупать", back: "kaufen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "покупали", back: "haben gekauft", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "голод", back: "der Hunger", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "евро", back: "der Euro", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "мясо", back: "das Fleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "пиво", back: "das Bier", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "сыр", back: "der Käse", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "соль", back: "das Salz", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "чай", back: "der Tee", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "чаи", back: "die Tees", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "хлеб", back: "das Brot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "хлеба", back: "die Brote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "вино", back: "der Wein", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "вина", back: "die Weine", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "минеральная вода", back: "das Mineralwasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "рис", back: "der Reis", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "рыба", back: "der Fisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "рыбы", back: "die Fische", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "один", back: "ein", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "никакой, не", back: "kein", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "яблоко", back: "der Apfel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "яблоки", back: "die Äpfel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "апельсин", back: "die Orange", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "апельсины", back: "die Orangen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "торт, пирог", back: "der Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "торты, пироги", back: "die Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "кофе", back: "der Kaffee", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "кофе (мн.ч. в значении сорта)", back: "die Kaffees", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "сок", back: "der Saft", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "соки", back: "die Säfte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "булочка", back: "das Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "булочки", back: "die Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "сосиска", back: "das Würstchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "сосиски", back: "die Würstchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "груша", back: "die Birne", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "груши", back: "die Birnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "помидор", back: "die Tomate", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "помидоры", back: "die Tomaten", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "картофель", back: "die Kartoffel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "картофели", back: "die Kartoffeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "йогурт", back: "der Joghurt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "йогурты", back: "die Joghurts", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "лук", back: "die Zwiebel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "луки", back: "die Zwiebeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "полка", back: "das Regal", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "полки", back: "die Regale", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "цена", back: "der Preis", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "цены", back: "die Preise", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "цент", back: "der Cent", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "проспект (буклет)", back: "der Prospekt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "проспекты (буклеты)", back: "die Prospekte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "специальное предложение", back: "das Sonderangebot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "специальные предложения", back: "die Sonderangebote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "продукты питания", back: "das Lebensmittel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "продукты питания", back: "die Lebensmittel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "сколько", back: "wie viel", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "стоить", back: "kosten", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "стоили", back: "haben gekostet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "килограмм", back: "das Kilo(gramm)", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "грамм", back: "das Gramm", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "фунт", back: "das Pfund", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "литр", back: "der Liter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "бутылка", back: "die Flasche", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "бутылки", back: "die Flaschen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "банка", back: "die Dose", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "банки", back: "die Dosen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "сливки", back: "die Sahne", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "колбаса", back: "die Wurst", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "колбасы", back: "die Würste", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "фарш", back: "das Hackfleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "продавец", back: "der Verkäufer", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "продавцы", back: "die Verkäufer", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "продавщица", back: "die Verkäuferin", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "продавщицы", back: "die Verkäuferinnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "клиент", back: "der Kunde", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "клиенты", back: "die Kunden", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "клиентка", back: "die Kundin", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "клиентки", back: "die Kundinnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "ещё", back: "noch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "всё", back: "all", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "хотеть (вежливо)", back: "möchten", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "хотели (вежливо)", back: "haben gewünscht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "находить", back: "finden", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "находили", back: "haben gefunden", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "магазин", back: "der Laden", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "магазины", back: "die Läden", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "фрукты", back: "das Obst", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "овощи", back: "das Gemüse", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "овощи", back: "die Gemüse", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "пекарня", back: "die Bäckerei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "пекарни", back: "die Bäckereien", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "вода", back: "das Wasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "перец", back: "der Pfeffer", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "шоколад", back: "die Schokolade", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "банан", back: "die Banane", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "бананы", back: "die Bananen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "масло", back: "die Butter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "яйцо", back: "das Ei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "яйца", back: "die Eier", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "молоко", back: "die Milch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "хлеб", back: "das Brot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "хлеба", back: "die Brote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "рыба", back: "der Fisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "рыбы", back: "die Fische", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "мясо", back: "das Fleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "сыр", back: "der Käse", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "яблоко", back: "der Apfel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "яблоки", back: "die Äpfel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "груша", back: "die Birne", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "груши", back: "die Birnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "булочка", back: "das Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "булочки", back: "die Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "торт, пирог", back: "der Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "торты, пироги", back: "die Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "апельсин", back: "die Orange", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "апельсины", back: "die Orangen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "сок", back: "der Saft", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "соки", back: "die Säfte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "йогурт", back: "der/ das Joghurt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "йогурты", back: "die Joghurts", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "картофель", back: "die Kartoffel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "картофель", back: "die Kartoffeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "лук", back: "die Zwiebel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "лук (мн.ч.)", back: "die Zwiebeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "помидор", back: "die Tomate", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "помидоры", back: "die Tomaten", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "минеральная вода", back: "das Mineralwasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "квартира", back: "die Wohnung", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "квартиры", back: "die Wohnungen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "лампа", back: "die Lampe", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "лампы", back: "die Lampen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "комната", back: "das Zimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "комнаты", back: "die Zimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "кухня", back: "die Küche", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "кухни", back: "die Küchen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "ванная", back: "das Bad", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "ванные", back: "die Bäder", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "старый", back: "alt", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "новый", back: "neu", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "большой", back: "groß", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "маленький", back: "klein", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "светлый", back: "hell", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "тёмный", back: "dunkel", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "дорогой", back: "teuer", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "дешёвый", back: "billig", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "красивый", back: "schön", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "уродливый", back: "hässlich", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "знать", back: "kennen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "знали", back: "haben gekannt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "коридор", back: "der Flur", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "коридоры", back: "die Flure", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "туалет", back: "die Toilette", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "туалеты", back: "die Toiletten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "балкон", back: "der Balkon", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "балконы", back: "die Balkone", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "гостиная", back: "das Wohnzimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "гостиные", back: "die Wohnzimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "этот, эта, это", back: "der, das, die", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "дом", back: "das Haus", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "дома", back: "die Häuser", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "здесь", back: "hier", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "там", back: "dort", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "но", back: "aber", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "не", back: "nicht", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "месяц", back: "der Monat", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "месяцы", back: "die Monate", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "узкий", back: "schmal", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "правильный", back: "richtig", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "широкий", back: "breit", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "шкаф", back: "der Schrank", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "шкафы", back: "die Schränke", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "холодильник", back: "der Kühlschrank", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "холодильники", back: "die Kühlschränke", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "диван", back: "das Sofa", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "диваны", back: "die Sofas", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "стол", back: "der Tisch", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "столы", back: "die Tische", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "стул", back: "der Stuhl", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "стулья", back: "die Stühle", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "кровать", back: "das Bett", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "кровати", back: "die Betten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "телевизор", back: "der Fernseher", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "телевизоры", back: "die Fernseher", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "душ", back: "die Dusche", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "души", back: "die Duschen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "плита", back: "der Herd", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "плиты", back: "die Herde", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "ванна", back: "die Badewanne", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "ванны", back: "die Badewannen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "ковёр", back: "der Teppich", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "ковры", back: "die Teppiche", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "кресло", back: "der Sessel", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "кресла", back: "die Sessel", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "мебель", back: "die Möbel", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "устройство", back: "das Gerät", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "устройства", back: "die Geräte", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "нравиться", back: "gefallen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "нравились", back: "haben gefallen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "цвет", back: "die Farbe", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "цвета", back: "die Farben", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "находить", back: "finden", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "находили", back: "haben gefunden", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "весь, совсем", back: "ganz", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "современный", back: "modern", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "чёрный", back: "schwarz", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "серый", back: "grau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "белый", back: "weiß", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "зелёный", back: "grün", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "коричневый", back: "braun", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "синий", back: "blau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "красный", back: "rot", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "жёлтый", back: "gelb", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "светло-", back: "hell-", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "темно-", back: "dunkel-", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "сантиметр", back: "der Zentimeter", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "сантиметры", back: "die Zentimeter", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "раз", back: "mal", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "мобильный телефон", back: "das Handy", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "мобильные телефоны", back: "die Handys", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "работа", back: "die Arbeit", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "объявление", back: "die Anzeige", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "объявления", back: "die Anzeigen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "милый", back: "nett", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "супруги", back: "das Ehepaar", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "супруги", back: "die Ehepaare", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "искать", back: "suchen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "искали", back: "haben gesucht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "сад", back: "der Garten", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "сады", back: "die Gärten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "сдавать в аренду", back: "vermieten", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "сдавали в аренду", back: "haben vermietet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "апартамент", back: "das Apartment", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "апартаменты", back: "die Apartments", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "комната, помещение", back: "der Raum", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "комнаты", back: "die Räume", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "этаж", back: "der Stock", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "приблизительно", back: "circa", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "частный", back: "privat", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "коричневый", back: "braun", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "синий", back: "blau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "красный", back: "rot", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "жёлтый", back: "gelb", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "цвета", back: "Farben", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "от", back: "ab", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "сразу", back: "sofort", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "максимальный", back: "maximal", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "звонок", back: "der Anruf", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "звонки", back: "die Anrufe", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "меблированный", back: "möbliert", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "телевизор", back: "das TV", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "телевизоры", back: "die TVs", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "гараж", back: "die Garage", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "гаражи", back: "die Garagen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "квадратный метр", back: "der Quadratmeter", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "квадратные метры", back: "die Quadratmeter", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "только", back: "nur", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "аренда", back: "die Miete", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "аренды", back: "die Mieten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "платить", back: "bezahlen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "платили", back: "haben bezahlt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "продавать", back: "verkaufen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "продавали", back: "haben verkauft", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "что-то", back: "etwas", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "компьютер", back: "der Computer", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "компьютеры", back: "die Computer", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "письменный стол", back: "der Schreibtisch", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "письменные столы", back: "die Schreibtische", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "сегодня", back: "heute", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "какой …?", back: "welche …?", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "значит, итак", back: "also", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "приблизительно", back: "ungefähr", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "метр", back: "der Meter", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "метры", back: "die Meter", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "длинный", back: "lang", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "точный", back: "genau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "видеть", back: "sehen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "видели", back: "haben gesehen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "высокий", back: "hoch", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "завтра", back: "morgen", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "делать", back: "machen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "делали", back: "haben gemacht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "презентация", back: "die Präsentation", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "презентации", back: "die Präsentationen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "завтракать", back: "frühstücken", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "завтракали", back: "haben gefrühstückt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "делать покупки", back: "einkaufen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "делали покупки", back: "haben eingekauft", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "слушать", back: "hören", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "слушали", back: "haben gehört", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "готовить", back: "kochen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "готовили", back: "haben gekocht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "гулять", back: "spazieren gehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "гуляли", back: "sein spaziert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "убирать", back: "aufräumen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "убирали", back: "haben aufgeräumt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "вставать", back: "aufstehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "вставали", back: "sein aufgestanden", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "идти", back: "gehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "шли", back: "sein gegangen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "или", back: "oder", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "уставший", back: "müde", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "звонить", back: "anrufen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "звонили", back: "haben angerufen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "рано", back: "früh", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "супермаркет", back: "der Supermarkt", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "супермаркеты", back: "die Supermärkte", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "смотреть телевизор", back: "fernsehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "смотрели телевизор", back: "haben ferngesehen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "с", back: "mit", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "работать", back: "arbeiten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "работали", back: "haben gearbeitet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "долго", back: "lange", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "играть", back: "spielen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "играли", back: "haben gespielt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "есть", back: "essen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "ели", back: "haben gegessen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "охотно", back: "gern", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "поздно", back: "spät", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "уже", back: "schon", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "сначала", back: "erst", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "квартал", back: "das Viertel", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "кварталы", back: "die Viertel", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "до, перед", back: "vor", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "после", back: "nach", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "половина", back: "halb", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "часы", back: "die Uhr", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "часы", back: "die Uhren", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "короткий", back: "kurz", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "сейчас, одинаковый", back: "gleich", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "интенсивный курс", back: "der Intensivkurs", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "интенсивные курсы", back: "die Intensivkurse", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "начинать", back: "anfangen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "начали", back: "haben angefangen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "в (день, дата)", back: "am", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "понедельник", back: "der Montag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "понедельники", back: "die Montage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "пятница", back: "der Freitag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "пятницы", back: "die Freitage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "четверг", back: "der Donnerstag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "четверги", back: "die Donnerstage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "среда", back: "der Mittwoch", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "среды", back: "die Mittwoche", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "вторник", back: "der Dienstag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "вторники", back: "die Dienstage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "когда", back: "wann", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "в (время)", back: "um", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "заканчивать", back: "enden", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "закончили", back: "haben geendet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "с ... до ...", back: "von ... bis ...", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "вечеринка", back: "die Party", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "вечеринки", back: "die Partys", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "время", back: "die Zeit", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "времена", back: "die Zeiten", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "футбол", back: "der Fußball", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "суббота", back: "der Samstag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "субботы", back: "die Samstage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "воскресенье", back: "der Sonntag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "воскресенья", back: "die Sonntage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "домашнее задание", back: "die Hausaufgabe", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "домашние задания", back: "die Hausaufgaben", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "мама", back: "die Mama", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "мамы", back: "die Mamas", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "спать", back: "schlafen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "спали", back: "haben geschlafen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "выходные", back: "das Wochenende", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "выходные", back: "die Wochenenden", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "следующий", back: "nächst-", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "неделя", back: "die Woche", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "недели", back: "die Wochen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "полдень", back: "der Mittag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "полдни", back: "die Mittage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "утро", back: "der Morgen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "утра", back: "die Morgen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "вечер", back: "der Abend", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "вечера", back: "die Abende", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "послеобеденное время", back: "der Nachmittag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "послеобеденное время", back: "die Nachmittage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "дообеденное время", back: "der Vormittag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "дообеденное время", back: "die Vormittage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "ночь", back: "die Nacht", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "ночи", back: "die Nächte", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "кинотеатр", back: "das Kino", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "кинотеатры", back: "die Kinos", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "спорт", back: "der Sport", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "пить", back: "trinken", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "пили", back: "haben getrunken", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "пицца", back: "die Pizza", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "пиццы", back: "die Pizzen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "чатиться", back: "chatten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "чатились", back: "haben gechattet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "открытый", back: "geöffnet", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "назначенная встреча", back: "der Termin", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "назначенные встречи", back: "die Termine", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "детский сад", back: "der Kindergarten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "детские сады", back: "die Kindergärten", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "магазин", back: "das Geschäft", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "магазины", back: "die Geschäfte", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "библиотека", back: "die Bibliothek", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "библиотеки", back: "die Bibliotheken", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "закрытый", back: "geschlossen", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "открывать", back: "öffnen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "открывали", back: "haben geöffnet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "закрывать", back: "schließen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "закрывали", back: "haben geschlossen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "практика, врачебный кабинет", back: "die Praxis", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "практики, врачебные кабинеты", back: "die Praxen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "день", back: "der Tag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "дни", back: "die Tage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "каждый", back: "jed-", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "детский сад", back: "die Kita", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "детские сады", back: "die Kitas", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "приносить", back: "bringen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "приносили", back: "haben gebracht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "забирать", back: "abholen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "забирали", back: "haben abgeholt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "больше", back: "mehr", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "пример", back: "das Beispiel", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "примеры", back: "die Beispiele", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "например", back: "zum Beispiel", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "снова", back: "wieder", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "друг", back: "der Freund", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "друзья", back: "die Freunde", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "подруга", back: "die Freundin", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "подруги", back: "die Freundinnen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "спрашивать", back: "fragen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "спрашивали", back: "haben gefragt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "отвечать", back: "antworten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "отвечали", back: "haben geantwortet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "полный, совершенно", back: "total", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "экскурсия", back: "der Ausflug", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "экскурсии", back: "die Ausflüge", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "автомобиль", back: "das Auto", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "автомобили", back: "die Autos", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "ходить в поход", back: "wandern", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "ходили в поход", back: "sein gewandert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "пикник", back: "das Picknick", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "пикники", back: "die Picknicks", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "гитара", back: "die Gitarre", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "гитары", back: "die Gitarren", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "звонить по телефону", back: "telefonieren", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "звонили по телефону", back: "haben telefoniert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "погода", back: "das Wetter", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "солнце", back: "die Sonne", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "светить", back: "scheinen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "светили", back: "haben geschienen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "идти (о дожде)", back: "regnen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "шел дождь", back: "haben geregnet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "много", back: "viel-", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "облако", back: "die Wolke", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "облака", back: "die Wolken", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "начать (начинать идти)", back: "los (losgehen)", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "забывать", back: "vergessen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "забывали", back: "haben vergessen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "жажда", back: "der Durst", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "градус", back: "das Grad", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "теплый", back: "warm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "ветреный", back: "windig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "холодный", back: "kalt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "идти (о снеге)", back: "schneien", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "шел снег", back: "haben geschneit", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "пасмурно", back: "bewölkt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "прогноз погоды", back: "der Wetterbericht", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "прогнозы погоды", back: "die Wetterberichte", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "середина", back: "die Mitte", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "везде", back: "überall", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "температура", back: "die Temperatur", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "температуры", back: "die Temperaturen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "подниматься", back: "steigen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "поднимались", back: "sein gestiegen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "солнечно", back: "sonnig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "легкий", back: "leicht", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "оставаться", back: "bleiben", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "оставались", back: "sein geblieben", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "дождь", back: "der Regen", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "снег", back: "der Schnee", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "плюс", back: "plus", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "минус", back: "minus", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "радио", back: "das Radio", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "радио (мн.ч.)", back: "die Radios", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "интернет", back: "das Internet", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "лето", back: "der Sommer", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "лета", back: "die Sommer", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "жарко", back: "heiß", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "весна", back: "der Frühling", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "весны", back: "die Frühlinge", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "осень", back: "der Herbst", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "осени", back: "die Herbste", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "плохой", back: "schlecht", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "зима", back: "der Winter", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "зимы", back: "die Winter", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "ветер", back: "der Wind", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "ветры", back: "die Winde", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "приятный", back: "angenehm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "меню", back: "die Speisekarte", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "меню (мн.ч.)", back: "die Speisekarten", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "гамбургер", back: "der Hamburger", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "гамбургеры", back: "die Hamburger", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "блюдо", back: "die Speise", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "блюда", back: "die Speisen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "картофель фри", back: "die Pommes frites", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "порция", back: "die Portion", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "порции", back: "die Portionen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "кетчуп", back: "der Ketchup", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "кетчупы", back: "die Ketchups", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "салат", back: "der Salat", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "салаты", back: "die Salate", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "ветчина", back: "der Schinken", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "ветчины", back: "die Schinken", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "напиток", back: "das Getränk", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "напитки", back: "die Getränke", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "кола", back: "die Cola", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "колы", back: "die Colas", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "же, всё-таки", back: "doch", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "скорее, лучше", back: "lieber", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "брать", back: "nehmen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "брали", back: "haben genommen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "почему", back: "warum", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "собака", back: "der Hund", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "собаки", back: "die Hunde", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "мороженое", back: "das Eis", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "танцевать", back: "tanzen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "танцевали", back: "haben getanzt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "плавать", back: "schwimmen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "плавали", back: "sein geschwommen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "встречать", back: "treffen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "встречали", back: "haben getroffen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "велосипед", back: "das Fahrrad", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "велосипеды", back: "die Fahrräder", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "ехать", back: "fahren", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "ездили", back: "sein gefahren", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "жарить на гриле", back: "grillen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "жарили на гриле", back: "haben gegrillt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "свободное время", back: "die Freizeit", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "хобби", back: "das Hobby", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "хобби (мн.ч.)", back: "die Hobbys", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "читать", back: "lesen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "читали", back: "haben gelesen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "детектив (книга, фильм)", back: "der Krimi", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "детективы", back: "die Krimis", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "любимый", back: "Lieblings-", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "фильм", back: "der Film", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "фильмы", back: "die Filme", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "важный", back: "wichtig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "гриль", back: "der Grill", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "грили", back: "die Grills", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "собирать", back: "sammeln", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "собирали", back: "haben gesammelt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "профессия", back: "der Beruf", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "профессии", back: "die Berufe", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "фото", back: "das Foto", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "фото (мн.ч.)", back: "die Fotos", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "особенно", back: "besonders", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "фотографировать", back: "fotografieren", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "фотографировали", back: "haben fotografiert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "удовольствие, удовольствие", back: "der Spaß", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "смартфон", back: "das Smartphone", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "смартфоны", back: "die Smartphones", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "глупый", back: "dumm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "часто", back: "oft", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "иметь в виду", back: "meinen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "имели в виду", back: "haben gemeint", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "кубик", back: "der Würfel", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "кубики", back: "die Würfel", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "игра", back: "das Spiel", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "игры", back: "die Spiele", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "к сожалению", back: "leider", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "проблема", back: "das Problem", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "проблемы", back: "die Probleme", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "всегда", back: "immer", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "возможно", back: "vielleicht", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "простой", back: "einfach", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "быстрый", back: "schnell", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "солнце", back: "die Sonne", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "солнца", back: "die Sonnen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "Солнечно.", back: "Es ist sonnig.", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "дождь", back: "der Regen", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "Идет дождь.", back: "Es regnet.", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "облако", back: "die Wolke", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "облака", back: "die Wolken", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "пасмурно", back: "es ist bewölkt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "снег", back: "der Schnee", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "идет снег", back: "es schneit", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "ветер", back: "der Wind", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "ветры", back: "die Winde", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "ветрено", back: "es ist windig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "холодно", back: "es ist kalt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "тепло", back: "es ist warm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "отлично", back: "prima", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "команда", back: "das Team", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "команды", back: "die Teams", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "будить", back: "wecken", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "будили", back: "haben geweckt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "завтрак", back: "das Frühstück", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "завтраки", back: "die Frühstücke", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "готовый", back: "fertig", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "начинать, отправляться", back: "los sein", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "писать", back: "schreiben", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "писали", back: "haben geschrieben", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "математика", back: "die Mathematik", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "тест", back: "der Test", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "тесты", back: "die Tests", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "пунктуальный", back: "pünktlich", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "ни в коем случае / в любом случае", back: "auf keinen/jeden Fall", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "иметь вкус", back: "schmecken", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "имели вкус", back: "haben geschmeckt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "домой", back: "nach Hause", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "школа", back: "die Schule", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "школы", back: "die Schulen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "мочь", back: "können", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "могли", back: "haben gekonnt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "больной", back: "krank", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "врач", back: "der Arzt", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "врачи", back: "die Ärzte", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "врач (женщина)", back: "die Ärztin", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "врачи (женщины)", back: "die Ärztinnen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "печь", back: "backen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "пекли", back: "haben gebacken", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "петь", back: "singen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "пели", back: "haben gesungen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "ездить верхом", back: "reiten", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "ездили верхом", back: "sein geritten", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "пианино", back: "das Klavier", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "пианино (мн.ч.)", back: "die Klaviere", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "рисовать", back: "malen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "рисовали", back: "haben gemalt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "лыжа", back: "der Ski", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "лыжи", back: "die Skier", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "теннис (играть)", back: "das Tennis (spielen)", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "хотеть", back: "wollen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "хотели", back: "haben gewollt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "наконец", back: "endlich", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "песня", back: "das Lied", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "песни", back: "die Lieder", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "упражняться", back: "üben", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "упражнялись", back: "haben geübt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "текст", back: "der Text", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "тексты", back: "die Texte", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "упражнение", back: "die Übung", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "упражнения", back: "die Übungen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "письмо", back: "der Brief", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "письма", back: "die Briefe", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "диктант", back: "das Diktat", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "диктанты", back: "die Diktate", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "книга", back: "das Buch", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "книги", back: "die Bücher", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "играть на гитаре", back: "Gitarre spielen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "играли на гитаре", back: "haben Gitarre gespielt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "ездить на велосипеде", back: "Fahrrad fahren", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "ездили на велосипеде", back: "sein Fahrrad gefahren", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "встречать друзей", back: "Freunde treffen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "встречали", back: "haben getroffen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "кататься на лыжах", back: "Ski fahren", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "катались на лыжах", back: "sein Ski gefahren", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "играть в теннис", back: "Tennis spielen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "играли в теннис", back: "haben Tennis gespielt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "история", back: "die Geschichte", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "истории", back: "die Geschichten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "больница", back: "das Krankenhaus", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "больницы", back: "die Krankenhäuser", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "интервью", back: "das Interview", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "интервью", back: "die Interviews", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "газета", back: "die Zeitung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "газеты", back: "die Zeitungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "телевидение", back: "das Fernsehen", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "образование", back: "die Ausbildung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "образования", back: "die Ausbildungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "начальник", back: "der Chef", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "начальники", back: "die Chefs", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "начальница", back: "die Chefin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "начальницы", back: "die Chefinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "пациент", back: "der Patient", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "пациенты", back: "die Patienten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "пациентка", back: "die Patientin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "пациентки", back: "die Patientinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "дворник/заведующий", back: "der Hausmeister", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "дворники/заведующие", back: "die Hausmeister", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "дворничиха/заведующая", back: "die Hausmeisterin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "дворничихи/заведующие", back: "die Hausmeisterinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "журналист", back: "der Journalist", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "журналисты", back: "die Journalisten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "журналистка", back: "die Journalistin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "журналистки", back: "die Journalistinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "тема", back: "das Thema", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "темы", back: "die Themen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "мехатроник", back: "der Mechatroniker", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "мехатроники", back: "die Mechatroniker", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "мехатроник (женщина)", back: "die Mechatronikerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "мехатроники (женщины)", back: "die Mechatronikerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "домохозяин", back: "der Hausmann", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "домохозяева", back: "die Hausmänner", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "домохозяйка", back: "die Hausfrau", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "домохозяйки", back: "die Hausfrauen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "полицейский", back: "der Polizist", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "полицейские", back: "die Polizisten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "полицейская", back: "die Polizistin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "полицейские (женщины)", back: "die Polizistinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "санитар/медбрат", back: "der Krankenpfleger", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "медсёстры", back: "die Krankenschwestern", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "медсестра", back: "die Krankenschwester", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "медсёстры", back: "die Krankenschwestern", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "профессиональный", back: "beruflich", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "ученик", back: "der Schüler", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "ученики", back: "die Schüler", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "ученица", back: "die Schülerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "ученицы", back: "die Schülerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "студент", back: "der Student", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "студенты", back: "die Studenten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "студентка", back: "die Studentin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "студентки", back: "die Studentinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "учиться", back: "studieren", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "учились", back: "haben studiert", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "работа", back: "der Job", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "работы", back: "die Jobs", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "место работы", back: "die Stelle", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "места работы", back: "die Stellen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "самостоятельный", back: "selbstständig", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "работающий по профессии", back: "berufstätig", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "безработный", back: "arbeitslos", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "в настоящее время", back: "zurzeit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "таксист", back: "der Taxifahrer", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "таксисты", back: "die Taxifahrer", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "таксистка", back: "die Taxifahrerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "таксистки", back: "die Taxifahrerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "длиться", back: "dauern", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "длились", back: "haben gedauert", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "с (временной предлог)", back: "seit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "заявление (о приеме)", back: "die Bewerbung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "заявления", back: "die Bewerbungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "практика", back: "das Praktikum", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "практики", back: "die Praktika", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "отдел", back: "die Abteilung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "отделы", back: "die Abteilungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "руководитель", back: "der Leiter", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "руководители", back: "die Leiter", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "руководительница", back: "die Leiterin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "руководительницы", back: "die Leiterinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "уважаемый", back: "geehrt", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "экономика", back: "die Wirtschaft", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "диплом", back: "das Diplom", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "дипломы", back: "die Diplome", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "как раз, прямо", back: "gerade", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "офис", back: "das Büro", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "офисы", back: "die Büros", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "информация", back: "die Information", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "информация (мн.ч.)", back: "die Informationen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "приветствие", back: "der Gruß", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "приветствия", back: "die Grüße", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "жениться/выйти замуж", back: "heiraten", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "женились/вышли замуж", back: "haben geheiratet", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "на самом деле", back: "eigentlich", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "позже", back: "später", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "гид", back: "der Reiseführer", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "гиды", back: "die Reiseführer", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "гид (женщина)", back: "die Reiseführerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "гиды (женщины)", back: "die Reiseführerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "турист", back: "der Tourist", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "туристы", back: "die Touristen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "туристка", back: "die Touristin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "туристки", back: "die Touristinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "показывать", back: "zeigen", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "показывали", back: "haben gezeigt", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "профессиональный опыт", back: "die Berufserfahrung", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "кафе", back: "das Café", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "кафе", back: "die Cafés", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "стресс", back: "der Stress", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "иногда", back: "manchmal", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "официант", back: "der Kellner", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "официанты", back: "die Kellner", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "официантка", back: "die Kellnerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "официантки", back: "die Kellnerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "ресторан", back: "das Restaurant", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "рестораны", back: "die Restaurants", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "архитектор", back: "der Architekt", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "архитекторы", back: "die Architekten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "архитектор (женщина)", back: "die Architektin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "архитекторы (женщины)", back: "die Architektinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "повар", back: "der Koch", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "повара", back: "die Köche", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "повариха", back: "die Köchin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "поварихи", back: "die Köchinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "работник", back: "der Arbeiter", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "работники", back: "die Arbeiter", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "работница", back: "die Arbeiterin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "работницы", back: "die Arbeiterinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "мало", back: "wenig", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "коллега", back: "der Kollege", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "коллеги", back: "die Kollegen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "коллега (женщина)", back: "die Kollegin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "коллеги (женщины)", back: "die Kolleginnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "заграница", back: "das Ausland", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "другой", back: "ander-", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "рабочее место", back: "der Arbeitsplatz", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "рабочие места", back: "die Arbeitsplätze", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "мечта", back: "der Traum", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "мечты", back: "die Träume", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "мечтательный", back: "traum-", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "в течение дня", back: "tagsüber", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "три раза", back: "dreimal", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "получать", back: "bekommen", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "получили", back: "haben bekommen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "секретарь", back: "der Sekretär", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "секретари", back: "die Sekretäre", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "секретарь (женщина)", back: "die Sekretärin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "секретари (женщины)", back: "die Sekretärinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "университет", back: "die Universität", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "университеты", back: "die Universitäten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "срочный", back: "befristet", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "полная занятость", back: "die Vollzeit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "неполная занятость", back: "die Teilzeit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "полный рабочий день", back: "ganztags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "полдня", back: "halbtags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "до полудня", back: "vormittags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "после полудня", back: "nachmittags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "репетиторство", back: "die Nachhilfe", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "по понедельникам", back: "montags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "по четвергам", back: "donnerstags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "пенсионер", back: "der Senior", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "пенсионеры", back: "die Senioren", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "пенсионерский", back: "senioren-", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "временный работник", back: "die Aushilfe", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "временные работники", back: "die Aushilfen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "срочно", back: "dringend", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "сервис", back: "der Service", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "по вечерам", back: "abends", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "по вторникам", back: "dienstags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "по средам", back: "mittwochs", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "по пятницам", back: "freitags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "по воскресеньям", back: "sonntags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "платить", back: "zahlen", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "платили", back: "haben gezahlt", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "за", back: "pro", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "час", back: "die Stunde", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "часы", back: "die Stunden", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "спрос", back: "die Nachfrage", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "споры", back: "die Nachfragen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "свободный", back: "frei", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "каждый раз", back: "jeweils", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "по субботам", back: "samstags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "водительское удостоверение", back: "der Führerschein", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "водительские удостоверения", back: "die Führerscheine", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "билет", back: "das Ticket", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "билеты", back: "die Tickets", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "учреждение, ведомство", back: "das Amt", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "учреждения, ведомства", back: "die Ämter", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "действительный", back: "gültig", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "арендовать", back: "mieten", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "арендовали", back: "haben gemietet", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "иностранный", back: "ausländisch", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "европейский", back: "europäisch", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "Европейский союз", back: "die Europäische Union", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "молодой", back: "jung", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "поездка", back: "die Fahrt", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "поездки", back: "die Fahrten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "билет", back: "die Fahrkarte", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "билеты", back: "die Fahrkarten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "заявление", back: "der Antrag", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "заявления", back: "die Anträge", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "должен", back: "müssen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "долженствовали", back: "haben gemusst", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "заполнять", back: "ausfüllen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "заполнили", back: "haben ausgefüllt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "удостоверение личности", back: "der Ausweis", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "удостоверения личности", back: "die Ausweise", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "приносить", back: "mitbringen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "приносили", back: "haben mitgebracht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "бумага", back: "das Papier", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "бумаги", back: "die Papiere", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "подписывать", back: "unterschreiben", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "подписали", back: "haben unterschrieben", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "наличный", back: "bar", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "автомат", back: "der Automat", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "автоматы", back: "die Automaten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "функционировать", back: "funktionieren", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "функционировали", back: "haben funktioniert", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "цель", back: "das Ziel", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "цели", back: "die Ziele", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "выбирать", back: "wählen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "выбирали", back: "haben gewählt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "взрослый / взрослая", back: "der Erwachsene / die Erwachsene", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "взрослые", back: "die Erwachsenen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "выбирать", back: "auswählen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "выбрали", back: "haben ausgewählt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "человек (общ.)", back: "man", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "сначала", back: "zuerst", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "затем", back: "danach", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "потом", back: "dann", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "конец", back: "der Schluss", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "тихо", back: "leise", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "объяснять", back: "erklären", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "объяснили", back: "haben erklärt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "громко", back: "laut", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "выключать", back: "ausmachen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "выключили", back: "haben ausgemacht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "слушать", back: "zuhören", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "слушали", back: "haben zugehört", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "вставать", back: "aufstehen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "вставали", back: "sein aufgestanden", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "ждать", back: "warten", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "ждали", back: "haben gewartet", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "плата", back: "die Gebühr", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "платы", back: "die Gebühren", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "касса", back: "die Kasse", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "кассы", back: "die Kassen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "смеяться", back: "lachen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "смеялись", back: "haben gelacht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "момент", back: "der Moment", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "моменты", back: "die Momente", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "подавать заявление", back: "beantragen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "подавали заявление", back: "haben beantragt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "иметь разрешение", back: "dürfen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "имели разрешение", back: "haben gedurft", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "внимание", back: "Achtung", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "сигарета", back: "die Zigarette", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "сигареты", back: "die Zigaretten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "курить", back: "rauchen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "курили", back: "haben geraucht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "медленно", back: "langsam", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "парковка", back: "der Parkplatz", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "парковки", back: "die Parkplätze", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "парковаться", back: "parken", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "парковались", back: "haben geparkt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "разрешённый", back: "erlaubt", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "запрещённый", back: "verboten", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "багаж", back: "das Gepäck", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "сдавать", back: "abgeben", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "сдавали", back: "haben abgegeben", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "брать с собой", back: "mitnehmen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "брали с собой", back: "haben mitgenommen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "один", back: "allein", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "орган власти", back: "die Behörde", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "органы власти", back: "die Behörden", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "человек", back: "die Person", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "люди", back: "die Personen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "девичья фамилия", back: "der Geburtsname", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "девичьи фамилии", back: "die Geburtsnamen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "пол", back: "das Geschlecht", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "полы", back: "die Geschlechter", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "иностранец", back: "der Ausländer", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "иностранцы", back: "die Ausländer", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "иностранка", back: "die Ausländerin", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "иностранки", back: "die Ausländerinnen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "жить раздельно", back: "getrennt leben", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "мужской", back: "männlich", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "женский", back: "weiblich", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "родственник / родственница", back: "der Angehörige / die Angehörige", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "родственники", back: "die Angehörigen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "означать", back: "bedeuten", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "означали", back: "haben bedeutet", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "повторять", back: "wiederholen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "повторяли", back: "haben wiederholt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "понимать", back: "verstehen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "понимали", back: "haben verstanden", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "языковая школа", back: "die Sprachenschule", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "языковые школы", back: "die Sprachenschulen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "посещать", back: "besuchen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "посещали", back: "haben besucht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "помогать", back: "helfen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "помогали", back: "haben geholfen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "справка", back: "die Auskunft", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "справки", back: "die Auskünfte", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "разрешение", back: "die Erlaubnis", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "объяснение", back: "die Erklärung", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "объяснения", back: "die Erklärungen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "документ", back: "das Dokument", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "документы", back: "die Dokumente", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "деньги", back: "das Geld", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "достаточно", back: "genug", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "доход", back: "das Einkommen", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "путешествие", back: "die Reise", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "путешествия", back: "die Reisen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "страховка", back: "die Versicherung", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "страховки", back: "die Versicherungen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "посольство", back: "die Botschaft", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "посольства", back: "die Botschaften", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "виза", back: "das Visum", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "визы", back: "die Visa", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "приносить", back: "holen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "приносили", back: "haben geholt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "сотрудник", back: "der Mitarbeiter", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "сотрудница", back: "die Mitarbeiterin", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "чиновник", back: "der Beamte", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "чиновница", back: "die Beamtin", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "зарабатывать", back: "verdienen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "зарабатывали", back: "haben verdient", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "паспорт", back: "der Pass", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "паспорта", back: "die Pässe", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "путешествовать", back: "reisen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "путешествовали", back: "sein gereist", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "клуб", back: "der Klub", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "клубы", back: "die Klubs", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "приемное отделение (скорой помощи)", back: "die Notaufnahme", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "приемные отделения", back: "die Notaufnahmen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "область, зона", back: "der Bereich", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "области, зоны", back: "die Bereiche", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "таблетка", back: "die Tablette", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "таблетки", back: "die Tabletten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "глаз", back: "das Auge", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "глаза", back: "die Augen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "причинять боль", back: "weh tun", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "причинили боль", back: "haben wehgetan", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "авария, несчастный случай", back: "der Unfall", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "аварии, несчастные случаи", back: "die Unfälle", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "доктор", back: "der Doktor", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "доктора", back: "die Doktoren", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "боль", back: "der Schmerz", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "боли", back: "die Schmerzen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "должен", back: "sollen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "долженствовали", back: "haben gesollt", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "оба", back: "beide", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "веселый", back: "lustig", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "плохой, серьезный", back: "schlimm", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "давать", back: "geben", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "дали", back: "haben gegeben", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "идея", back: "die Idee", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "идеи", back: "die Ideen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "нога (от колена вниз)", back: "das Bein", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "ноги", back: "die Beine", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "волос", back: "das Haar", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "волосы", back: "die Haare", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "ухо", back: "das Ohr", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "уши", back: "die Ohren", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "рука", back: "der Arm", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "руки", back: "die Arme", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "живот", back: "der Bauch", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "животы", back: "die Bäuche", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "палец", back: "der Finger", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "пальцы", back: "die Finger", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "ступня", back: "der Fuß", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "ступни", back: "die Füße", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "шея", back: "der Hals", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "шеи", back: "die Hälse", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "голова", back: "der Kopf", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "головы", back: "die Köpfe", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "спина", back: "der Rücken", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "грудь", back: "die Brust", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "груди", back: "die Brüste", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "кисть руки", back: "die Hand", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "кисти рук", back: "die Hände", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "нос", back: "die Nase", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "носы", back: "die Nasen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "рот", back: "der Mund", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "рты", back: "die Münder", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "быть", back: "sein", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "её, их", back: "ihr", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "зуб", back: "der Zahn", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "зубы", back: "die Zähne", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "информировать", back: "informieren", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "информировали", back: "haben informiert", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "наш", back: "unser", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "выпадать, не состояться", back: "ausfallen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "выпали, не состоялись", back: "ist ausgefallen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "сообщение", back: "die Nachricht", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "сообщения", back: "die Nachrichten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "поцелуй", back: "der Kuss", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "поцелуи", back: "die Küsse", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "ваш", back: "euer", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "здоровый", back: "gesund", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "надеюсь", back: "hoffentlich", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "знакомый / знакомая", back: "der Bekannte / die Bekannte", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "знакомые / знакомые", back: "die Bekannten / die Bekannten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "шаг", back: "der Schritt", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "шаги", back: "die Schritte", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "несколько", back: "ein paar", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "медицина, лекарство", back: "die Medizin", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "спокойный", back: "ruhig", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "аптека", back: "die Apotheke", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "аптеки", back: "die Apotheken", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "жар", back: "das Fieber", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "кашель", back: "der Husten", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "мазь", back: "die Salbe", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "мази", back: "die Salben", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "использовать", back: "verwenden", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "использовали", back: "haben verwendet", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "здоровье", back: "die Gesundheit", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "насморк", back: "der Schnupfen", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "делать", back: "tun", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "делали", back: "haben getan", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "отправитель", back: "der Absender", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "отправители", back: "die Absender", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "место", back: "der Ort", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "места", back: "die Orte", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "получатель", back: "der Empfänger", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "получатели", back: "die Empfänger", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "обращение", back: "die Anrede", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "обращения", back: "die Anreden", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "дата", back: "das Datum", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "даты", back: "die Daten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "подпись", back: "die Unterschrift", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "подписи", back: "die Unterschriften", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "посылать", back: "schicken", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "послали", back: "haben geschickt", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "приемное время (у врача)", back: "die Sprechstunde", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "приемные времена", back: "die Sprechstunden", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "экстренный случай", back: "der Notfall", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "экстренные случаи", back: "die Notfälle", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "поблизости", back: "in der Nähe", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "минута", back: "die Minute", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "минуты", back: "die Minuten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "в порядке", back: "in Ordnung", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "заходить, проходить мимо", back: "vorbeikommen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "заходили, проходили мимо", back: "ist vorbeigekommen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "страховая карта", back: "die Versichertenkarte", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "страховые карты", back: "die Versichertenkarten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "пол, земля", back: "der Boden", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "полы, земли", back: "die Böden", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "лежать", back: "liegen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "лежали", back: "haben gelegen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "врач скорой помощи", back: "der Notarzt", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "врачи скорой помощи", back: "die Notärzte", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "сильный", back: "stark", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "помощь", back: "die Hilfe", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "внезапно", back: "plötzlich", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "случаться", back: "passieren", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "случились", back: "ist passiert", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "лекарство", back: "das Medikament", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "лекарства", back: "die Medikamente", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "мотоцикл", back: "das Motorrad", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "мотоциклы", back: "die Motorräder", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "травма", back: "die Verletzung", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "травмы", back: "die Verletzungen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "мастерская", back: "die Werkstatt", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "мастерские", back: "die Werkstätten", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "ключ", back: "der Schlüssel", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "ключи", back: "die Schlüssel", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "автомагистраль", back: "die Autobahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "автомагистрали", back: "die Autobahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "мост", back: "die Brücke", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "мосты", back: "die Brücken", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "справа", back: "rechts", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "прямо", back: "geradeaus", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "слева", back: "links", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "путь, дорога", back: "der Weg", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "пути, дороги", back: "die Wege", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "вокзал", back: "der Bahnhof", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "вокзалы", back: "die Bahnhöfe", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "мясная лавка", back: "die Metzgerei", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "мясные лавки", back: "die Metzgereien", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "почта", back: "die Post", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "отель", back: "das Hotel", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "отели", back: "die Hotels", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "музей", back: "das Museum", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "музеи", back: "die Museen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "светофор", back: "die Ampel", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "светофоры", back: "die Ampeln", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "автозаправка", back: "die Tankstelle", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "автозаправки", back: "die Tankstellen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "план города", back: "der Stadtplan", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "планы городов", back: "die Stadtpläne", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "чужой, иностранный", back: "fremd", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "летать", back: "fliegen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "летал", back: "ist geflogen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "самолет", back: "das Flugzeug", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "самолеты", back: "die Flugzeuge", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "трамвай", back: "die Straßenbahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "трамваи", back: "die Straßenbahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "поезд", back: "der Zug", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "поезда", back: "die Züge", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "метро", back: "die U-Bahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "метро", back: "die U-Bahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "автобус", back: "der Bus", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "автобусы", back: "die Busse", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "городской поезд", back: "die S-Bahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "городские поезда", back: "die S-Bahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "куда", back: "wohin", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "станция", back: "die Station", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "станции", back: "die Stationen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "грузовик", back: "der Lkw", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "грузовики", back: "die Lkws", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "киоск", back: "der Kiosk", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "киоски", back: "die Kioske", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "остановка", back: "die Haltestelle", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "остановки", back: "die Haltestellen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "книжный магазин", back: "die Buchhandlung", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "книжные магазины", back: "die Buchhandlungen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "сидеть", back: "sitzen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "сидели", back: "haben gesessen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "библиотека", back: "die Bücherei", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "библиотеки", back: "die Büchereien", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "дерево", back: "der Baum", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "деревья", back: "die Bäume", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "банк / скамейка", back: "die Bank", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "банки / скамейки", back: "die Banken", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "у, на", back: "an", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "на", back: "auf", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "за", back: "hinter", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "рядом", back: "neben", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "над, через", back: "über", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "под", back: "unter", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "между", back: "zwischen", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "пешеходная зона", back: "die Fußgängerzone", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "пешеходные зоны", back: "die Fußgängerzonen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "концерт", back: "das Konzert", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "концерты", back: "die Konzerte", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "брать напрокат", back: "ausleihen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "брали напрокат", back: "haben ausgeliehen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "копировать", back: "kopieren", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "копировали", back: "haben kopiert", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "(там) впереди", back: "(da) vorne", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "(там) вон там", back: "(da) drüben", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "угол", back: "die Ecke", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "углы", back: "die Ecken", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "(там) сзади", back: "(da) hinten", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "отъезжать", back: "abfahren", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "отъехали", back: "ist abgefahren", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "путь (на вокзале)", back: "das Gleis", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "пути", back: "die Gleise", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "садиться (в транспорт)", back: "einsteigen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "сели", back: "ist eingestiegen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "опоздание", back: "die Verspätung", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "опоздания", back: "die Verspätungen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "прибывать", back: "ankommen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "прибыли", back: "ist angekommen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "пересаживаться", back: "umsteigen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "пересели", back: "ist umgestiegen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "выходить (из транспорта)", back: "aussteigen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "вышли", back: "ist ausgestiegen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "отъезд", back: "die Abfahrt", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "отъезды", back: "die Abfahrten", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "прибытие", back: "die Ankunft", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "прибытия", back: "die Ankünfte", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "пересадка", back: "der Anschluss", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "пересадки", back: "die Anschlüsse", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "платформа", back: "der Bahnsteig", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "платформы", back: "die Bahnsteige", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "прямо", back: "direkt", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "объявление (по громкой связи)", back: "die Durchsage", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "объявления", back: "die Durchsagen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "окошко (кассы)", back: "der Schalter", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "окошки", back: "die Schalter", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "туда и обратно", back: "hin und zurück", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "расписание (транспорта)", back: "der Fahrplan", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "расписания", back: "die Fahrpläne", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "сумка", back: "die Tasche", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "сумки", back: "die Taschen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "пакет", back: "die Tüte", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "пакеты", back: "die Tüten", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "счет", back: "die Rechnung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "счета", back: "die Rechnungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "сломанный", back: "kaputt", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "ремонтировать", back: "reparieren", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "ремонтировали", back: "haben repariert", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "кислый, сердитый", back: "sauer", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "недружелюбный", back: "unfreundlich", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "обычный", back: "normal", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "родина", back: "das Heimatland", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "родины", back: "die Heimatländer", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "тренировка", back: "Training", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "одежда", back: "die Kleider", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "шить", back: "nähen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "сшили", back: "haben genäht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "ремонт", back: "die Reparatur", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "ремонты", back: "die Reparaturen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "принимать душ", back: "duschen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "принимали душ", back: "haben geduscht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "высказывание", back: "die Aussage", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "высказывания", back: "die Aussagen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "техник", back: "der Techniker", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "техники", back: "die Techniker", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "отопление", back: "die Heizung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "отопления", back: "die Heizungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "принтер", back: "der Drucker", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "принтеры", back: "die Drucker", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "модель", back: "das Modell", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "модели", back: "die Modelle", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "гарантия", back: "die Garantie", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "гарантии", back: "die Garantien", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "мимо-, прошедший", back: "vorbei-", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "приносить (пройти с чем-то)", back: "vorbeibringen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "принесли (пройдя с чем-то)", back: "haben vorbeigebracht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "включать", back: "anmachen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "включили", back: "haben angemacht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "дверь", back: "die Tür", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "двери", back: "die Türen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "закрывать", back: "zumachen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "закрыли", back: "haben zugemacht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "окно", back: "das Fenster", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "окна", back: "die Fenster", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "открывать", back: "aufmachen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "открыли", back: "haben aufgemacht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "бумага", back: "das Papier", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "бумаги", back: "die Papiere", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "свет", back: "das Licht", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "огни", back: "die Lichter", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "посудомоечная машина", back: "die Spülmaschine", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "посудомоечные машины", back: "die Spülmaschinen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "рекомендовать", back: "empfehlen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "рекомендовали", back: "haben empfohlen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "резервировать", back: "reservieren", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "резервировали", back: "haben reserviert", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "ресепшн", back: "die Rezeption", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "ресепшны", back: "die Rezeptionen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "объявление", back: "die Ansage", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "объявления", back: "die Ansagen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "нажимать", back: "drücken", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "нажимали", back: "haben gedrückt", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "регистрироваться", back: "anmelden", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "зарегистрировались", back: "haben angemeldet", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "соединять", back: "verbinden", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "соединили", back: "haben verbunden", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "оставлять", back: "hinterlassen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "оставили", back: "haben hinterlassen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "перезванивать", back: "zurückrufen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "перезвонили", back: "haben zurückgerufen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "выглядеть", back: "aussehen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "выглядели", back: "haben ausgesehen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "отпуск", back: "der Urlaub", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "отпуска", back: "die Urlaube", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "снаружи", back: "draußen", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "прочь", back: "weg", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "кофемашина", back: "die Kaffeemaschine", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "кофемашины", back: "die Kaffeemaschinen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "парикмахер (муж.)", back: "der Friseur", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "парикмахеры (муж.)", back: "die Friseure", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "парикмахер (жен.)", back: "die Friseurin", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "парикмахеры (жен.)", back: "die Friseurinnen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "заказывать", back: "bestellen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "заказал", back: "hat bestellt", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "предложение", back: "das Angebot", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "предложения", back: "die Angebote", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "предлагать", back: "anbieten", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "предложил", back: "hat angeboten", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "подросток (м/ж)", back: "der Jugendliche / die Jugendliche", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "подростки", back: "die Jugendlichen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "инструкция по применению", back: "die Gebrauchsanweisung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "инструкции по применению", back: "die Gebrauchsanweisungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "чистка, уборка", back: "die Reinigung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "чистки, уборки", back: "die Reinigungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "вилка (электрическая)", back: "der Stecker", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "вилки", back: "die Stecker", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "розетка", back: "die Steckdose", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "розетки", back: "die Steckdosen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "тянуть", back: "ziehen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "тянул", back: "hat gezogen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "вверху", back: "oben", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "уксус", back: "der Essig", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "кнопка", back: "die Taste", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "кнопки", back: "die Tasten", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "секунда", back: "die Sekunde", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "", back: "die Sekunden", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "куртка", back: "die Jacke", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "куртки", back: "die Jacken", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "пальто", back: "der Mantel", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "пальто (мн.ч.)", back: "die Mäntel", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "тонкий", back: "dünn", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "подходить", back: "passen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "подходил", back: "hat gepasst", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "широкий", back: "weit", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "одежда", back: "die Kleidung", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "блузка", back: "die Bluse", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "блузки", back: "die Blusen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "футболка", back: "das T-Shirt", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "футболки", back: "die T-Shirts", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "обувь", back: "der Schuh", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "обувь (мн.ч.)", back: "die Schuhe", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "брюки", back: "die Hose", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "брюки", back: "die Hosen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "юбка", back: "der Rock", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "юбки", back: "die Röcke", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "платье", back: "das Kleid", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "платья", back: "die Kleider", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "сапог", back: "der Stiefel", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "сапоги", back: "die Stiefel", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "пуловер", back: "der Pullover", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "пуловеры", back: "die Pullover", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "носок", back: "die Socke", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "носки", back: "die Socken", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "чулок", back: "der Strumpf", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "чулки", back: "die Strümpfe", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "джинсы", back: "die Jeans", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "джинсы", back: "die Jeans", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "платок", back: "das Tuch", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "платки", back: "die Tücher", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "рубашка", back: "das Hemd", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "рубашки", back: "die Hemden", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "костюм", back: "der Anzug", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "костюмы", back: "die Anzüge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "очки", back: "die Brille", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "очки", back: "die Brillen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "скучный", back: "langweilig", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "(зонт от дождя)", back: "der (Regen-)Schirm", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "зонты", back: "die (Regen-)Schirme", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "выгодный", back: "günstig", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "совершенный", back: "perfekt", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "стоять", back: "stehen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "стоял", back: "hat gestanden", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "жареная колбаса", back: "die Bratwurst", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "жареные колбасы", back: "die Bratwürste", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "ландшафт", back: "die Landschaft", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "ландшафты", back: "die Landschaften", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "гора", back: "der Berg", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "горы", back: "die Berge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "деревня", back: "das Dorf", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "деревни", back: "die Dörfer", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "лес", back: "der Wald", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "леса", back: "die Wälder", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "Северное море", back: "die Nordsee", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "пляж", back: "der Strand", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "пляжи", back: "die Strände", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "море", back: "das Meer", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "моря", back: "die Meere", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "порт", back: "der Hafen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "порты", back: "die Häfen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "никогда", back: "nie", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "лучше", back: "besser", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "лучше всего", back: "am besten", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "назад", back: "rückwärts", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "вперед", back: "vorwärts", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "при этом", back: "dabei", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "тяжелый", back: "schwer", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "музыкант (муж.)", back: "der Musiker", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "музыканты", back: "die Musiker", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "музыкант (жен.)", back: "die Musikerin", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "музыканты (жен.)", back: "die Musikerinnen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "тренироваться", back: "trainieren", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "тренировался", back: "hat trainiert", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "ездить на велосипеде", back: "rad fahren", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "ездил на велосипеде", back: "ist rad gefahren", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "рекорд", back: "der Rekord", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "рекорды", back: "die Rekorde", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "с наибольшим удовольствием", back: "am liebsten", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "больше всего", back: "am meisten", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "довольный", back: "zufrieden", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "шутка", back: "der Witz", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "шутки", back: "die Witze", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "этот", back: "dies-", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "какой", back: "welch-", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "чемодан", back: "der Koffer", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "чемоданы", back: "die Koffer", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "принадлежать", back: "gehören", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "принадлежал", back: "hat gehört", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "нравиться", back: "mögen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "нравился", back: "hat gemocht", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "день недели", back: "der Wochentag", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "дни недели", back: "die Wochentage", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "первый этаж", back: "das Erdgeschoss", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "первые этажи", back: "die Erdgeschosse", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "верхний этаж", back: "das Obergeschoss", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "верхние этажи", back: "die Obergeschosse", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "подвал / цокольный этаж", back: "das Untergeschoss", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "подвалы / цокольные этажи", back: "die Untergeschosse", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "выход", back: "der Ausgang", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "выходы", back: "die Ausgänge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "аптечный магазин", back: "die Drogerie", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "аптечные магазины", back: "die Drogerien", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "косметика", back: "die Kosmetik", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "украшения", back: "der Schmuck", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "посуда", back: "das Geschirr", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "стакан", back: "das Glas", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "стаканы", back: "die Gläser", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "мода", back: "die Mode", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "моды", back: "die Moden", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "вход", back: "der Eingang", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "входы", back: "die Eingänge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "извиняться", back: "entschuldigen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "извинился", back: "hat entschuldigt", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "знать", back: "wissen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "знал", back: "hat gewusst", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "мыло", back: "die Seife", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "мыла", back: "die Seifen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "зубная щетка", back: "die Zahnbürste", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "зубные щетки", back: "die Zahnbürsten", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "зубная паста", back: "die Zahnpasta", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "размер", back: "die Größe", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "размеры", back: "die Größen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "надевать", back: "anziehen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "надевал", back: "hat angezogen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "примерять", back: "anprobieren", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "примерял", back: "hat anprobiert", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "день рождения", back: "der Geburtstag", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "дни рождения", back: "die Geburtstage", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "шина", back: "der Reifen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "шины", back: "die Reifen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "рассказывать", back: "erzählen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "рассказывал", back: "hat erzählt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "праздновать", back: "feiern", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "праздновал", back: "hat gefeiert", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "прощание", back: "der Abschied", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "прощания", back: "die Abschiede", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "скоро", back: "bald", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "начинать", back: "beginnen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "начинал", back: "hat begonnen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "место работы", back: "die Arbeitsstelle", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "места работы", back: "die Arbeitsstellen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "счастье", back: "das Glück", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "радость", back: "die Freude", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "желать (себе)", back: "(sich) wünschen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "желал (себе)", back: "hat gewünscht", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "поздравлять", back: "gratulieren", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "поздравлял", back: "hat gratuliert", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "поздравление", back: "der Glückwunsch", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "поздравления", back: "die Glückwünsche", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "верить", back: "glauben", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "верил", back: "hat geglaubt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "посещать", back: "besuchen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "посещал", back: "hat besucht", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "ноябрь", back: "der November", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "январь", back: "der Januar", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "первый", back: "erste", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "второй", back: "zweite", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "третий", back: "dritte", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "февраль", back: "der Februar", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "март", back: "der März", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "апрель", back: "der April", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "май", back: "der Mai", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "июнь", back: "der Juni", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "июль", back: "der Juli", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "август", back: "der August", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "сентябрь", back: "der September", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "октябрь", back: "der Oktober", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "декабрь", back: "der Dezember", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "цветок", back: "die Blume", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "цветы", back: "die Blumen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "карнавал", back: "der Karneval", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "последний", back: "letzt-", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "участвовать", back: "mitmachen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "участвовал", back: "hat mitgemacht", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "праздник", back: "der Feiertag", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "праздники", back: "die Feiertage", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "подарок", back: "das Geschenk", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "подарки", back: "die Geschenke", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "любить (друг друга)", back: "(sich) lieben", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "любил (друг друга)", back: "hat geliebt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "чудесный", back: "wunderbar", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "десерт", back: "der Nachtisch", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "десерты", back: "die Nachtische", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "чистить", back: "putzen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "чистил", back: "hat geputzt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "ноутбук", back: "der Laptop", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "ноутбуки", back: "die Laptops", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "грязный", back: "schmutzig", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "стирать", back: "waschen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "стирал", back: "hat gewaschen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "дедушка", back: "der Großvater", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "дедушки", back: "die Großväter", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "бабушка", back: "die Großmutter", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "бабушки", back: "die Großmütter", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "праздник", back: "die Feier", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "праздники", back: "die Feiern", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "организовывать", back: "organisieren", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "организовывал", back: "hat organisiert", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "информировать", back: "Bescheid geben", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "информировал", back: "hat Bescheid gegeben", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "приглашение", back: "die Einladung", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "приглашения", back: "die Einladungen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "рейс, полёт", back: "der Flug", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "рейсы, полёты", back: "die Flüge", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "становиться", back: "werden", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "стал", back: "ist geworden", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "приглашать", back: "einladen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "приглашал", back: "hat eingeladen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "радоваться", back: "sich freuen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "радовался", back: "hat sich gefreut", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "праздник", back: "das Fest", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "праздники", back: "die Feste", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "сердечный", back: "herzlich", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "гость", back: "das Gast", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "гости", back: "die Gäste", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "причина", back: "der Grund", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "причины", back: "die Gründe", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "ответ", back: "die Antwort", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "ответы", back: "die Antworten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "просить", back: "bitten", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "просил", back: "hat gebeten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "Рождество", back: "das Weihnachten", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "Пасха", back: "das Ostern", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "Новый год", back: "das Silvester", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "Новый год", back: "das Neujahr", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "выигрывать", back: "gewinnen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "выиграл", back: "hat gewonnen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "родственник / родственница", back: "der Verwandte / die Verwandte", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "родственники", back: "die Verwandten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "карта, открытка", back: "die Karte", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "карты, открытки", back: "die Karten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "свадьба", back: "die Hochzeit", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "свадьбы", back: "die Hochzeiten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "счастливый", back: "glücklich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "смотреть", back: "ansehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "смотрел", back: "hat angesehen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "сосед", back: "der Nachbar", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "соседи", back: "die Nachbarn", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "соседка", back: "die Nachbarin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "соседки", back: "die Nachbarinnen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "покупка", back: "der Einkauf", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "покупки", back: "die Einkäufe", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "получаться", back: "klappen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "получилось", back: "hat geklappt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "центр", back: "das Zentrum", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "центры", back: "die Zentren", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "чувство", back: "das Gefühl", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "чувства", back: "die Gefühle", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "начало", back: "der Anfang", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "начала", back: "die Anfänge", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "скучать", back: "vermissen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "скучал", back: "hat vermisst", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "потому что", back: "weil", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "человек", back: "der Mensch", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "люди", back: "die Menschen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "работодатель", back: "der Arbeitgeber", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "работодатели", back: "die Arbeitgeber", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "работодательница", back: "die Arbeitgeberin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "работодательницы", back: "die Arbeitgeberinnen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "переезжать", back: "umziehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "переехал", back: "ist umgezogen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "знакомиться", back: "(sich) kennenlernen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "познакомился", back: "hat kennengelernt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "вчера", back: "gestern", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "переезд", back: "der Umzug", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "переезды", back: "die Umzüge", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "вещи", back: "die Sachen", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "распаковывать", back: "auspacken", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "распаковал", back: "hat ausgepackt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "засыпать", back: "einschlafen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "заснул", back: "ist eingeschlafen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "будильник", back: "der Wecker", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "будильники", back: "die Wecker", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "запоминать", back: "(sich) merken", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "запомнил", back: "hat gemerkt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "наконец", back: "schließlich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "даже", back: "sogar", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "рабочий день", back: "der Arbeitstag", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "рабочие дни", back: "die Arbeitstage", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "звучать", back: "klingen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "звучал", back: "hat geklungen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "переживать", back: "erleben", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "переживал", back: "hat erlebt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "поломка", back: "die Panne", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "поломки", back: "die Pannen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "повседневность", back: "der Alltag", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "пропускать", back: "verpassen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "пропустил", back: "hat verpasst", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "замечать", back: "bemerken", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "заметил", back: "hat bemerkt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "узнавать", back: "erfahren", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "узнал", back: "hat erfahren", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "представлять себе", back: "(sich) vorstellen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "представил себе", back: "hat vorgestellt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "кошелёк", back: "die Geldbörse", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "кошельки", back: "die Geldbörsen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "терять", back: "verlieren", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "потерял", back: "hat verloren", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "неудача", back: "das Pech", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "кредитная карта", back: "die Kreditkarte", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "кредитные карты", back: "die Kreditkarten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "толкать / сталкиваться", back: "stoßen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "толкал / столкнулся", back: "hat/ist gestoßen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "неловкий", back: "peinlich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "дядя", back: "der Onkel", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "дяди", back: "die Onkel", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "тётя", back: "die Tante", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "тёти", back: "die Tanten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "кузен", back: "der Cousin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "кузены", back: "die Cousins", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "кузина", back: "die Cousine", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "кузины", back: "die Cousinen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "племянник", back: "der Neffe", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "племянники", back: "die Neffen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "племянница", back: "die Nichte", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "племянницы", back: "die Nichten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "симпатичный", back: "sympathisch", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "член", back: "das Mitglied", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "члены", back: "die Mitglieder", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "коммунальная квартира", back: "die Wohngemeinschaft", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "коммунальные квартиры", back: "die Wohngemeinschaften", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "вероятно", back: "wahrscheinlich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "крыша", back: "das Dach", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "крыши", back: "die Dächer", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "до сих пор", back: "bisher", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "разный", back: "verschieden", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "квартал", back: "das Viertel", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "кварталы", back: "die Viertel", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "арендатор", back: "der Mieter", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "арендаторы", back: "die Mieter", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "арендаторша", back: "die Mieterin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "арендаторы (ж.р.)", back: "die Mieterinnen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "въезжать", back: "einziehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "въехал", back: "ist eingezogen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "раз", back: "das Mal", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "разы", back: "die Male", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "странный", back: "komisch", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "кто-то", back: "jemand", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "хватать", back: "reichen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "хватало", back: "hat gereicht", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "делить", back: "teilen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "делил", back: "hat geteilt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "выезжать", back: "ausziehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "выехал", back: "ist ausgezogen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "место", back: "der Platz", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "места", back: "die Plätze", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "каждый", back: "jeder", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "использовать", back: "benutzen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "использовал", back: "hat benutzt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "вместе", back: "gemeinsam", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "иначе", back: "sonst", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "теперь", back: "nun", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "обычно", back: "normalerweise", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "беременная", back: "schwanger", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "тесть", back: "der Schwiegervater", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "тести", back: "die Schwiegerväter", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "тёща / свекровь", back: "die Schwiegermutter", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "тёщи / свекрови", back: "die Schwiegermütter", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "хозяйство", back: "der Haushalt", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "хозяйства", back: "die Haushalte", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "пенсия", back: "die Rente", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "пенсии", back: "die Renten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "энергия", back: "die Energie", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "сам", back: "selbst", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "менять", back: "wechseln", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "менял", back: "hat gewechselt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "потолок / одеяло", back: "die Decke", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "потолки / одеяла", back: "die Decken", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "висеть / вешать", back: "hängen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "повесил / висел", back: "hat gehängt / hat gehangen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "благодарность", back: "der Dank", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "ничего", back: "nichts", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "количество", back: "die Menge", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "количества", back: "die Mengen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "шариковая ручка", back: "der Kugelschreiber", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "шариковые ручки", back: "die Kugelschreiber", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "засовывать / застревать", back: "stecken", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "засовывал / застрял", back: "hat gesteckt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "замок", back: "das Schloss", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "замки", back: "die Schlösser", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "стоять", back: "stehen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "стоял", back: "hat gestanden", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "картина / изображение", back: "das Bild", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "картины / изображения", back: "die Bilder", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "стена", back: "die Wand", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "стены", back: "die Wände", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "кошка", back: "die Katze", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "кошки", back: "die Katzen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "класть", back: "legen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "положил", back: "hat gelegt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "покой", back: "die Ruhe", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "знак / табличка", back: "das Schild", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "знаки / таблички", back: "die Schilder", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "мешать", back: "stören", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "мешал", back: "hat gestört", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "ставить", back: "stellen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "ставил", back: "hat gestellt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "ручка / карандаш", back: "der Stift", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "ручки / карандаши", back: "die Stifte", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "строить", back: "bauen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "строил", back: "hat gebaut", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "туда", back: "dahin", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "растение", back: "die Pflanze", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "растения", back: "die Pflanzen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "туда", back: "dorthin", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "осторожность", back: "die Vorsicht", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "падать вниз", back: "runterfallen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "упал вниз", back: "ist gefallen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "внутрь", back: "rein", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "мусор", back: "der Müll", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "наружу", back: "raus", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "войти", back: "reinkommen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "вошёл", back: "ist reingekommen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "сообщение", back: "die Mitteilung", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "сообщения", back: "die Mitteilungen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "житель", back: "der Bewohner", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "жители", back: "die Bewohner", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "жительница", back: "die Bewohnerin", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "жительницы", back: "die Bewohnerinnen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "разделять", back: "trennen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "разделил", back: "hat getrennt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "био-", back: "bio-", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "отходы", back: "der Abfall", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "отходы", back: "die Abfälle", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "пластик", back: "das Plastik", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "обращать внимание", back: "beachten", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "обращал внимание", back: "hat beachtet", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "вывоз мусора", back: "die Müllabfuhr", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "вывозы мусора", back: "die Müllabfuhren", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "мусорный бак", back: "die Mülltonne", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "мусорные баки", back: "die Mülltonnen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "ставить (откладывать)", back: "abstellen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "ставил", back: "hat abgestellt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "въезд", back: "die Einfahrt", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "въезды", back: "die Einfahrten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "двор", back: "der Hof", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "дворы", back: "die Höfe", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "увольнять / расторгать", back: "kündigen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "уволил / расторгнул", back: "hat gekündigt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "договор", back: "der Vertrag", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "договоры", back: "die Verträge", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "надеяться", back: "hoffen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "надеялся", back: "hat gehofft", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "понимание", back: "das Verständnis", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "заключать", back: "abschließen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "заключил", back: "hat abgeschlossen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "низкий", back: "niedrig", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "расходы / затраты", back: "die Kosten", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "повышаться", back: "(sich) erhöhen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "повысился", back: "hat erhöht", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "удалять", back: "entfernen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "удалил", back: "hat entfernt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "предмет", back: "der Gegenstand", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "предметы", back: "die Gegenstände", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "отапливать", back: "heizen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "отапливал", back: "hat geheizt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "детская коляска", back: "der Kinderwagen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "детские коляски", back: "die Kinderwagen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "лифт", back: "der Aufzug", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "лифты", back: "die Aufzüge", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "лестница", back: "die Treppe", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "лестницы", back: "die Treppen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "почтовый ящик", back: "der Briefkasten", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "почтовые ящики", back: "die Briefkästen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "решение", back: "die Lösung", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "решения", back: "die Lösungen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "довольно", back: "ziemlich", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "быть правым", back: "recht haben", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "был прав", back: "hat recht gehabt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "вопрос", back: "die Frage", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "вопросы", back: "die Fragen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "просьба", back: "die Bitte", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "просьбы", back: "die Bitten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "намерение", back: "die Absicht", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "намерения", back: "die Absichten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "смена", back: "die Schicht", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "смены", back: "die Schichten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "позволять / оставлять", back: "lassen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "позволял / оставлял", back: "hat gelassen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "бросать", back: "werfen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "бросал", back: "hat geworfen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "присматривать", back: "aufpassen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "присматривал", back: "hat aufgepasst", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "поливать", back: "gießen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "поливал", back: "hat gegossen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "действительно", back: "wirklich", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "звонить (в дверь, звонок)", back: "klingeln", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "звонил", back: "hat geklingelt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "обсуждать", back: "besprechen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "обсуждал", back: "hat besprochen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "кормить", back: "füttern", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "кормил", back: "hat gefüttert", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "мастер / рабочий", back: "der Handwerker", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "мастера / рабочие", back: "die Handwerker", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "биоотходы", back: "der Biomüll", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "десерт", back: "die Nachspeise", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "десерты", back: "die Nachspeisen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "мёд", back: "der Honig", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "обычно", back: "meistens", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "редко", back: "selten", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "соглашаться", back: "stimmen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "согласован", back: "hat gestimmt", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "в пути", back: "unterwegs", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "приём пищи", back: "die Mahlzeit", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "приёмы пищи", back: "die Mahlzeiten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "в полдень", back: "mittags", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "по утрам", back: "morgens", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "чашка", back: "die Tasse", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "чашки", back: "die Tassen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "определённо", back: "bestimmt", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "еда", back: "das Essen", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "обед", back: "das Mittagessen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "обеды", back: "die Mittagessen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "столовая", back: "die Kantine", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "столовые", back: "die Kantinen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "почти", back: "fast", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "вегетарианский", back: "vegetarisch", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "блюдо", back: "das Gericht", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "блюда", back: "die Gerichte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "привычка", back: "die Gewohnheit", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "привычки", back: "die Gewohnheiten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "брать на себя", back: "übernehmen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "взял на себя", back: "hat übernommen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "варенье", back: "die Marmelade", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "варенья", back: "die Marmeladen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "немецкий", back: "deutsch", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "свинья", back: "das Schwein", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "свиньи", back: "die Schweine", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "алкоголь", back: "der Alkohol", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "дважды", back: "zweimal", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "ложка", back: "der Löffel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "ложки", back: "die Löffel", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "нож", back: "das Messer", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "ножи", back: "die Messer", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "тарелка", back: "der Teller", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "тарелки", back: "die Teller", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "вилка", back: "die Gabel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "вилки", back: "die Gabeln", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "квартет", back: "das Quartett", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "квартеты", back: "die Quartette", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "кастрюля", back: "der Topf", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "кастрюли", back: "die Töpfe", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "чайник, кувшин", back: "die Kanne", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "чайники, кувшины", back: "die Kannen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "миска", back: "die Schüssel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "миски", back: "die Schüsseln", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "сковорода", back: "die Pfanne", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "сковороды", back: "die Pfannen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "аппетит", back: "der Appetit", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "пахнуть", back: "riechen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "пахнул", back: "hat gerochen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "раздеваться", back: "(sich) ausziehen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "раздевался", back: "hat ausgezogen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "полный", back: "voll", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "хорошо", back: "okay", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "раньше", back: "vorher", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "вежливый", back: "höflich", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "диета", back: "die Diät", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "диеты", back: "die Diäten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "сытый", back: "satt", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "другой", back: "anders", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "так же", back: "genauso", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "удивлять", back: "überraschen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "удивил", back: "hat überrascht", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "странный", back: "seltsam", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "острый", back: "scharf", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "сладкий", back: "süß", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "солёный", back: "salzig", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "жирный", back: "fett", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "руководить", back: "leiten", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "руководил", back: "hat geleitet", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "свежий", back: "frisch", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "круглый", back: "rund", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "различный", back: "unterschiedlich", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "вид, тип", back: "die Art", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "виды, типы", back: "die Arten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "мюсли", back: "das Müsli", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "мюсли", back: "die Müslis", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "фрукт", back: "die Frucht", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "фрукты", back: "die Früchte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "закуска", back: "die Vorspeise", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "закуски", back: "die Vorspeisen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "главный", back: "Haupt-", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "процент", back: "das Prozent", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "проценты", back: "die Prozente", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "рынок", back: "der Markt", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "рынки", back: "die Märkte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "региональный", back: "regional", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "продукт", back: "das Produkt", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "продукты", back: "die Produkte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "окружение", back: "die Umgebung", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "окружения", back: "die Umgebungen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "стейк", back: "das Steak", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "стейки", back: "die Steaks", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "фабрика", back: "die Fabrik", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "фабрики", back: "die Fabriken", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "против", back: "gegen", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "планировать", back: "planen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "планировал", back: "hat geplant", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "ежедневно", back: "täglich", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "шницель", back: "das Schnitzel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "шницели", back: "die Schnitzel", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "суп", back: "die Suppe", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "супы", back: "die Suppen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "кусок", back: "das Stück", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "куски", back: "die Stücke", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "лимон", back: "die Zitrone", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "лимоны", back: "die Zitronen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "чистый", back: "sauber", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "говядина", back: "das Rind", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "говядины", back: "die Rinder", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "жаркое", back: "der Braten", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "жаркие", back: "die Braten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "занятый", back: "besetzt", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "чаевые", back: "das Trinkgeld", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "чаевые (мн.ч.)", back: "die Trinkgelder", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "стакан", back: "das Glas", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "стаканы", back: "die Gläser", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "бронь, резервация", back: "die Reservierung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "брони, резервации", back: "die Reservierungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "подтверждение", back: "die Bestätigung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "подтверждения", back: "die Bestätigungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "записывать", back: "notieren", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "записал", back: "hat notiert", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "онлайн", back: "online", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "сложный", back: "schwierig", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "совещание", back: "die Besprechung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "совещания", back: "die Besprechungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "ведь, а именно", back: "nämlich", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "дружелюбный", back: "freundlich", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "умный", back: "klug", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "ошибка", back: "der Fehler", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "ошибки", back: "die Fehler", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "если", back: "wenn", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "безопасный, уверенный", back: "sicher", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "материал", back: "das Material", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "материалы", back: "die Materialien", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "участник", back: "der Teilnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "участники", back: "die Teilnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "участница", back: "die Teilnehmerin", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "участницы", back: "die Teilnehmerinnen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "совет, подсказка", back: "der Tipp", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "советы, подсказки", back: "die Tipps", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "регулярно", back: "regelmäßig", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "обращать внимание на", back: "achten auf", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "обратил внимание на", back: "hat geachtet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "записка, бумажка", back: "der Zettel", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "записки, бумажки", back: "die Zettel", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "универмаг", back: "das Kaufhaus", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "универмаги", back: "die Kaufhäuser", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "использовать", back: "nutzen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "использовал", back: "hat genutzt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "платформа", back: "die Plattform", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "платформы", back: "die Plattformen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "форум", back: "das Forum", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "форумы", back: "die Foren", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "агентство", back: "die Agentur", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "агентства", back: "die Agenturen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "временная работа", back: "die Zeitarbeit", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "временные работы", back: "die Zeitarbeiten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "ученик, стажёр / ученица, стажёрша", back: "der Auszubildende / die Auszubildende", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "ученики, стажёры / ученицы, стажёры", back: "die Auszubildenden", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "выключать", back: "aus·schalten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "выключил", back: "hat ausgeschaltet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "профсоюз", back: "die Gewerkschaft", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "профсоюзы", back: "die Gewerkschaften", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "безопасность", back: "die Sicherheit", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "защита", back: "der Schutz", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "предприятие", back: "der Betrieb", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "предприятия", back: "die Betriebe", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "собрание", back: "die Versammlung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "собрания", back: "die Versammlungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "срок", back: "die Frist", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "сроки", back: "die Fristen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "повышение квалификации", back: "die Weiterbildung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "повышения квалификации", back: "die Weiterbildungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "интерес", back: "das Interesse", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "выходить на пенсию", back: "in Rente gehen", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "жизнь", back: "das Leben", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "пенсионер (муж.)", back: "der Rentner", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "пенсионеры (муж.)", back: "die Rentner", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "пенсионерка (жен.)", back: "die Rentnerin", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "пенсионерки (жен.)", back: "die Rentnerinnen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "мероприятие", back: "die Veranstaltung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "мероприятия", back: "die Veranstaltungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "обращаться", back: "wenden", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "обратился", back: "hat gewandt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "происходить", back: "statt·finden", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "происходил", back: "hat stattgefunden", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "производственный совет", back: "der Betriebsrat", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "производственные советы", back: "die Betriebsräte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "сообщать", back: "berichten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "сообщил", back: "hat berichtet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "консультировать", back: "beraten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "консультировал", back: "hat beraten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "тариф", back: "der Tarif", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "тарифы", back: "die Tarife", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "право", back: "das Recht", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "права", back: "die Rechte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "увольнение (заявление)", back: "die Kündigung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "увольнения", back: "die Kündigungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "увольнение (факт)", back: "die Entlassung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "увольнения", back: "die Entlassungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "предписание", back: "die Vorschrift", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "предписания", back: "die Vorschriften", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "без", back: "ohne", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "увольнять", back: "entlassen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "уволил", back: "hat entlassen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "защищать", back: "schützen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "защищал", back: "hat geschützt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "благодарить", back: "(sich) bedanken", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "поблагодарил", back: "hat bedankt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "передавать (приветы)", back: "aus·richten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "передал", back: "hat ausgerichtet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "экспорт", back: "der Export", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "экспорты", back: "die Exporte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "пытаться", back: "versuchen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "пытался", back: "hat versucht", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "никто", back: "niemand", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "конец рабочего дня", back: "der Feierabend", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "концы рабочего дня", back: "die Feierabende", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "импорт", back: "der Import", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "импорты", back: "die Importe", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "работник", back: "der Arbeitnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "работники", back: "die Arbeitnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "работница", back: "die Arbeitnehmerin", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "работницы", back: "die Arbeitnehmerinnen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "средний", back: "durchschnittlich", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "понятие, догадка", back: "die Ahnung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "понятия, догадки", back: "die Ahnungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "национальный праздник", back: "der Nationalfeiertag", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "национальные праздники", back: "die Nationalfeiertage", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "сверхурочный час", back: "die Überstunde", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "сверхурочные часы", back: "die Überstunden", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "зарплата", back: "der Lohn", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "зарплаты", back: "die Löhne", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "предлагать", back: "bieten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "предлагал", back: "hat geboten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "правило", back: "die Regel", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "правила", back: "die Regeln", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "промышленность", back: "die Industrie", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "среднее значение", back: "der Durchschnitt", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "средние значения", back: "die Durchschnitte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "большинство", back: "die meisten", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "в целом", back: "insgesamt", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "считаться", back: "gelten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "считался", back: "hat gegolten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "как минимум", back: "mindestens", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "двигаться", back: "(sich) bewegen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "двигался", back: "hat bewegt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "интересоваться", back: "(sich) interessieren für", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "интересовался", back: "hat interessiert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "танец", back: "der Tanz", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "танцы", back: "die Tänze", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "баскетбол", back: "der Basketball", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "чувствовать", back: "(sich) fühlen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "чувствовал", back: "hat gefühlt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "слишком мало", back: "zu wenig", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "видео", back: "das Video", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "видео", back: "die Videos", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "падать", back: "hin·fallen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "упал", back: "ist hingefallen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "желание", back: "die Lust", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "клуб, объединение", back: "der Verein", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "клубы, объединения", back: "die Vereine", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "попытка", back: "der Versuch", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "попытки", back: "die Versuche", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "мастер", back: "der Meister", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "мастера", back: "die Meister", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "вид спорта", back: "die Sportart", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "виды спорта", back: "die Sportarten", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "расслабление", back: "die Entspannung", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "питание", back: "die Ernährung", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "движение", back: "die Bewegung", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "движения", back: "die Bewegungen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "в форме", back: "fit", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "прогулка", back: "der Spaziergang", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "прогулки", back: "die Spaziergänge", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "договариваться о встрече", back: "(sich) verabreden mit", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "договорился", back: "hat verabredet", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "отдыхать", back: "(sich) aus·ruhen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "отдыхал", back: "hat ausgeruht", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "питаться", back: "(sich) ernähren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "питался", back: "hat ernährt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "злиться (на)", back: "(sich) ärgern (über)", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "злился", back: "hat geärgert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "краситься", back: "(sich) schminken", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "красился", back: "hat geschminkt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "бриться", back: "(sich) rasieren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "брился", back: "hat rasiert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "переодеваться", back: "(sich) um·ziehen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "переодевался", back: "hat umgezogen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "причёсываться", back: "(sich) kämmen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "причесался", back: "hat gekämmt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "мыться", back: "(sich) waschen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "мылся", back: "hat gewaschen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "торопиться", back: "(sich) beeilen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "торопился", back: "hat beeilt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "концентрироваться (на)", back: "(sich) konzentrieren (auf)", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "сосредоточился", back: "hat konzentriert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "жаловаться (на)", back: "(sich) beschweren (über)", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "жаловался", back: "hat beschwert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "вообще", back: "überhaupt", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "журнал", back: "die Zeitschrift", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "журналы", back: "die Zeitschriften", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "история", back: "die Geschichte", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "театр", back: "das Theater", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "театры", back: "die Theater", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "новости", back: "die Nachrichten", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "чемпионат мира", back: "die Weltmeisterschaft", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "чемпионаты мира", back: "die Weltmeisterschaften", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "прогноз погоды", back: "die Wettervorhersage", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "прогнозы погоды", back: "die Wettervorhersagen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "команда", back: "die Mannschaft", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "команды", back: "die Mannschaften", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "визит, посещение", back: "der Besuch", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "визиты, посещения", back: "die Besuche", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "заботиться о", back: "(sich) kümmern um", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "заботился", back: "hat gekümmert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "мечтать о", back: "träumen von", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "мечтал", back: "hat geträumt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "страх", back: "die Angst", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "страхи", back: "die Ängste", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "честный", back: "ehrlich", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "золото", back: "das Gold", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "сезон", back: "die Saison", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "сезоны", back: "die Saisons", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "вспоминать о", back: "(sich) erinnern an", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "вспоминал", back: "hat erinnert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "думать о", back: "denken an", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "думал", back: "hat gedacht", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "каникулы", back: "die Ferien", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "гимнастика", back: "die Gymnastik", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "настольный теннис", back: "das Tischtennis", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "волейбол", back: "der Volleyball", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "фитнес", back: "die Fitness", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "вклад, статья", back: "der Beitrag", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "вклады, статьи", back: "die Beiträge", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "составлять, равняться", back: "betragen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "составил", back: "hat betragen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "группа", back: "die Gruppe", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "группы", back: "die Gruppen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "скидка", back: "die Ermäßigung", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "скидки", back: "die Ermäßigungen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "бесплатно", back: "kostenlos", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "ученик на производстве", back: "der Azubi", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "ученики на производстве", back: "die Azubis", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "дополнительный", back: "zusätzlich", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "активный", back: "aktiv", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "бегать трусцой", back: "joggen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "бегал трусцой", back: "ist gejoggt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "держаться", back: "(sich) halten", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "держался", back: "hat gehalten", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "часто", back: "häufig", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "причина", back: "die Ursache", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "причины", back: "die Ursachen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "болезнь", back: "die Krankheit", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "болезни", back: "die Krankheiten", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "экран", back: "der Bildschirm", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "экраны", back: "die Bildschirme", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "тело", back: "der Körper", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "тела", back: "die Körper", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "кроме того", back: "außerdem", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "воздух", back: "die Luft", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "обследование", back: "die Untersuchung", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "обследования", back: "die Untersuchungen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "справляться", back: "schaffen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "справился", back: "hat geschafft", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "выгодный, недорогой", back: "preiswert", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "бегать", back: "laufen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "бегал", back: "ist gelaufen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "тренд", back: "der Trend", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "тренды", back: "die Trends", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "игровая площадка", back: "der Spielplatz", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "игровые площадки", back: "die Spielplätze", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "дополнительный", back: "extra", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "гибкий", back: "flexibel", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "окружающая среда", back: "die Umwelt", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "медицинская страховая", back: "die Krankenkasse", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "медицинские страховые", back: "die Krankenkassen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "популярный", back: "beliebt", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "участок, маршрут", back: "die Strecke", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "участки, маршруты", back: "die Strecken", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "ясный", back: "klar", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "преувеличивать", back: "übertreiben", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "преувеличил", back: "hat übertrieben", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "само собой разумеется", back: "selbstverständlich", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "играть в теннис", back: "tennis spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "кататься на лыжах", back: "ski fahren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "катался на лыжах", back: "ist gefahren", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "играть в баскетбол", back: "basketball spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "заниматься гимнастикой", back: "gymnastik machen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "играть в настольный теннис", back: "tischtennis spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "играть в волейбол", back: "volleyball spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "заниматься фитнесом", back: "fitnesstraining machen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "играть в хоккей", back: "eishockey spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "плавать", back: "schwimmen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "плавал", back: "ist geschwommen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "ездить на велосипеде", back: "fahrrad fahren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "ездил на велосипеде", back: "ist gefahren", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "играть в футбол", back: "fußball spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "ходить в походы", back: "wandern", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "ходил в походы", back: "ist gewandert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "танцевать", back: "tanzen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "танцевал", back: "hat getanzt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "свидетельство об обучении", back: "das Zeugnis", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "свидетельства об обучении", back: "die Zeugnisse", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "предмет", back: "das Fach", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "предметы", back: "die Fächer", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "оценка", back: "die Note", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "оценки", back: "die Noten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "гимназия", back: "das Gymnasium", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "гимназии", back: "die Gymnasien", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "доклад", back: "das Referat", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "доклады", back: "die Referate", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "аттестат зрелости", back: "das Abitur", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "окончание, диплом", back: "der Abschluss", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "окончания, дипломы", back: "die Abschlüsse", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "экзамен", back: "die Prüfung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "экзамены", back: "die Prüfungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "ленивый", back: "faul", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "ужасный", back: "schrecklich", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "прилежный, усердный", back: "fleißig", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "умный", back: "intelligent", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "спорить", back: "streiten", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "спорил", back: "hat gestritten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "что (союз)", back: "dass", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "улучшать", back: "verbessern", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "улучшил", back: "hat verbessert", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "поведение", back: "das Verhalten", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "строгий", back: "streng", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "желание", back: "der Wunsch", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "желания", back: "die Wünsche", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "план", back: "der Plan", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "планы", back: "die Pläne", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "астронавт", back: "der Astronaut", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "астронавты", back: "die Astronauten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "астронавтка", back: "die Astronautin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "астронавтки", back: "die Astronautinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "только что, недавно", back: "vorhin", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "средний", back: "mittler-", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "активность", back: "die Aktivität", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "активности", back: "die Aktivitäten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "система", back: "das System", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "системы", back: "die Systeme", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "(профессиональный) вуз", back: "die (Fach-)Hochschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "(профессиональные) вузы", back: "die (Fach-)Hochschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "университет", back: "die Universität", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "университеты", back: "die Universitäten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "объединённая школа", back: "die Gesamtschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "объединённые школы", back: "die Gesamtschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "реальная школа", back: "die Realschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "реальные школы", back: "die Realschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "основная школа", back: "die Hauptschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "основные школы", back: "die Hauptschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "средняя школа", back: "die Mittelschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "средние школы", back: "die Mittelschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "профессионально-техническое училище", back: "die Berufsschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "ПТУ", back: "die Berufsschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "добровольный", back: "freiwillig", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "ясли", back: "die Krippe", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "ясли", back: "die Krippen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "физика", back: "die Physik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "обществоведение", back: "die Sozialkunde", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "биология", back: "die Biologie", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "химия", back: "die Chemie", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "география", back: "die Geografie", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "искусство", back: "die Kunst", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "история", back: "die Geschichte", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "ненавидеть", back: "hassen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "ненавидел", back: "hat gehasst", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "весна", back: "das Frühjahr", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "начало", back: "der Beginn", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "теория", back: "die Theorie", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "теории", back: "die Theorien", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "введение", back: "die Einführung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "введения", back: "die Einführungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "сохранять", back: "speichern", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "сохранил", back: "hat gespeichert", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "мигрант", back: "der Migrant", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "мигранты", back: "die Migranten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "мигрантка", back: "die Migrantin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "мигрантки", back: "die Migrantinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "социальный", back: "sozial", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "доклад", back: "der Vortrag", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "доклады", back: "die Vorträge", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "подавать заявку", back: "(sich) bewerben", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "подал заявку", back: "hat beworben", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "представлять", back: "präsentieren", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "представил", back: "hat präsentiert", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "эксперт", back: "der Experte", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "эксперты", back: "die Experten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "экспертка", back: "die Expertin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "экспертки", back: "die Expertinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "подготовка", back: "die Vorbereitung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "подготовки", back: "die Vorbereitungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "сертификат", back: "das Zertifikat", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "сертификаты", back: "die Zertifikate", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "поддержка", back: "die Förderung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "поддержки", back: "die Förderungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "возможный", back: "möglich", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "консультация", back: "die Beratung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "консультации", back: "die Beratungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "пораниться", back: "sich verletzen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "поранился", back: "hat verletzt", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "кровоточить", back: "bluten", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "кровоточил", back: "hat geblutet", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "обучение в вузе", back: "das Studium", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "распорядок дня", back: "der Tagesablauf", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "распорядки дня", back: "die Tagesabläufe", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "сдавать (экзамен)", back: "bestehen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "сдал", back: "hat bestanden", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "миграционный фон", back: "der Migrationshintergrund", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "гордый", back: "stolz", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "электрический", back: "elektrisch", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "техника", back: "die Technik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "контакт", back: "der Kontakt", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "контакты", back: "die Kontakte", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "признавать", back: "anerkennen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "признал", back: "hat anerkannt", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "проверять", back: "prüfen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "проверил", back: "hat geprüft", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "сложный", back: "kompliziert", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "пекарь", back: "der Bäcker", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "пекари", back: "die Bäcker", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "пекарша", back: "die Bäckerin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "пекарши", back: "die Bäckerinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "актёр", back: "der Schauspieler", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "актёры", back: "die Schauspieler", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "актриса", back: "die Schauspielerin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "актрисы", back: "die Schauspielerinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "музыка", back: "die Musik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "математика", back: "die Mathematik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "спорт", back: "der Sport", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "неизвестный", back: "unbekannt", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "готовить", back: "vorbereiten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "приготовил", back: "hat vorbereitet", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "мастерить", back: "basteln", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "мастерил", back: "hat gebastelt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "решать", back: "entscheiden", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "решил", back: "hat entschieden", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "дарить", back: "schenken", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "подарил", back: "hat geschenkt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "малыш", back: "das Baby", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "малыши", back: "die Babys", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "цепочка", back: "die Kette", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "цепочки", back: "die Ketten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "угадывать", back: "raten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "угадал", back: "hat geraten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "кукла", back: "die Puppe", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "куклы", back: "die Puppen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "DVD", back: "die DVD", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "DVD", back: "die DVDs", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "духи", back: "das Parfüm", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "духи", back: "die Parfüms", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "крем", back: "die Creme", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "кремы", back: "die Cremes", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "кошелек", back: "der Geldbeutel", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "кошельки", back: "die Geldbeutel", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "пробовать", back: "probieren", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "пробовал", back: "hat probiert", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "лапша", back: "die Nudel", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "лапши", back: "die Nudeln", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "доставлять", back: "liefern", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "доставил", back: "hat geliefert", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "надежный", back: "zuverlässig", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "специальный", back: "Sonder-", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "называть", back: "nennen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "назвал", back: "hat genannt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "коробка", back: "die Schachtel", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "коробки", back: "die Schachteln", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "распечатывать", back: "ausdrucken", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "распечатал", back: "hat ausgedruckt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "почтовая марка", back: "die Briefmarke", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "почтовые марки", back: "die Briefmarken", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "люди", back: "die Leute", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "церковь", back: "die Kirche", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "церкви", back: "die Kirchen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "венчание", back: "die Trauung", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "венчания", back: "die Trauungen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "безумный", back: "wahnsinnig", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "настроение", back: "die Stimmung", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "глупый", back: "blöd", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "приветствовать", back: "grüßen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "приветствовал", back: "hat gegrüßt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "прекрасный", back: "wunderschön", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "плакать", back: "weinen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "плакал", back: "hat geweint", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "типичный", back: "typisch", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "торт", back: "die Torte", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "торты", back: "die Torten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "кстати", back: "übrigens", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "ступать", back: "treten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "ступил", back: "ist getreten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "вероятно, пожалуй", back: "wohl", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "нервный", back: "nervös", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "по крайней мере", back: "wenigstens", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "бодрствующий", back: "wach", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "дикий", back: "wild", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "носить", back: "tragen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "носил", back: "hat getragen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "личный", back: "persönlich", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "сердце", back: "das Herz", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "сердца", back: "die Herzen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "смерть", back: "der Tod", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "тратить", back: "ausgeben", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "потратил", back: "hat ausgegeben", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "родина", back: "die Heimat", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "посредством, через", back: "per", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "смс", back: "die SMS", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "смс", back: "die SMS", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "беседовать", back: "sich unterhalten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "беседовал", back: "hat unterhalten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "украшать", back: "dekorieren", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "украшал", back: "hat dekoriert", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "разговор, развлечение", back: "die Unterhaltung", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "разговоры, развлечения", back: "die Unterhaltungen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "убеждать", back: "überzeugen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "убедил", back: "hat überzeugt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "конфета", back: "die Praline", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "конфеты", back: "die Pralinen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "шоколад", back: "die Schokolade", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "шоколады", back: "die Schokoladen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "книга", back: "das Buch", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "книги", back: "die Bücher", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "дерево", back: "das Holz", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "деревья", back: "die Hölzer", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "молоток", back: "der Hammer", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "молотки", back: "die Hämmer", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "инструмент", back: "das Werkzeug", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "инструменты", back: "die Werkzeuge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "играть вместе", back: "mitspielen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "играл вместе", back: "hat mitgespielt", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "дискотека", back: "die Disko / die Diskothek", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "дискотеки", back: "die Diskos / die Diskotheken", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "выходить (в свет)", back: "ausgehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "вышел (в свет)", back: "ist ausgegangen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "проводить (время)", back: "verbringen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "провел (время)", back: "hat verbracht", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "белье", back: "die Wäsche", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "предпринимать", back: "unternehmen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "предпринял", back: "hat unternommen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "вещь", back: "das Ding", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "вещи", back: "die Dinge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "озеро", back: "der See", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "озера", back: "die Seen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "несмотря на", back: "trotzdem", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "велосипедная экскурсия", back: "die Radtour", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "велосипедные экскурсии", back: "die Radtouren", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "блошиный рынок", back: "der Flohmarkt", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "блошиные рынки", back: "die Flohmärkte", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "быть простуженным", back: "erkältet sein", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "постоянный", back: "ständig", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "предложение", back: "der Vorschlag", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "предложения", back: "die Vorschläge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "обзорная поездка", back: "die Rundfahrt", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "обзорные поездки", back: "die Rundfahrten", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "согласный", back: "einverstanden", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "положительный", back: "positiv", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "реагировать", back: "reagieren", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "реагировал", back: "hat reagiert", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "отрицательный", back: "negativ", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "бар", back: "die Bar", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "бары", back: "die Bars", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "культура", back: "die Kultur", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "природа", back: "die Natur", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "опера", back: "die Oper", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "оперы", back: "die Opern", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "место встречи", back: "der Treffpunkt", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "места встречи", back: "die Treffpunkte", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "ратуша", back: "das Rathaus", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "ратуши", back: "die Rathäuser", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "участие", back: "die Teilnahme", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "выступать", back: "auftreten", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "выступил", back: "ist aufgetreten", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "джаз", back: "der Jazz", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "железная дорога", back: "die Bahn", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "железные дороги", back: "die Bahnen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "открытый", back: "offen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "народный университет", back: "die Volkshochschule", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "народные университеты", back: "die Volkshochschulen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "политика", back: "die Politik", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "фотография", back: "die Fotografie", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "необходимый", back: "erforderlich", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "вход свободный", back: "Eintritt frei", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "регистрация не требуется", back: "keine Anmeldung erforderlich", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "семестр", back: "das Semester", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "семестры", back: "die Semester", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "пеший поход", back: "die Wanderung", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "пешие походы", back: "die Wanderungen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "программа", back: "das Programm", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "программы", back: "die Programme", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "фанат", back: "der Fan", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "фанаты", back: "die Fans", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "художник, артист", back: "der Künstler", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "художники, артисты", back: "die Künstler", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "художница, артистка", back: "die Künstlerin", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "художницы, артистки", back: "die Künstlerinnen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "Европа", back: "Europa", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "игрушка", back: "das Spielzeug", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "игрушки", back: "die Spielzeuge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "CD-диск", back: "die CD", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "CD-диски", back: "die CDs", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "по будням", back: "wochentags", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "билет на вход", back: "die Eintrittskarte", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "билеты на вход", back: "die Eintrittskarten", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "передатчик, канал", back: "der Sender", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "передатчики, каналы", back: "die Sender", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "совершать пеший поход", back: "eine Wanderung machen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "делать", back: "machen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "сделал", back: "hat gemacht", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "идти в оперу", back: "in die Oper gehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "в бар", back: "in eine Bar", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "совершать обзорную поездку", back: "eine Rundfahrt machen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "велосипедная экскурсия", back: "eine Radtour", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "идти на блошиный рынок", back: "auf einen Flohmarkt gehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "идти на дискотеку", back: "in die Disko gehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "ехать к озеру", back: "an den See fahren", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "to set up, to arrange", back: "einrichten", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "has set up, has arranged", back: "hat eingerichtet", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the poster", back: "das Poster", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the posters", back: "die Poster", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the candle", back: "die Kerze", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the candles", back: "die Kerzen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "awful, hideous, horrible", back: "scheußlich", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "colorful, multicolored", back: "bunt", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "to look, to watch", back: "gucken", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "has looked, has watched", back: "hat geguckt", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the wallet, the purse", back: "die Brieftasche", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the wallets, the purses", back: "die Brieftaschen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the lighter", back: "das Feuerzeug", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the lighters", back: "die Feuerzeuge", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the camera", back: "die Kamera", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the cameras", back: "die Kameras", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the bikini", back: "der Bikini", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the bikinis", back: "die Bikinis", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "practical", back: "praktisch", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "pretty, lovely", back: "hübsch", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "thick, fat", back: "dick", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the plate", back: "die Platte", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the plates", back: "die Platten", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the height", back: "die Höhe", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the heights", back: "die Höhen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the condition, the state", back: "der Zustand", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the conditions, the states", back: "die Zustände", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the quality", back: "die Qualität", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the qualities", back: "die Qualitäten", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the cutlery", back: "das Besteck", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the cutleries", back: "die Bestecke", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the metal", back: "das Metall", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the metals", back: "die Metalle", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the fabric, the material", back: "der Stoff", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the fabrics, the materials", back: "die Stoffe", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the backpack", back: "der Rucksack", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the backpacks", back: "die Rucksäcke", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the hat", back: "der Hut", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the hats", back: "die Hüte", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the love", back: "die Liebe", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the novel", back: "der Roman", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the novels", back: "die Romane", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "exciting, thrilling", back: "spannend", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "than, as", back: "als", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the stadium", back: "das Stadion", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the stadiums", back: "die Stadien", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the PC, the personal computer", back: "der PC", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the PCs", back: "die PCs", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the pudding", back: "der Pudding", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the puddings", back: "die Puddings", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the shop window", back: "das Schaufenster", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the shop windows", back: "die Schaufenster", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "to suggest", back: "vorschlagen", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "has suggested", back: "hat vorgeschlagen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "distant, removed", back: "entfernt", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the statistics", back: "die Statistik", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the statistics", back: "die Statistiken", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the foodstuff", back: "das Nahrungsmittel", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the foodstuffs", back: "die Nahrungsmittel", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the gas", back: "das Gas", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the gases", back: "die Gase", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the credit", back: "der Kredit", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the credits", back: "die Kredite", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "to record, to admit, to take", back: "aufnehmen", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "has recorded, has admitted", back: "hat aufgenommen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "to save", back: "sparen", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "has saved", back: "hat gespart", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "some, many", back: "manch-", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the memory", back: "die Erinnerung", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the memories", back: "die Erinnerungen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the thought", back: "der Gedanke", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the thoughts", back: "die Gedanken", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "valuable", back: "wertvoll", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "back then, at that time", back: "damals", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "dear, sweet", back: "lieb", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "therefore, that's why", back: "deshalb", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "inside, in there", back: "drin", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the hammer", back: "der Hammer", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the hammers", back: "die Hämmer", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the wood", back: "das Holz", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the woods", back: "die Hölzer", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the lamp", back: "die Lampe", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the lamps", back: "die Lampen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the glass", back: "das Glas", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the glasses", back: "die Gläser", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the cutlery", back: "das Besteck", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the cutleries", back: "die Bestecke", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the metal", back: "das Metall", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the metals", back: "die Metalle", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the (salad) bowl", back: "die (Salat-) Schüssel", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the (salad) bowls", back: "die (Salat-) Schüsseln", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the plastic", back: "das Plastik", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "the entrance ticket", back: "die Eintrittskarte", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the entrance tickets", back: "die Eintrittskarten", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the paper", back: "das Papier", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "the papers", back: "die Papiere", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "the package", back: "das Paket", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the packages", back: "die Pakete", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the envelope", back: "der Briefumschlag", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the envelopes", back: "die Briefumschläge", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the postcard", back: "die Postkarte", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the postcards", back: "die Postkarten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the scissors", back: "die Schere", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the scissors", back: "die Scheren", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to send, to dispatch", back: "verschicken", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has sent, has dispatched", back: "hat verschickt", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to send, to mail", back: "versenden", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has sent, has mailed", back: "hat versendet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "neat, orderly", back: "ordentlich", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the shipment, the broadcast", back: "die Sendung", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the shipments, the broadcasts", back: "die Sendungen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to transport", back: "transportieren", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has transported", back: "hat transportiert", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "hard", back: "hart", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "to weigh", back: "wiegen", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has weighed", back: "hat gewogen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to pack", back: "verpacken", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has packed", back: "hat verpackt", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the ship", back: "das Schiff", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the ships", back: "die Schiffe", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the harvest", back: "die Ernte", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the harvests", back: "die Ernten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "ripe", back: "reif", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "soft", back: "weich", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the imagination, the fantasy", back: "die Fantasie", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the imaginations, the fantasies", back: "die Fantasien", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "what kind of, what a", back: "was für ein-", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the possibility", back: "die Möglichkeit", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the possibilities", back: "die Möglichkeiten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "then, actually, because", back: "denn", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the registered letter", back: "das Einschreiben", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "to send", back: "senden", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has sent", back: "hat gesendet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the small package", back: "das Päckchen", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the small packages", back: "die Päckchen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the customs", back: "der Zoll", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the customs", back: "die Zölle", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "valuable, worth", back: "wert", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "absolutely, necessarily", back: "unbedingt", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the worry, the concern", back: "die Sorge", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the worries, the concerns", back: "die Sorgen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to freeze", back: "frieren", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has frozen", back: "hat gefroren", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the railway", back: "die Eisenbahn", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the railways", back: "die Eisenbahnen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the leaf", back: "das Blatt", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the leaves", back: "die Blätter", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the bear", back: "der Bär", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the bears", back: "die Bären", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the coin", back: "die Münze", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the coins", back: "die Münzen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the duck", back: "die Ente", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the ducks", back: "die Enten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the souvenir", back: "das Souvenir", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the souvenirs", back: "die Souvenirs", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the animal", back: "das Tier", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the animals", back: "die Tiere", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the bird", back: "der Vogel", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the birds", back: "die Vögel", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "un-, not", back: "un-", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the point", back: "der Punkt", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the points", back: "die Punkte", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the elephant", back: "der Elefant", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the elephants", back: "die Elefanten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the rose", back: "die Rose", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the roses", back: "die Rosen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the star", back: "der Stern", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the stars", back: "die Sterne", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the sky", back: "der Himmel", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the skies", back: "die Himmel", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "orange", back: "orange", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the network", back: "das Netzwerk", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the networks", back: "die Netzwerke", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to test", back: "testen", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has tested", back: "hat getestet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the knowledge", back: "das Wissen", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the quiz", back: "das Quiz", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the mobile phone", back: "das Mobiltelefon", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the mobile phones", back: "die Mobiltelefone", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the mail, the email", back: "die Mail", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the mails", back: "die Mails", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "worldwide", back: "weltweit", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the mailbox", back: "die Mailbox", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the mailboxes", back: "die Mailboxen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the success", back: "der Erfolg", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the successes", back: "die Erfolge", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the pub, the tavern", back: "die Kneipe", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the pubs, the taverns", back: "die Kneipen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "to report, to get in touch", back: "melden (sich)", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "has reported, has gotten in touch", back: "hat sich gemeldet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the parent council", back: "der Elternbeirat", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the parent councils", back: "die Elternbeiräte", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the flu", back: "die Grippe", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the vaccination", back: "die Impfung", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the vaccinations", back: "die Impfungen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the consulate", back: "das Konsulat", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the consulates", back: "die Konsulate", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "general", back: "allgemein", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "the letter", back: "der Brief", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the letters", back: "die Briefe", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the mailbox", back: "der Briefkasten", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the mailboxes", back: "die Briefkästen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the email", back: "die E-Mail", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the emails", back: "die E-Mails", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the mobile phone", back: "das Handy", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the mobile phones", back: "die Handys", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the chat", back: "der Chat", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "the chats", back: "die Chats", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "the zoo", back: "der Zoo", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the zoos", back: "die Zoos", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the tiger", back: "der Tiger", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the tigers", back: "die Tiger", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the zebra", back: "das Zebra", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the zebras", back: "die Zebras", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to look at, to watch", back: "anschauen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has looked at, has watched", back: "hat angeschaut", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to leave, to depart", back: "wegfahren", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has left, has departed", back: "ist weggefahren", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to jump", back: "springen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has jumped", back: "ist gesprungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to refuel", back: "tanken", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has refueled", back: "hat getankt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "along", back: "entlang", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "past … at", back: "vorbei … an", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "opposite, across from", back: "gegenüber", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the direction", back: "die Richtung", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the directions", back: "die Richtungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the river", back: "der Fluss", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the rivers", back: "die Flüsse", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the intersection", back: "die Kreuzung", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the intersections", back: "die Kreuzungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to turn (off)", back: "abbiegen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has turned", back: "ist abgebogen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the exit", back: "die Ausfahrt", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the exits", back: "die Ausfahrten", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the copier", back: "der Kopierer", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the copiers", back: "die Kopierer", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the cafeteria", back: "die Cafeteria", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the cafeterias", back: "die Cafeterien", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the traffic jam", back: "der Stau", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the traffic jams", back: "die Staus", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the sidewalk", back: "der Bürgersteig", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the sidewalks", back: "die Bürgersteige", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to fall, to tumble", back: "stürzen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has fallen", back: "ist gestürzt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the cyclist", back: "der Radfahrer", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the cyclists", back: "die Radfahrer", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the knee", back: "das Knie", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the knees", back: "die Knie", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to stick, to glue", back: "kleben", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has stuck, has glued", back: "hat geklebt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the band-aid, plaster", back: "das Pflaster", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the band-aids, plasters", back: "die Pflaster", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the bike, the wheel", back: "das Rad", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the bikes, the wheels", back: "die Räder", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the darling, the favorite", back: "der Liebling", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the darlings, the favorites", back: "die Lieblinge", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to stop, to remain standing", back: "stehen bleiben", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has stopped, has remained standing", back: "ist stehen geblieben", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the gasoline, petrol", back: "das Benzin", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the battery", back: "die Batterie", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the batteries", back: "die Batterien", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "empty", back: "leer", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "on time, punctual", back: "rechtzeitig", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the traffic", back: "der Verkehr", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the construction site", back: "die Baustelle", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the construction sites", back: "die Baustellen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the lane, the track", back: "die Spur", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the lanes, the tracks", back: "die Spuren", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to overtake", back: "überholen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has overtaken", back: "hat überholt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the roadway", back: "die Fahrbahn", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the roadways", back: "die Fahrbahnen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "careful, cautious", back: "vorsichtig", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "because of, due to", back: "wegen", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the ice", back: "das Eis", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the fog", back: "der Nebel", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the fogs", back: "die Nebel", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the storm", back: "der Sturm", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the storms", back: "die Stürme", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the thunderstorm", back: "das Gewitter", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the thunderstorms", back: "die Gewitter", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "foggy", back: "neblig", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the chaos", back: "das Chaos", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "to worry, to care for", back: "sorgen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has worried, has cared for", back: "hat gesorgt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the situation", back: "die Situation", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the situations", back: "die Situationen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "complete", back: "komplett", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "for hours", back: "stundenlang", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the car", back: "der Wagen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the cars", back: "die Wagen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the region", back: "die Region", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the regions", back: "die Regionen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the heat", back: "die Hitze", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the part", back: "das Teil", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the parts", back: "die Teile", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "strong, vigorous", back: "kräftig", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "to avoid", back: "vermeiden", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has avoided", back: "hat vermieden", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the danger", back: "die Gefahr", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the dangers", back: "die Gefahren", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the citizen", back: "der Bürger", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the citizens", back: "die Bürger", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the female citizen", back: "die Bürgerin", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the female citizens", back: "die Bürgerinnen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the view", back: "die Aussicht", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the views", back: "die Aussichten", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to promise", back: "versprechen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has promised", back: "hat versprochen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "summery, hot", back: "sommerlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "dense, close, tight", back: "dicht", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "to prevent", back: "verhindern", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has prevented", back: "hat verhindert", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the start", back: "der Start", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the starts", back: "die Starts", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the landing", back: "die Landung", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the landings", back: "die Landungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the airport", back: "der Flughafen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the airports", back: "die Flughäfen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to start, to take off", back: "starten", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has started, has taken off", back: "ist gestartet", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to land", back: "landen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has landed", back: "ist gelandet", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "expected, likely", back: "voraussichtlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the departure", back: "der Abflug", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the departures", back: "die Abflüge", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "dangerous", back: "gefährlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "to stand out, to be noticeable", back: "auffallen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has stood out, has been noticeable", back: "ist aufgefallen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the moped", back: "das Moped", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the mopeds", back: "die Mopeds", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the means of transport", back: "das Verkehrsmittel", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the means of transport", back: "die Verkehrsmittel", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to honk, to beep", back: "hupen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has honked, has beeped", back: "hat gehupt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "to brake", back: "bremsen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has braked", back: "hat gebremst", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the pedestrian", back: "der Fußgänger", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the pedestrians", back: "die Fußgänger", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the female pedestrian", back: "die Fußgängerin", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the female pedestrians", back: "die Fußgängerinnen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the fine, the ticket", back: "der Strafzettel", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the fines, the tickets", back: "die Strafzettel", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the penalty, the punishment", back: "die Strafe", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the penalties, the punishments", back: "die Strafen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "exhausting, strenuous", back: "anstrengend", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "terrible, awful", back: "furchtbar", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "public", back: "öffentlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "to talk, to speak", back: "reden", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "has talked, has spoken", back: "hat geredet", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the difference", back: "der Unterschied", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "the differences", back: "die Unterschiede", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "the country", back: "das Land", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "the speed, the pace", back: "das Tempo", lesson: "A2.11" },	
{ front: "Балтийское море", back: "die Ostsee", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "выбор", back: "die Wahl", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "осматривать", back: "besichtigen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "осмотрел", back: "hat besichtigt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "против", back: "dagegen", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "восхищённый", back: "begeistert", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "жильё", back: "die Unterkunft", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "жильё (мн. ч.)", back: "die Unterkünfte", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "мечта", back: "der Traum", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "мечты", back: "die Träume", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "побережье", back: "die Küste", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "побережья", back: "die Küsten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "остров", back: "die Insel", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "острова", back: "die Inseln", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "горы", back: "das Gebirge", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "Люксембург", back: "Luxemburg", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "купаться", back: "baden", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "купался", back: "hat gebadet", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "песок", back: "der Sand", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "дальше", back: "weiter", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "прохладный", back: "kühl", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "ферма", back: "der Bauernhof", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "фермы", back: "die Bauernhöfe", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "корова", back: "die Kuh", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "коровы", back: "die Kühe", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "лошадь", back: "das Pferd", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "лошади", back: "die Pferde", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "овца", back: "das Schaf", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "овцы", back: "die Schafe", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "лодка", back: "das Boot", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "лодки", back: "die Boote", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "фестиваль", back: "das Festival", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "фестивали", back: "die Festivals", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "достопримечательность", back: "die Sehenswürdigkeit", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "достопримечательности", back: "die Sehenswürdigkeiten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "прежде всего", back: "vor allem", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "настоящий", back: "echt", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "пансион", back: "die Pension", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "пансионы", back: "die Pensionen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "взгляд", back: "der Blick", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "взгляды", back: "die Blicke", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "одноместный номер", back: "das Einzelzimmer", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "двухместный номер", back: "das Doppelzimmer", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "туалет", back: "das WC", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "туалеты", back: "die WCs", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "полупансион", back: "die Halbpension", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "кемпинг", back: "das Camping", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "тур", back: "die Tour", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "туры", back: "die Touren", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "долина", back: "das Tal", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "долины", back: "die Täler", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "луг", back: "die Wiese", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "луга", back: "die Wiesen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "романтичный", back: "romantisch", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "расположение", back: "die Lage", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "расположения", back: "die Lagen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "замок", back: "das Schloss", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "замки", back: "die Schlösser", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "исторический", back: "historisch", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "многочисленный", back: "zahlreich", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "ночлег", back: "die Übernachtung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "ночлеги", back: "die Übernachtungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "знаменитый", back: "berühmt", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "собор", back: "der Dom", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "соборы", back: "die Dome", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "молодежная гостиница", back: "die Jugendherberge", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "молодежные гостиницы", back: "die Jugendherbergen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "включая", back: "inklusive", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "пребывание", back: "der Aufenthalt", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "пребывания", back: "die Aufenthalte", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "бронировать", back: "buchen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "забронировал", back: "hat gebucht", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "туристическое агентство", back: "das Reisebüro", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "туристические агентства", back: "die Reisebüros", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "специалист", back: "der Spezialist", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "специалисты", back: "die Spezialisten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "сотрудник", back: "der Angestellte", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "сотрудники", back: "die Angestellten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "сотрудница", back: "die Angestellte", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "сотрудницы", back: "die Angestellten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "связь", back: "die Verbindung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "связи", back: "die Verbindungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "конечно", back: "natürlich", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "серфить", back: "surfen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "серфил", back: "ist gesurft", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "экскурсия", back: "die Führung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "экскурсии", back: "die Führungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "старый город", back: "die Altstadt", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "старые города", back: "die Altstädte", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "выставка", back: "die Ausstellung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "выставки", back: "die Ausstellungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "известный", back: "bekannt", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "нигде", back: "nirgends", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "паковать", back: "einpacken", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "упаковал", back: "hat eingepackt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "договориться", back: "einigen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "договорился", back: "hat geeinigt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "ночевать", back: "übernachten", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "ночевал", back: "hat übernachtet", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "быть против", back: "dagegen sein", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "был против", back: "ist dagegen gewesen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "быть за", back: "dafür sein", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "был за", back: "ist dafür gewesen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "принимать", back: "annehmen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "принял", back: "hat angenommen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "отклонять", back: "ablehnen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "отклонил", back: "hat abgelehnt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "лениться", back: "faulenzen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "ленился", back: "hat gefaulenzt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "туристическая цель", back: "das Reiseziel", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "туристические цели", back: "die Reiseziele", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "занятия", back: "die Aktivitäten", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "осматривать достопримечательности", back: "Sehenswürdigkeiten ansehen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "осмотрел достопримечательности", back: "hat Sehenswürdigkeiten angesehen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "осматривать старый город", back: "die Altstadt besichtigen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "осмотрел старый город", back: "hat die Altstadt besichtigt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "смотреть выставку", back: "eine Ausstellung ansehen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "посмотрел выставку", back: "hat eine Ausstellung angesehen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "делать экскурсию по городу", back: "eine Stadtführung machen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "сделал экскурсию по городу", back: "hat eine Stadtführung gemacht", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "в туристическом агентстве", back: "im Reisebüro", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "бронировать поездку", back: "eine Reise buchen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "забронировал поездку", back: "hat eine Reise gebucht", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "справка", back: "die Auskunft", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "путешествие", back: "die Reise", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "путешествия", back: "die Reisen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "офис", back: "das Büro", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "офисы", back: "die Büros", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "лёд", back: "das Eis", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "яйцо", back: "das Ei", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "яйца", back: "die Eier", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "сумма", back: "der Betrag", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "суммы", back: "die Beträge", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "счёт", back: "das Konto", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "счёта", back: "die Konten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "открывать", back: "eröffnen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "открыл", back: "hat eröffnet", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "отвечать", back: "beantworten", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "ответил", back: "hat beantwortet", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "достать, приобрести", back: "besorgen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "достал", back: "hat besorgt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "откладывать", back: "verschieben", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "отложил", back: "hat verschoben", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "банковская карта", back: "die EC-Karte", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "банковские карты", back: "die EC-Karten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "снимать (деньги)", back: "abheben", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "снял", back: "hat abgehoben", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "получать", back: "kriegen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "получил", back: "hat gekriegt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "банкомат", back: "der Geldautomat", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "банкоматы", back: "die Geldautomaten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "расчётный счёт", back: "das Girokonto", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "расчётные счёта", back: "die Girokonten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "ли", back: "ob", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "наличные деньги", back: "das Bargeld", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "сумма", back: "die Summe", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "суммы", back: "die Summen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "но (после отрицания)", back: "sondern", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "ежемесячный", back: "monatlich", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "проценты", back: "die Zinsen", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "принимать", back: "akzeptieren", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "принял", back: "hat akzeptiert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "карманные деньги", back: "das Taschengeld", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "выполнять, завершать", back: "erledigen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "выполнил", back: "hat erledigt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "контролировать", back: "kontrollieren", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "контролировал", back: "hat kontrolliert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "контроль", back: "die Kontrolle", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "контроли", back: "die Kontrollen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "ломаться", back: "kaputtgehen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "сломался", back: "ist kaputtgegangen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "узнавать", back: "erkennen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "узнал", back: "hat erkannt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "производитель", back: "der Hersteller", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "производители", back: "die Hersteller", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "масло", back: "das Öl", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "тормоз", back: "die Bremse", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "тормоза", back: "die Bremsen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "проверять", back: "überprüfen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "проверил", back: "hat überprüft", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "ремонтировать", back: "renovieren", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "отремонтировал", back: "hat renoviert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "изменять", back: "ändern", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "изменил", back: "hat geändert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "порезаться", back: "schneiden (sich)", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "порезался", back: "hat geschnitten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "вносить деньги", back: "einzahlen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "внес деньги", back: "hat eingezahlt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "брошюра", back: "die Broschüre", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "брошюры", back: "die Broschüren", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "зарплата", back: "das Gehalt", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "зарплаты", back: "die Gehälter", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "справка о зарплате", back: "der Gehaltsnachweis", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "справки о зарплате", back: "die Gehaltsnachweise", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "набирать (текст)", back: "tippen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "набрал", back: "hat getippt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "переводить (деньги)", back: "überweisen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "перевёл", back: "hat überwiesen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "меню", back: "das Menü", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "меню (мн. ч.)", back: "die Menüs", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "официант", back: "der Ober", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "официанты", back: "die Ober", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "полиция", back: "die Polizei", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "злой", back: "böse", lesson: "A2.13" },	
{ front: "настроение", back: "die Laune", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "настроения", back: "die Launen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "повышение", back: "die Erhöhung", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "повышения", back: "die Erhöhungen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "выписка со счёта", back: "der Kontoauszug", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "выписки со счёта", back: "die Kontoauszüge", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "снимать деньги", back: "Geld abheben", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "снял деньги", back: "hat abgehoben", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "опрос", back: "die Umfrage", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "опросы", back: "die Umfragen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "едва", back: "kaum", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "будущее", back: "die Zukunft", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "решение", back: "die Entscheidung", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "решения", back: "die Entscheidungen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "умирать", back: "sterben", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "умер", back: "ist gestorben", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "детство", back: "die Kindheit", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "детства", back: "die Kindheiten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "рядом", back: "nebenan", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "влюбляться", back: "verlieben (sich)", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "влюбился", back: "hat sich verliebt", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "ерунда", back: "der Quatsch", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "учёба / обучение", back: "die Lehre", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "учёбы / обучения", back: "die Lehren", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "случайно", back: "zufällig", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "заведение (кафе, ресторан и т.п.)", back: "das Lokal", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "заведения", back: "die Lokale", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "с тех пор", back: "seitdem", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "единственный-", back: "einzig-", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "противоположность", back: "das Gegenteil", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "противоположности", back: "die Gegenteile", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "всё равно", back: "egal", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "ссора", back: "der Streit", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "ссоры", back: "die Streite", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "пара", back: "das Paar", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "пары", back: "die Paare", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "воспитание", back: "die Erziehung", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "мнение", back: "die Meinung", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "мнения", back: "die Meinungen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "совет", back: "der Ratschlag", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "советы", back: "die Ratschläge", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "мышь", back: "die Maus", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "мыши", back: "die Mäuse", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "скорее", back: "eher", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "популярный", back: "populär", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "курильщик", back: "der Raucher", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "курильщики", back: "die Raucher", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "курильщица", back: "die Raucherin", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "курильщицы", back: "die Raucherinnen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "сказка", back: "das Märchen", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "сказки", back: "die Märchen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "заговорить", back: "ansprechen", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "заговорил", back: "hat angesprochen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "благодарить", back: "danken", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "поблагодарил", back: "hat gedankt", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "идея", back: "der Einfall", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "идеи", back: "die Einfälle", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "мир", back: "die Welt", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "миры", back: "die Welten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "домашнее животное", back: "das Haustier", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "домашние животные", back: "die Haustiere", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "серьёзный", back: "ernst", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "удобный", back: "bequem", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "детство", back: "die Kindheit", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "детства", back: "die Kindheiten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "пара", back: "das Paar", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "пары", back: "die Paare", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "решение", back: "die Entscheidung", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "решения", back: "die Entscheidungen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "опрос", back: "die Umfrage", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "опросы", back: "die Umfragen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "мир", back: "die Welt", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "миры", back: "die Welten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "событие", back: "das Erlebnis", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "события", back: "die Erlebnisse", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "статья", back: "der Artikel", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "быть", back: "sein", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "был отсутствовал", back: "sein weg gewesen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "религия", back: "die Religion", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "религии", back: "die Religionen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "неожиданность", back: "die Überraschung", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "неожиданности", back: "die Überraschungen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "сумасшедший", back: "verrückt", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "выигрыш", back: "der Gewinn", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "выигрыши", back: "die Gewinne", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "налог", back: "die Steuer", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "голос", back: "die Stimme", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "голоса", back: "die Stimmen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "садиться", back: "sich setzen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "сел(ся)", back: "hat sich gesetzt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "смелый", back: "mutig", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "сообщение", back: "die Meldung", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "сообщения", back: "die Meldungen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "заголовок", back: "die Überschrift", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "заголовки", back: "die Überschriften", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "во время", back: "während", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "исчезать", back: "verschwinden", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "исчезнул", back: "ist verschwunden", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "несколько", back: "mehrer-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "напрасно", back: "vergeblich", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "подниматься", back: "steigen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "поднялся", back: "ist gestiegen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "удивляться", back: "sich wundern", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "удивился", back: "hat sich gewundert", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "хотя", back: "zwar", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "смелость", back: "der Mut", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "оба", back: "beid-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "достигать", back: "erreichen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "достиг", back: "hat erreicht", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "глубокий", back: "tief", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "путать", back: "verwechseln", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "перепутал", back: "hat verwechselt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "средство", back: "das Mittel", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "согласный", back: "einig-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "находиться", back: "sich befinden", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "находился", back: "hat sich befunden", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "обдумывать", back: "nachdenken", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "обдумал", back: "hat nachgedacht", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "указание", back: "die Angabe", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "указания", back: "die Angaben", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "спасать", back: "retten", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "спас", back: "hat gerettet", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "быть достаточным", back: "ausreichen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "хватило", back: "hat ausgereicht", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "досада", back: "der Ärger", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "следовать", back: "folgen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "последовал", back: "ist gefolgt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "по крайней мере", back: "zumindest", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "отменять", back: "absagen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "отменил", back: "hat abgesagt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "звать", back: "rufen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "позвал", back: "hat gerufen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "перекрывать", back: "absperren", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "перекрыл", back: "hat abgesperrt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "задерживать", back: "festnehmen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "задержал", back: "hat festgenommen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "пьяный", back: "betrunken", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "грабитель", back: "der Einbrecher", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "захватывающий", back: "aufregend", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "смешной", back: "witzig", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "мотороллер", back: "der Motorroller", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "быть", back: "sein", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "был влюблён", back: "ist verliebt gewesen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "ломать / ломаться", back: "brechen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "сломался / сломал", back: "ist/hat gebrochen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "тренер", back: "der Trainer", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "тренер (ж.р.)", back: "die Trainerin", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "тренеры (ж.р.)", back: "die Trainerinnen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "поле", back: "das Feld", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "поля", back: "die Felder", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "весь", back: "aller-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "ворота", back: "das Tor", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "ворота", back: "die Tore", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "бежать / убегать", back: "fliehen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "убежал", back: "ist geflohen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "лучший", back: "best-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "загс", back: "das Standesamt", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "загсы", back: "die Standesämter", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "стрелять", back: "schießen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "стрелял", back: "hat geschossen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "ущерб", back: "der Schaden", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "ущербы", back: "die Schäden", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "занавес", back: "der Vorhang", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "занавески", back: "die Vorhänge", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "мгновенный", back: "augenblicklich", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "кусать", back: "beißen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "кусал", back: "hat gebissen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "пугать / испугаться", back: "erschrecken", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "испугался", back: "ist erschrocken", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "контакт", back: "der Kontakt", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "контакты", back: "die Kontakte", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "данные", back: "die Daten", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "разговор", back: "das Gespräch", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "разговоры", back: "die Gespräche", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "отчёт", back: "der Bericht", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "отчёты", back: "die Berichte", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "полночь", back: "die Mitternacht", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "камень", back: "der Stein", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "камни", back: "die Steine", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "лев", back: "der Löwe", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "львы", back: "die Löwen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "сообщение", back: "die Meldung", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "сообщения", back: "die Meldungen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "заголовок", back: "die Überschrift", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "заголовки", back: "die Überschriften", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "статья", back: "der Artikel", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "отчёт", back: "der Bericht", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "отчёты", back: "die Berichte", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "интервью", back: "das Interview", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "интервью", back: "die Interviews", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "информация", back: "die Information", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "информации", back: "die Informationen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "объявление", back: "die Anzeige", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "объявления", back: "die Anzeigen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "сериал", back: "die Serie", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "сериалы", back: "die Serien", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "серия", back: "die Folge", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "серии", back: "die Folgen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "характер", back: "der Charakter", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "характеры", back: "die Charaktere", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "хотя", back: "obwohl", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "постоянно", back: "dauernd", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "проигравший", back: "der Verlierer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "проигравшие", back: "die Verlierer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "тип", back: "der Typ", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "типы", back: "die Typen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "оптимистичный", back: "optimistisch", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "фигура", back: "die Figur", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "фигуры", back: "die Figuren", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "невероятный", back: "unglaublich", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "изобретать", back: "erfinden", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "изобрёл", back: "hat erfunden", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "операция", back: "die Operation", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "операции", back: "die Operationen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "кровь", back: "das Blut", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "криминальный", back: "Kriminal", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "публиковать", back: "veröffentlichen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "опубликовал", back: "hat veröffentlicht", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "случай", back: "der Fall", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "случаи", back: "die Fälle", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "учебный словарь", back: "der Lernwortschatz", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "сегодняшний", back: "heutig", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "действовать", back: "handeln", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "действовал", back: "hat gehandelt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "прошлое", back: "die Vergangenheit", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "певица", back: "die Sängerin", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "певицы", back: "die Sängerinnen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "группа", back: "die Band", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "группы", back: "die Bands", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "возникать", back: "entstehen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "возник", back: "ist entstanden", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "электронный", back: "elektronisch", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "производить", back: "produzieren", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "произвёл", back: "hat produziert", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "большой город", back: "die Großstadt", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "большие города", back: "die Großstädte", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "тем временем", back: "inzwischen", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "сначала", back: "anfangs", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "так называемый", back: "sogenannt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "песня", back: "der Song", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "песни", back: "die Songs", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "хит", back: "der Hit", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "хиты", back: "die Hits", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "полностью", back: "völlig", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "юмор", back: "der Humor", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "повседневный", back: "alltäglich", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "насилие", back: "die Gewalt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "критиковать", back: "kritisieren", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "критиковал", back: "hat kritisiert", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "звезда", back: "der Star", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "звёзды", back: "die Stars", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "сцена", back: "die Szene", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "успешный", back: "erfolgreich", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "заниматься", back: "sich beschäftigen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "занимался", back: "hat sich beschäftigt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "безработица", back: "die Arbeitslosigkeit", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "лагерь", back: "das Lager", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "лагеря", back: "die Lager", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "отношение", back: "das Verhältnis", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "отношения", back: "die Verhältnisse", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "удаваться", back: "gelingen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "удалось", back: "ist gelungen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "совет", back: "der Rat", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "в конце концов", back: "zuletzt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "покидать", back: "verlassen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "покинул", back: "hat verlassen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "сопровождать", back: "begleiten", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "сопровождал", back: "hat begleitet", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "ящик", back: "die Kiste", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "ящики", back: "die Kisten", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "берег", back: "das Ufer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "берега", back: "die Ufer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "мыть", back: "spülen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "вымыл", back: "hat gespült", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "снаружи", back: "außen", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "внутри", back: "innen", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "встречать", back: "begegnen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "встретил", back: "ist begegnet", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "приключение", back: "das Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "приключения", back: "die Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "сбываться", back: "sich erfüllen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "сбылось", back: "hat sich erfüllt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "за это", back: "dafür", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "соглашаться", back: "zustimmen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "согласился", back: "hat zugestimmt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "СМИ", back: "die Medien", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "СМИ", back: "die Medien", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "радио", back: "der Rundfunk", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "чуть-чуть", back: "knapp", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "двойной", back: "doppelt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "относительно", back: "relativ", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "сериал", back: "die Serie", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "сериалы", back: "die Serien", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "серия", back: "die Folge", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "серии", back: "die Folgen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "фигура", back: "die Figur", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "фигуры", back: "die Figuren", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "характер", back: "der Charakter", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "характеры", back: "die Charaktere", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "криминальный", back: "Kriminal", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "радио", back: "der Rundfunk", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "приключение", back: "das Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "приключения", back: "die Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "кино", back: "das Kino", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "кинотеатры", back: "die Kinos", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "желудок", back: "der Magen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "желудки", back: "die Mägen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "уговаривать", back: "überreden", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "уговорил", back: "hat überredet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "договариваться", back: "vereinbaren", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "договорился", back: "hat vereinbart", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "средство", back: "das Mittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "средства", back: "die Mittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "сон", back: "der Schlaf", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "фактор", back: "der Faktor", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "факторы", back: "die Faktoren", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "ночью", back: "nachts", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "основа", back: "die Grundlage", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "основы", back: "die Grundlagen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "достаточный", back: "ausreichend", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "обращать внимание", back: "achten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "обратил внимание", back: "hat geachtet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "жир", back: "das Fett", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "жиры", back: "die Fette", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "идеальный", back: "ideal", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "также", back: "ebenfalls", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "дышать", back: "atmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "дышал", back: "hat geatmet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "плоский", back: "flach", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "действие, эффект", back: "die Wirkung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "действия, эффекты", back: "die Wirkungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "чаще", back: "öfter", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "сила", back: "die Kraft", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "силы", back: "die Kräfte", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "одновременно", back: "gleichzeitig", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "истощённый", back: "erschöpft", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "результат", back: "das Ergebnis", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "результаты", back: "die Ergebnisse", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "обходить, обращаться", back: "umgehen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "обошёл, обращался", back: "ist umgegangen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "просыпаться", back: "aufwachen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "проснулся", back: "bist aufgewacht", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "недостаток", back: "der Mangel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "недостатки", back: "die Mängel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "экстремальный", back: "extrem", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "измерять", back: "messen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "измерил", back: "hat gemessen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "худеть / уменьшать", back: "abnehmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "похудел / уменьшил", back: "hat abgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "вес", back: "das Gewicht", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "обследовать, исследовать", back: "untersuchen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "обследовал", back: "hat untersucht", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "мусорное ведро", back: "der Abfalleimer", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "мусорные ведра", back: "die Abfalleimer", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "улучшение", back: "die Verbesserung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "улучшения", back: "die Verbesserungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "приём (лекарств)", back: "die Einnahme", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "такой", back: "solch", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "специалист", back: "der Fachmann", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "специалисты", back: "die Fachmänner", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "плечо", back: "die Schulter", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "плечи", back: "die Schultern", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "сначала", back: "zunächst", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "предполагать", back: "vermuten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "предположил", back: "hat vermutet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "нарушение", back: "die Störung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "нарушения", back: "die Störungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "обезболивающее средство", back: "das Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "обезболивающие средства", back: "die Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "вести", back: "führen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "вел", back: "hat geführt", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "выписывать (рецепт)", back: "verschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "выписал (рецепт)", back: "hat verschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "получать", back: "erhalten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "получил", back: "hat erhalten", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "худеть / уменьшать", back: "abnehmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "похудел / уменьшил", back: "hat abgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "благополучие", back: "das Wohl", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "бесплатно, зря", back: "umsonst", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "участвовать", back: "teilnehmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "участвовал", back: "hat teilgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "Leistung", back: "die Leistung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "Leistungen", back: "die Leistungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "делать прививку", back: "impfen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "сделал прививку", back: "hat geimpft", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "заниматься (спортом и т.п.)", back: "treiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "занимался", back: "hat getrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "половина", back: "die Hälfte", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "половины", back: "die Hälften", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "четверть", back: "das Viertel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "четверти", back: "die Viertel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "треть", back: "das Drittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "трети", back: "die Drittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "в основном, принципиально", back: "grundsätzlich", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "фрукт", back: "die Frucht", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "фрукты", back: "die Früchte", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "отказываться", back: "verzichten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "отказался", back: "hat verzichtet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "творог", back: "der Quark", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "витамин", back: "das Vitamin", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "витамины", back: "die Vitamine", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "сообщать о болезни", back: "krankmelden", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "сообщил о болезни", back: "hat krankgemeldet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "выписывать больничный", back: "krankschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "выписал больничный", back: "hat krankgeschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "конференция", back: "die Konferenz", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "конференции", back: "die Konferenzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "блокнот", back: "der Schreibblock", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "блокноты", back: "die Schreibblöcke", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "лаборатория", back: "das Labor", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "лаборатории", back: "die Labors / die Labore", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "повязка", back: "der Verband", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "повязки", back: "die Verbände", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "шприц", back: "die Spritze", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "шприцы", back: "die Spritzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "обследовать (кого-то/что-то)", back: "untersuchen (jemanden/etwas)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "обследовал", back: "hat untersucht", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "делать прививку (кому-то)", back: "impfen (jemanden)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "сделал прививку", back: "hat geimpft", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "лекарство", back: "das Medikament", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "лекарства", back: "die Medikamente", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "выписывать (рецепт)", back: "verschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "выписал (рецепт)", back: "hat verschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "кого-то", back: "jemanden", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "выписывать больничный", back: "krankschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "выписал больничный", back: "hat krankgeschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "шприц", back: "die Spritze", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "шприцы", back: "die Spritzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "повязка", back: "der Verband", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "повязки", back: "die Verbände", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "обезболивающее средство", back: "das Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "обезболивающие средства", back: "die Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "мазь", back: "die Salbe", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "мази", back: "die Salben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "боль", back: "der Schmerz", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "боли", back: "die Schmerzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "насморк", back: "der Schnupfen", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "измерять (артериальное давление)", back: "messen (den Blutdruck)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "измерил", back: "hat gemessen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "сдавать (кровь)", back: "abnehmen (Blut)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "сдал кровь", back: "hat abgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "проверять (вес)", back: "prüfen (das Gewicht)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "проверил", back: "hat geprüft", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "живот", back: "der Bauch", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "животы", back: "die Bäuche", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "температура (жар)", back: "das Fieber", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "кашель", back: "der Husten", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "о чём", back: "worüber", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "спешка", back: "die Eile", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "подвал", back: "der Keller", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "подвалы", back: "die Keller", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "там, здесь", back: "da", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "предложение", back: "der Satz", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "предложения", back: "die Sätze", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "этот, та", back: "da(r)-", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "совсем, вообще", back: "gar", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "во всяком случае", back: "jedenfalls", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "улыбаться", back: "lächeln", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "улыбался", back: "hat gelächelt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "просто, ну", back: "halt", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "ясно, чётко", back: "deutlich", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "столько", back: "so viel", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "намереваться", back: "vorhaben", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "намеревался", back: "hat vorgehabt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "правда", back: "die Wahrheit", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "правды", back: "die Wahrheiten", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "лгать", back: "lügen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "лгал", back: "hat gelogen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "заканчивать", back: "beenden", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "закончил", back: "hat beendet", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "место для обучения", back: "der Ausbildungsplatz", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "места для обучения", back: "die Ausbildungsplätze", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "выбирать", back: "aussuchen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "выбрал", back: "hat ausgesucht", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "президент / президентка", back: "der Präsident / die Präsidentin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "президенты / президентки", back: "die Präsidenten / Präsidentinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "кошелёк", back: "das Portemonnaie", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "кошельки", back: "die Portemonnaies", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "бегло", back: "fließend", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "поэтому", back: "deswegen", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "когда-нибудь", back: "irgendwann", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "переводить", back: "übersetzen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "перевёл", back: "hat übersetzt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "поэтому", back: "daher", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "родной язык", back: "die Muttersprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "родные языки", back: "die Muttersprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "произношение", back: "die Aussprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "поэтому", back: "darum", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "записывать", back: "aufschreiben", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "записал", back: "hat aufgeschrieben", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "выражение", back: "der Ausdruck", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "выражения", back: "die Ausdrücke", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "ещё раз", back: "noch mal", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "механик", back: "der Mechaniker", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "механики", back: "die Mechaniker", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "механик (женщина)", back: "die Mechanikerin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "механики (женщины)", back: "die Mechanikerinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "повторение", back: "die Wiederholung", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "повторения", back: "die Wiederholungen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "студенческая столовая", back: "die Mensa", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "студенческие столовые", back: "die Mensen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "курс интеграции", back: "der Integrationskurs", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "курсы интеграции", back: "die Integrationskurse", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "происхождение", back: "die Herkunft", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "происхождения", back: "die Herkünfte", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "прятаться", back: "sich verstecken", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "прятался", back: "hat sich versteckt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "классный, крутой", back: "cool", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "греческий язык", back: "das Griechisch", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "грек", back: "der Grieche", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "греки", back: "die Griechen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "гречанка", back: "die Griechin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "гречанки", back: "die Griechinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "перепутанный, в беспорядке", back: "durcheinander", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "не позднее", back: "spätestens", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "выбирать", back: "wählen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "выбрал", back: "hat gewählt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "происходить", back: "stammen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "происходил", back: "hat gestammt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "соус", back: "die Soße", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "соусы", back: "die Soßen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "постепенно", back: "allmählich", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "нерв", back: "der Nerv", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "нервы", back: "die Nerven", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "странный", back: "merkwürdig", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "правильный", back: "korrekt", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "с другой стороны", back: "andererseits", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "также", back: "ebenso", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "лоб", back: "die Stirn", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "лбы", back: "die Stirnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "страдать", back: "leiden", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "страдал", back: "hat gelitten", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "смешивать", back: "mischen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "смешивал", back: "hat gemischt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "однако", back: "allerdings", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "существовать, выдержать", back: "bestehen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "существовал, выдержал", back: "hat bestanden", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "автор", back: "der Autor", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "авторы", back: "die Autoren", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "автор (женщина)", back: "die Autorin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "авторы (женщины)", back: "die Autorinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "знания", back: "die Kenntnisse", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "знания", back: "die Kenntnisse", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "сравнивать", back: "vergleichen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "сравнил", back: "hat verglichen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "партнёр", back: "der Partner", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "партнёры", back: "die Partner", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "партнёр (женщина)", back: "die Partnerin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "партнёры (женщины)", back: "die Partnerinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "ругаться", back: "schimpfen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "ругался", back: "hat geschimpft", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "письменность, почерк", back: "die Schrift", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "письменности, почерки", back: "die Schriften", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "родной язык", back: "die Muttersprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "родные языки", back: "die Muttersprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "иностранный язык", back: "die Fremdsprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "иностранные языки", back: "die Fremdsprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "языковая школа", back: "die Sprachenschule", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "языковые школы", back: "die Sprachenschulen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "произношение", back: "die Aussprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "произношения", back: "die Aussprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "письменность, почерк", back: "die Schrift", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "письменности, почерки", back: "die Schriften", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "бегло", back: "fließend", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "переводить", back: "übersetzen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "перевёл", back: "hat übersetzt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "к, в, на", back: "zu", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "талант", back: "das Talent", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "таланты", back: "die Talente", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "примерно, около", back: "etwa", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "быть достаточным", back: "genügen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "было достаточно", back: "hat genügt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "прекращать", back: "aufhören", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "прекратил", back: "hat aufgehört", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "торговля", back: "der Handel", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "преимущество", back: "der Vorteil", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "преимущества", back: "die Vorteile", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "ожидать", back: "erwarten", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "ожидал", back: "hat erwartet", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "предпосылка", back: "die Voraussetzung", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "предпосылки", back: "die Voraussetzungen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "сотрудник сервиса", back: "der Serviceangestellte", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "сотрудники сервиса", back: "die Serviceangestellten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "сотрудница сервиса", back: "die Serviceangestellte", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "сотрудницы сервиса", back: "die Serviceangestellten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "документы", back: "die Unterlagen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "документы", back: "die Unterlagen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "задание", back: "die Aufgabe", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "задания", back: "die Aufgaben", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "поддержка", back: "die Unterstützung", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "поддержки", back: "die Unterstützungen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "письменный", back: "schriftlich", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "устанавливать", back: "feststellen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "установил", back: "hat festgestellt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "привыкший", back: "gewohnt", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "обычный", back: "üblich", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "установка, приложение", back: "die Anlage", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "установки, приложения", back: "die Anlagen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "резюме", back: "der Lebenslauf", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "резюме", back: "die Lebensläufe", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "развивать", back: "entwickeln", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "развил", back: "hat entwickelt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "производить", back: "herstellen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "произвёл", back: "hat hergestellt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "деятельность", back: "die Tätigkeit", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "деятельности", back: "die Tätigkeiten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "вне", back: "außerhalb", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "внутри", back: "innerhalb", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "момент времени", back: "der Zeitpunkt", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "моменты времени", back: "die Zeitpunkte", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "считать", back: "rechnen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "посчитал", back: "hat gerechnet", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "зеркало", back: "der Spiegel", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "зеркала", back: "die Spiegel", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "успокаиваться", back: "sich beruhigen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "успокоился", back: "hat sich beruhigt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "технический", back: "technisch", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "ответственный", back: "zuständig", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "совместный, вместе", back: "zusammen-", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "ответственность", back: "die Verantwortung", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "маляр", back: "der Maler", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "маляры", back: "die Maler", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "маляр (женщина)", back: "die Malerin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "малярши", back: "die Malerinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "заказ", back: "der Auftrag", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "заказы", back: "die Aufträge", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "переводчик", back: "der Übersetzer", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "переводчики", back: "die Übersetzer", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "переводчица", back: "die Übersetzerin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "переводчицы", back: "die Übersetzerinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "обдумывать", back: "sich überlegen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "обдумал", back: "hat überlegt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "конкуренция", back: "die Konkurrenz", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "кстати, между прочим", back: "nebenbei", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "подрабатывать", back: "jobben", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "подработал", back: "hat gejobbt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "справляться", back: "zurechtkommen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "справился", back: "ist zurechtgekommen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "зоопарк", back: "der Tierpark", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "зоопарки", back: "die Tierparks", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "повышение квалификации", back: "die Fortbildung", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "повышения квалификации", back: "die Fortbildungen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "представлять", back: "vertreten", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "представлял", back: "hat vertreten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "учитель", back: "der Lehrer", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "учителя", back: "die Lehrer", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "учительница", back: "die Lehrerin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "учительницы", back: "die Lehrerinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "дворник, домоуправ", back: "der Hausmeister", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "дворники, домоуправы", back: "die Hausmeister", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "дворничиха, домоуправ", back: "die Hausmeisterin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "дворничихи, домоуправы", back: "die Hausmeisterinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "врач", back: "der Arzt", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "врачи", back: "die Ärzte", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "врач (женщина)", back: "die Ärztin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "врачи (женщины)", back: "die Ärztinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "архитектор", back: "der Architekt", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "архитекторы", back: "die Architekten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "архитектор (женщина)", back: "die Architektin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "архитекторы (женщины)", back: "die Architektinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "парикмахер", back: "der Friseur", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "парикмахеры", back: "die Friseure", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "парикмахер (женщина)", back: "die Friseurin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "парикмахеры (женщины)", back: "die Friseurinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "журналист", back: "der Journalist", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "журналисты", back: "die Journalisten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "санитар", back: "der Krankenpfleger", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "санитары", back: "die Krankenpfleger", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "журналистка", back: "die Journalistin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "журналистки", back: "die Journalistinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "медсестра", back: "die Krankenschwester", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "медсестры", back: "die Krankenschwestern", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "полицейский", back: "der Polizist", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "полицейские", back: "die Polizisten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "полицейская", back: "die Polizistin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "полицейские (женщины)", back: "die Polizistinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "продавец", back: "der Verkäufer", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "продавцы", back: "die Verkäufer", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "продавщица", back: "die Verkäuferin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "продавщицы", back: "die Verkäuferinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "вместо", back: "statt", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "сначала, первый", back: "erst-", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "производство", back: "die Produktion", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "производства", back: "die Produktionen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "замена", back: "der Ersatz", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "определённый", back: "bestimmt", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "решать", back: "lösen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "решил", back: "hat gelöst", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "тайна", back: "das Geheimnis", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "тайны", back: "die Geheimnisse", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "риск", back: "das Risiko", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "риски", back: "die Risiken", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "изменение", back: "die Änderung", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "изменения", back: "die Änderungen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "смысл", back: "der Sinn", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "быть выгодным", back: "sich lohnen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "было выгодно", back: "hat gelohnt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "время года", back: "die Jahreszeit", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "времена года", back: "die Jahreszeiten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "владеть", back: "besitzen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "владел", back: "hat besessen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "родиться", back: "geboren werden", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "родился", back: "ist geboren worden", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "решиться", back: "sich entschließen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "решился", back: "hat entschlossen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "тоска по дому", back: "das Heimweh", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "соревнование", back: "der Wettbewerb", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "соревнования", back: "die Wettbewerbe", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "приправа", back: "das Gewürz", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "приправы", back: "die Gewürze", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "тем временем, между тем", back: "mittlerweile", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "уважение, внимание", back: "die Rücksicht", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "уважения, внимания", back: "die Rücksichten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "межкультурный", back: "interkulturell", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "основывать", back: "gründen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "основал", back: "hat gegründet", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "заботиться", back: "betreuen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "заботился", back: "hat betreut", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "привыкать", back: "sich gewöhnen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "привык", back: "hat gewöhnt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "ухаживать", back: "pflegen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "ухаживал", back: "hat gepflegt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "многолетний", back: "jahrelang", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "купец", back: "der Kaufmann", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "купцы", back: "die Kaufleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "купчиха", back: "die Kauffrau", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "купчихи", back: "die Kauffrauen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "эксперимент", back: "das Experiment", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "эксперименты", back: "die Experimente", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "финансовый", back: "finanziell", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "бизнесмены", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "бизнесмены", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "исключительно", back: "ausschließlich", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "ингредиент", back: "die Zutat", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "ингредиенты", back: "die Zutaten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "максимум", back: "höchstens", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "студия", back: "das Studio", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "студии", back: "die Studios", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "чтобы", back: "um … zu", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "максимально", back: "möglichst", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "речь", back: "die Rede", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "речи", back: "die Reden", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "компромисс", back: "der Kompromiss", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "компромиссы", back: "die Kompromisse", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "кондиционер", back: "die Klimaanlage", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "кондиционеры", back: "die Klimaanlagen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "программное обеспечение", back: "die Software", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "программное обеспечение (мн.ч. редко)", back: "die Softwares", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "возвращаться", back: "wiederkommen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "вернулся", back: "ist wiedergekommen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "усилие", back: "die Mühe", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "усилия", back: "die Mühen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "зубная паста", back: "die Zahncreme", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "зубные пасты", back: "die Zahncremes", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "моющее средство", back: "das Waschmittel", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "щётка", back: "die Bürste", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "щётки", back: "die Bürsten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "приветствовать", back: "begrüßen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "поприветствовал", back: "hat begrüßt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "прощаться", back: "sich verabschieden", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "попрощался", back: "hat verabschiedet", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "роль", back: "die Rolle", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "роли", back: "die Rollen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "претензия, требование", back: "der Anspruch", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "претензии, требования", back: "die Ansprüche", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "подтверждать", back: "bestätigen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "подтвердил", back: "hat bestätigt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "копия", back: "die Kopie", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "копии", back: "die Kopien", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "повреждать", back: "beschädigen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "повредил", back: "hat beschädigt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "раздражающий", back: "ärgerlich", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "инструкция по эксплуатации", back: "die Bedienungsanleitung", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "инструкции по эксплуатации", back: "die Bedienungsanleitungen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "обменивать", back: "umtauschen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "обменял", back: "hat umgetauscht", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "однако", back: "jedoch", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "уже", back: "bereits", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "требовать", back: "fordern", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "потребовал", back: "hat gefordert", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "разочаровывать", back: "enttäuschen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "разочаровал", back: "hat enttäuscht", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "призывать, приглашать", back: "auffordern", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "пригласил, призвал", back: "hat aufgefordert", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "предприятие, бизнес", back: "der Betrieb", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "предприятия", back: "die Betriebe", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "фирма", back: "die Firma", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "фирмы", back: "die Firmen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "производство", back: "die Produktion", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "производства", back: "die Produktionen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "торговля", back: "der Handel", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "риск", back: "das Risiko", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "риски", back: "die Risiken", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "бизнесмены", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "бизнесмены", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "купец", back: "der Kaufmann", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "купцы", back: "die Kaufleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "купчиха", back: "die Kauffrau", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "купчихи", back: "die Kauffrauen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "основывать", back: "gründen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "основал", back: "hat gegründet", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "суд, блюдо", back: "das Gericht", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "суды, блюда", back: "die Gerichte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "процесс", back: "der Prozess", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "процессы", back: "die Prozesse", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "гореть", back: "brennen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "горел", back: "hat gebrannt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "шум", back: "der Lärm", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "адвокат (муж.)", back: "der Rechtsanwalt", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "адвокаты", back: "die Rechtsanwälte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "адвокат (жен.)", back: "die Rechtsanwältin", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "адвокаты", back: "die Rechtsanwältinnen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "участок земли", back: "das Grundstück", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "участки земли", back: "die Grundstücke", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "подозревать", back: "verdächtigen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "подозревал", back: "hat verdächtigt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "мир", back: "der Frieden", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "реальность", back: "die Wirklichkeit", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "реальности", back: "die Wirklichkeiten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "газон", back: "der Rasen", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "федеральная земля", back: "das Bundesland", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "федеральные земли", back: "die Bundesländer", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "друг друга", back: "-einander", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "юрист, адвокат", back: "der Anwalt", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "юристы, адвокаты", back: "die Anwälte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "юрист (жен.), адвокат", back: "die Anwältin", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "юристы (жен.), адвокаты", back: "die Anwältinnen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "либо ... либо", back: "entweder ... oder", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "центральный", back: "zentral", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "обязанность", back: "die Pflicht", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "обязанности", back: "die Pflichten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "собственность", back: "das Eigentum", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "собственники", back: "die Eigentümer", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "кричать", back: "schreien", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "кричал", back: "hat geschrien", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "вместе", back: "miteinander", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "ластик", back: "der Radiergummi", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "ластики", back: "die Radiergummis", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "карандаш", back: "der Bleistift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "карандаши", back: "die Bleistifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "цветной карандаш", back: "der Farbstift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "цветные карандаши", back: "die Farbstifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "обнаруживать", back: "entdecken", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "обнаружил", back: "hat entdeckt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "сердитый", back: "wütend", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "пазл", back: "das Puzzle", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "пазлы", back: "die Puzzles", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "запрет", back: "das Verbot", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "запреты", back: "die Verbote", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "только, лишь", back: "bloß", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "сюда", back: "hierher", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "внимательный", back: "aufmerksam", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "договариваться", back: "abmachen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "договорился", back: "hat abgemacht", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "действительно", back: "tatsächlich", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "наглость", back: "die Frechheit", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "наглости", back: "die Frechheiten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "из-за меня, ради меня", back: "meinetwegen", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "начинаться, касаться", back: "angehen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "начался, коснулся", back: "ist angegangen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "лифт", back: "der Lift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "лифты", back: "die Lifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "терраса", back: "die Terrasse", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "террасы", back: "die Terrassen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "какой-то", back: "irgend-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "центр города", back: "die Innenstadt", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "центры городов", back: "die Innenstädte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "поперечная улица", back: "die Querstraße", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "поперечные улицы", back: "die Querstraßen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "существенный", back: "wesentlich", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "альтернатива", back: "die Alternative", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "альтернативы", back: "die Alternativen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "край", back: "der Rand", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "края", back: "die Ränder", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "ссылка", back: "der Link", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "ссылки", back: "die Links", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "где", back: "wo(r)-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "отсутствовать", back: "fehlen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "отсутствовал", back: "hat gefehlt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "государство", back: "der Staat", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "государства", back: "die Staaten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "восточный", back: "Ost-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "западный", back: "West-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "стена", back: "die Mauer", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "стены", back: "die Mauern", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "правительство", back: "die Regierung", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "правительства", back: "die Regierungen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "царить, господствовать", back: "herrschen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "царил, господствовал", back: "hat geherrscht", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "ступень", back: "die Stufe", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "ступени", back: "die Stufen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "посередине", back: "mitten", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "угловатый", back: "eckig", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "северный", back: "nördlich", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "земля", back: "die Erde", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "земли", back: "die Erden", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "шанс", back: "die Chance", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "шансы", back: "die Chancen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "увеличивать", back: "vergrößern", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "увеличил", back: "hat vergrößert", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "давно", back: "längst", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "несмотря на", back: "trotz", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "строительство", back: "der Bau", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "строительства", back: "die Bauten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "разрешение", back: "die Genehmigung", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "разрешения", back: "die Genehmigungen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "туризм", back: "der Tourismus", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "одинаковый", back: "gleich-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "здание", back: "das Gebäude", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "крыша", back: "das Dach", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "крыши", back: "die Dächer", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "дом", back: "das Haus", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "дома", back: "die Häuser", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "стена", back: "die Mauer", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "стены", back: "die Mauern", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "участок", back: "das Grundstück", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "участки", back: "die Grundstücke", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "лестница", back: "die Treppe", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "лестницы", back: "die Treppen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "ступень", back: "die Stufe", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "ступени", back: "die Stufen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "дверь", back: "die Tür", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "двери", back: "die Türen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "окно", back: "das Fenster", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "подвал", back: "der Keller", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "лифт", back: "der Lift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "лифты", back: "die Lifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "терраса", back: "die Terrasse", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "террасы", back: "die Terrassen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "сад", back: "der Garten", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "сады", back: "die Gärten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "балкон", back: "der Balkon", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "балконы", back: "die Balkone", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "газон", back: "der Rasen", lesson: "B1.7" }	
  ],
 romanian:[
{ front: "eu", back: "ich", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "a se numi", back: "heißen", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "a se fi numit", back: "haben geheißen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "numele", back: "der Name", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "numele", back: "die Namen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "a veni", back: "kommen", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "a venit", back: "sein gekommen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "Germania", back: "das Deutschland", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "a vorbi", back: "sprechen", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "a vorbit", back: "haben gesprochen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "limba germană", back: "das Deutsch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "și", back: "und", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "puțin", back: "ein bisschen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "bună ziua", back: "guten Tag", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "salut", back: "hallo", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "la revedere", back: "auf Wiedersehen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "pa", back: "tschüs", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "domnul", back: "der Herr", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "domnii", back: "die Herren", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "copil", back: "das Kind", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "copiii", back: "die Kinder", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "bună seara", back: "guten Abend", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "doamna", back: "die Dame", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "doamne", back: "die Damen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "bun venit", back: "willkommen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "la", back: "bei", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "muzica", back: "die Musik", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "internațional", back: "international", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "bună dimineața", back: "guten Morgen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "femeia", back: "die Frau", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "femeile", back: "die Frauen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "a mulțumi", back: "danken", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "a mulțumit", back: "haben gedankt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "noapte bună", back: "gute Nacht", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "tata", back: "der Papa", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "tații", back: "die Papas", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "a fi", back: "sein", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "a fost", back: "gewesen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "scuza", back: "die Entschuldigung", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "scuze", back: "die Entschuldigungen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "cum", back: "wie", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "ea/ei", back: "sie", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "cine", back: "wer", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "da", back: "ja", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "nu", back: "nein", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "de unde", back: "woher", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "din", back: "aus", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "tu", back: "du", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Austria", back: "Österreich", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Elveția", back: "die Schweiz", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "aha", back: "aha", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "grozav", back: "toll", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "interesant", back: "interessant", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "ce", back: "was", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "și", back: "auch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "limba", back: "die Sprache", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "limbile", back: "die Sprachen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "litera", back: "der Buchstabe", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "litere", back: "die Buchstaben", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "alfabetul", back: "das Alphabet", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "ce ați spus?", back: "wie bitte?", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "a spelta", back: "buchstabieren", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "a spus cu litere", back: "haben buchstabiert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "vă rog", back: "bitte", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "firma", back: "die Firma", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "firme", back: "die Firmen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "mulțumesc mult", back: "vielen Dank", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "la revedere (la telefon)", back: "auf Wiederhören", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "adresa", back: "die Adresse", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "adrese", back: "die Adressen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "carte de vizită", back: "die Visitenkarte", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "cărți de vizită", back: "die Visitenkarten", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "prenumele", back: "der Vorname", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "prenume", back: "die Vornamen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "numele de familie", back: "der Familienname", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "nume de familie", back: "die Familiennamen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "strada", back: "die Straße", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "străzi", back: "die Straßen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "oraș", back: "die Stadt", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "orașe", back: "die Städte", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "țară", back: "das Land", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "țări", back: "die Länder", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "e-mail", back: "die E-Mail", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "e-mailuri", back: "die E-Mails", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "telefon", back: "das Telefon", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "telefoane", back: "die Telefone", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "formular", back: "das Formular", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "formulare", back: "die Formulare", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "curs", back: "der Kurs", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "cursuri", back: "die Kurse", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "limbă străină", back: "die Fremdsprache", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "limbi străine", back: "die Fremdsprachen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "înregistrare", back: "die Anmeldung", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "înregistrări", back: "die Anmeldungen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "cod poștal", back: "die Postleitzahl", lesson: "A1.1" },	{ front: "coduri poștale", back: "die Postleitzahlen", lesson: "A1.1" },
{ front: "învățați cuvinte", back: "lernen Sie Wörter", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "turcă", back: "türkisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "germană", back: "deutsch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Polonia", back: "Polen", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "poloneză", back: "polnisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Turcia", back: "die Türkei", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Spania", back: "Spanien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Ungaria", back: "Ungarn", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Germania", back: "Deutschland", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Austria", back: "Österreich", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "turcesc", back: "türkisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "spaniol", back: "spanisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "maghiar", back: "ungarisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "german", back: "deutsch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Elveția", back: "die Schweiz", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "România", back: "Rumänien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Siria", back: "Syrien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Bulgaria", back: "Bulgarien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Italia", back: "Italien", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "Grecia", back: "Griechenland", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "română", back: "rumänisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "arabă", back: "arabisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "bulgară", back: "bulgarisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "italiană", back: "italienisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "greacă", back: "griechisch", lesson: "A1.1" },	
{ front: "a învăța", back: "lernen", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "a învățat", back: "haben gelernt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "parc", back: "der Park", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "parcuri", back: "die Parks", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "pauză", back: "die Pause", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "pauze", back: "die Pausen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "familie", back: "die Familie", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "familii", back: "die Familien", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "tată", back: "der Vater", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "tați", back: "die Väter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "bunici", back: "die Großeltern", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "mamă", back: "die Mutter", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "mame", back: "die Mütter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "părinți", back: "die Eltern", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "fratele", back: "der Bruder", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "frații", back: "die Brüder", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "frații (surori și frați)", back: "die Geschwister", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "anul", back: "das Jahr", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "anii", back: "die Jahre", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "a trăi", back: "leben", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "a trăit", back: "haben gelebt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "în", back: "in", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "bun", back: "gut", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "super", back: "super", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "ei bine", back: "na ja", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "ah", back: "ach", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "așa", back: "so", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "foarte", back: "sehr", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "nepot (băiat)", back: "der Enkel", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "nepoții (băieți)", back: "die Enkel", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "nepoată (fată)", back: "die Enkelin", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "nepoatele (fete)", back: "die Enkelinnen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "fiica", back: "die Tochter", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "fiicele", back: "die Töchter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "fiul", back: "der Sohn", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "fiii", back: "die Söhne", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "sora", back: "die Schwester", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "surorile", back: "die Schwestern", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "bunica", back: "die Oma", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "bunicile", back: "die Omas", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "bărbat", back: "der Mann", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "bărbații", back: "die Männer", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "bunicul", back: "der Opa", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "bunicii", back: "die Opas", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "al tău / a ta", back: "dein", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "al meu / a mea", back: "mein", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "al ei / a ei", back: "ihr", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "soț", back: "der Ehemann", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "soții", back: "die Ehemänner", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "soție", back: "die Ehefrau", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "soțiile", back: "die Ehefrauen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "greșit", back: "falsch", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "ea / ei", back: "sie", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "împreună", back: "zusammen", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "ei / ele", back: "sie", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "divorțat", back: "geschieden", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "el", back: "er", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "a locui", back: "wohnen", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "a locuit", back: "haben gewohnt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "acum", back: "jetzt", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "voi", back: "ihr", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "noi", back: "wir", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "număr", back: "die Zahl", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "numere", back: "die Zahlen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "unde", back: "wo", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "născut", back: "geboren", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "număr", back: "die Nummer", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "numere", back: "die Nummern", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "căsătorit", back: "verheiratet", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "a avea", back: "haben", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "a avut", back: "haben gehabt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "locul nașterii", back: "der Geburtsort", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "locurile nașterii", back: "die Geburtsorte", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "locul de domiciliu", back: "der Wohnort", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "locurile de domiciliu", back: "die Wohnorte", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "stare civilă", back: "der Familienstand", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "necăsătorit", back: "ledig", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "văduv", back: "verwitwet", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "vârsta", back: "das Alter", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "vârste", back: "die Alter", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "nord", back: "der Norden", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "est", back: "der Osten", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "sud", back: "der Süden", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "vest", back: "der Westen", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "capitală", back: "die Hauptstadt", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "capitale", back: "die Hauptstädte", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "sud", back: "Süd", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "nord", back: "Nord", lesson: "A1.2" },	
{ front: "profesor (bărbat)", back: "der Lehrer", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "profesorii", back: "die Lehrer", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "profesoară", back: "die Lehrerin", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "profesoarele", back: "die Lehrerinnen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "german (bărbat)", back: "der Deutsche", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "germanii", back: "die Deutschen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "germancă", back: "die Deutsche", lesson: "A1.2" },	{ front: "germancele", back: "die Deutschen", lesson: "A1.2" },
{ front: "banana", back: "die Banane", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "bananele", back: "die Bananen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "unt", back: "die Butter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "ou", back: "das Ei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "ouă", back: "die Eier", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "făină", back: "das Mehl", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "lapte", back: "die Milch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "zahăr", back: "der Zucker", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "clătită", back: "der Pfannkuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "clătitele", back: "die Pfannkuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "ciocolată", back: "die Schokolade", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "a avea nevoie", back: "brauchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "a avut nevoie", back: "haben gebraucht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a cumpăra", back: "kaufen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "a cumpărat", back: "haben gekauft", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "foame", back: "der Hunger", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "euro", back: "der Euro", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "carne", back: "das Fleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "bere", back: "das Bier", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "brânză", back: "der Käse", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "sare", back: "das Salz", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "ceai", back: "der Tee", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "ceaiuri", back: "die Tees", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "pâine", back: "das Brot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pâini", back: "die Brote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "vin", back: "der Wein", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "vinuri", back: "die Weine", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "apă minerală", back: "das Mineralwasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "orez", back: "der Reis", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "pește", back: "der Fisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pești", back: "die Fische", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "un/o", back: "ein", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "niciun/ă", back: "kein", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "măr", back: "der Apfel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "mere", back: "die Äpfel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "portocală", back: "die Orange", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "portocale", back: "die Orangen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "prăjitură", back: "der Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "prăjituri", back: "die Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cafea", back: "der Kaffee", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cafele", back: "die Kaffees", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "suc", back: "der Saft", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "sucuri", back: "die Säfte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "chiflă", back: "das Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "chifle", back: "die Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cârnat mic", back: "das Würstchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cârnați mici", back: "die Würstchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "pară", back: "die Birne", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pere", back: "die Birnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "roșie", back: "die Tomate", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "roșii", back: "die Tomaten", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cartof", back: "die Kartoffel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cartofi", back: "die Kartoffeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "iaurt", back: "der Joghurt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "iaurturi", back: "die Joghurts", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "ceapă", back: "die Zwiebel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cepe", back: "die Zwiebeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "raft", back: "das Regal", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "rafturi", back: "die Regale", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "preț", back: "der Preis", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "prețuri", back: "die Preise", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cent", back: "der Cent", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "prospect", back: "der Prospekt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "prospecte", back: "die Prospekte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "ofertă specială", back: "das Sonderangebot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "oferte speciale", back: "die Sonderangebote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "aliment", back: "das Lebensmittel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "alimente", back: "die Lebensmittel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cât", back: "wie viel", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "a costa", back: "kosten", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "a costat", back: "haben gekostet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "kilogram", back: "das Kilo(gramm)", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "gram", back: "das Gramm", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "jumătate de kilogram", back: "das Pfund", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "litru", back: "der Liter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "sticlă", back: "die Flasche", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "sticle", back: "die Flaschen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "conservă", back: "die Dose", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "conserve", back: "die Dosen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "frișcă", back: "die Sahne", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "cârnat", back: "die Wurst", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cârnați", back: "die Würste", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "carne tocată", back: "das Hackfleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "vânzător", back: "der Verkäufer", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "vânzători", back: "die Verkäufer", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "vânzătoare", back: "die Verkäuferin", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "vânzătoare", back: "die Verkäuferinnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "client", back: "der Kunde", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "clienți", back: "die Kunden", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "clientă", back: "die Kundin", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cliente", back: "die Kundinnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "încă", back: "noch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "tot", back: "all", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "a dori", back: "möchten", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "a dorit", back: "haben gewünscht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a găsi", back: "finden", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "a găsit", back: "haben gefunden", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "magazin", back: "der Laden", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "magazine", back: "die Läden", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "fructe", back: "das Obst", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "legume", back: "das Gemüse", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "legume", back: "die Gemüse", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "brutărie", back: "die Bäckerei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "brutării", back: "die Bäckereien", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "apă", back: "das Wasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "piper", back: "der Pfeffer", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "ciocolată", back: "die Schokolade", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "banană", back: "die Banane", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "banane", back: "die Bananen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "unt", back: "die Butter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "ou", back: "das Ei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "ouă", back: "die Eier", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "lapte", back: "die Milch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "pâine", back: "das Brot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pâini", back: "die Brote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "pește", back: "der Fisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pești", back: "die Fische", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "carne", back: "das Fleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "brânză", back: "der Käse", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "măr", back: "der Apfel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "mere", back: "die Äpfel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "pară", back: "die Birne", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pere", back: "die Birnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "chiflă", back: "das Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "chifle", back: "die Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "prăjitură", back: "der Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "prăjituri", back: "die Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "portocală", back: "die Orange", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "portocale", back: "die Orangen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "suc", back: "der Saft", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "sucuri", back: "die Säfte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "iaurt", back: "der/ das Joghurt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "iaurturi", back: "die Joghurts", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cartof", back: "die Kartoffel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cartofi", back: "die Kartoffeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "ceapă", back: "die Zwiebel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cepe", back: "die Zwiebeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "roșie", back: "die Tomate", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "roșii", back: "die Tomaten", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "apă minerală", back: "das Mineralwasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "orez", back: "der Reis", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "pește", back: "der Fisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pești", back: "die Fische", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "un", back: "ein", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "niciun", back: "kein", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "măr", back: "der Apfel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "mere", back: "die Äpfel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "portocală", back: "die Orange", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "portocale", back: "die Orangen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "prăjitură", back: "der Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "prăjituri", back: "die Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cafea", back: "der Kaffee", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cafele", back: "die Kaffees", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "suc", back: "der Saft", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "sucuri", back: "die Säfte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "chiflă", back: "das Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "chifle", back: "die Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cârnat mic", back: "das Würstchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cârnați mici", back: "die Würstchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "pară", back: "die Birne", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pere", back: "die Birnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "roșie", back: "die Tomate", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "roșii", back: "die Tomaten", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cartof", back: "die Kartoffel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cartofi", back: "die Kartoffeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "iaurt", back: "der Joghurt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "iaurturi", back: "die Joghurts", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "ceapă", back: "die Zwiebel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cepe", back: "die Zwiebeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "raft", back: "das Regal", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "rafturi", back: "die Regale", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "preț", back: "der Preis", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "prețuri", back: "die Preise", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cent", back: "der Cent", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "prospect", back: "der Prospekt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "prospecte", back: "die Prospekte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "ofertă specială", back: "das Sonderangebot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "oferte speciale", back: "die Sonderangebote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "alimente", back: "das Lebensmittel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "alimente", back: "die Lebensmittel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cât", back: "wie viel", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "a costa", back: "kosten", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "a costat", back: "haben gekostet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "kilogram", back: "das Kilo(gramm)", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "gram", back: "das Gramm", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "jumătate de kilogram", back: "das Pfund", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "litru", back: "der Liter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "sticlă", back: "die Flasche", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "sticle", back: "die Flaschen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cutie", back: "die Dose", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cutii", back: "die Dosen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "frișcă", back: "die Sahne", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "cârnat", back: "die Wurst", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cârnați", back: "die Würste", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "carne tocată", back: "das Hackfleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "vânzător", back: "der Verkäufer", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "vânzători", back: "die Verkäufer", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "vânzătoare", back: "die Verkäuferin", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "vânzătoare", back: "die Verkäuferinnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "client", back: "der Kunde", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "clienți", back: "die Kunden", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "clientă", back: "die Kundin", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cliente", back: "die Kundinnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "încă", back: "noch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "tot", back: "all", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "a dori", back: "möchten", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "a dorit", back: "haben gewünscht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a găsi", back: "finden", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "a găsit", back: "haben gefunden", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "magazin", back: "der Laden", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "magazine", back: "die Läden", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "fructe", back: "das Obst", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "legume", back: "das Gemüse", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "legume", back: "die Gemüse", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "brutărie", back: "die Bäckerei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "brutării", back: "die Bäckereien", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "apă", back: "das Wasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "piper", back: "der Pfeffer", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "ciocolată", back: "die Schokolade", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "banană", back: "die Banane", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "banane", back: "die Bananen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "unt", back: "die Butter", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "ou", back: "das Ei", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "ouă", back: "die Eier", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "lapte", back: "die Milch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "pâine", back: "das Brot", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pâini", back: "die Brote", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "pește", back: "der Fisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pești", back: "die Fische", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "carne", back: "das Fleisch", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "brânză", back: "der Käse", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "măr", back: "der Apfel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "mere", back: "die Äpfel", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "pară", back: "die Birne", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "pere", back: "die Birnen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "chiflă", back: "das Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "chifle", back: "die Brötchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "prăjitură", back: "der Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "prăjituri", back: "die Kuchen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "portocală", back: "die Orange", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "portocale", back: "die Orangen", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "suc", back: "der Saft", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "sucuri", back: "die Säfte", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "iaurt", back: "der/ das Joghurt", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "iaurturi", back: "die Joghurts", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "cartof", back: "die Kartoffel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cartofi", back: "die Kartoffeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "ceapă", back: "die Zwiebel", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "cepe", back: "die Zwiebeln", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "roșie", back: "die Tomate", lesson: "A1.3" },	{ front: "roșii", back: "die Tomaten", lesson: "A1.3" },
{ front: "apă minerală", back: "das Mineralwasser", lesson: "A1.3" },	
{ front: "locuință", back: "die Wohnung", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "locuințe", back: "die Wohnungen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "lampă", back: "die Lampe", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "lămpi", back: "die Lampen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "cameră", back: "das Zimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "camere", back: "die Zimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "bucătărie", back: "die Küche", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "bucătării", back: "die Küchen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "baie", back: "das Bad", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "băi", back: "die Bäder", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "bătrân / vechi", back: "alt", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "nou", back: "neu", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "mare", back: "groß", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "mic", back: "klein", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "luminos", back: "hell", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "întunecat", back: "dunkel", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "scump", back: "teuer", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "ieftin", back: "billig", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "frumos", back: "schön", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "urât", back: "hässlich", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "a cunoaște", back: "kennen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "a cunoscut", back: "haben gekannt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "hol", back: "der Flur", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "holuri", back: "die Flure", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "toaletă", back: "die Toilette", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "toalete", back: "die Toiletten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "balcon", back: "der Balkon", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "balcoane", back: "die Balkone", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "sufragerie", back: "das Wohnzimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "sufragerii", back: "die Wohnzimmer", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "-", back: "der, das, die", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "casă", back: "das Haus", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "case", back: "die Häuser", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "aici", back: "hier", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "acolo", back: "dort", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "dar / însă", back: "aber", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "nu", back: "nicht", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "lună", back: "der Monat", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "luni", back: "die Monate", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "îngust", back: "schmal", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "corect", back: "richtig", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "lat", back: "breit", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "dulap", back: "der Schrank", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "dulapuri", back: "die Schränke", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "frigider", back: "der Kühlschrank", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "frigidere", back: "die Kühlschränke", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "canapea", back: "das Sofa", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "canapele", back: "die Sofas", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "masă", back: "der Tisch", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "mese", back: "die Tische", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "scaun", back: "der Stuhl", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "scaune", back: "die Stühle", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "pat", back: "das Bett", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "paturi", back: "die Betten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "televizor", back: "der Fernseher", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "televizoare", back: "die Fernseher", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "duș", back: "die Dusche", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "dușuri", back: "die Duschen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "aragaz", back: "der Herd", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "aragaze", back: "die Herde", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "cadă de baie", back: "die Badewanne", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "căzi de baie", back: "die Badewannen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "covor", back: "der Teppich", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "covoare", back: "die Teppiche", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "fotoliu", back: "der Sessel", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "fotolii", back: "die Sessel", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "mobilă", back: "die Möbel", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "aparat", back: "das Gerät", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "aparate", back: "die Geräte", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "a plăcea", back: "gefallen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "a plăcut", back: "haben gefallen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "culoare", back: "die Farbe", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "culori", back: "die Farben", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "a găsi", back: "finden", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "a găsit", back: "haben gefunden", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "întreg", back: "ganz", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "modern", back: "modern", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "negru", back: "schwarz", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "gri", back: "grau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "alb", back: "weiß", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "verde", back: "grün", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "maro", back: "braun", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "albastru", back: "blau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "roșu", back: "rot", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "galben", back: "gelb", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "deschis (culoare)", back: "hell-", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "închis (culoare)", back: "dunkel-", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "centimetru", back: "der Zentimeter", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "centimetri", back: "die Zentimeter", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "dată", back: "mal", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "telefon mobil", back: "das Handy", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "telefoane mobile", back: "die Handys", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "muncă", back: "die Arbeit", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "anunț", back: "die Anzeige", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "anunțuri", back: "die Anzeigen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "drăguț", back: "nett", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "cuplu căsătorit", back: "das Ehepaar", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "cupluri căsătorite", back: "die Ehepaare", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "a căuta", back: "suchen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "a căutat", back: "haben gesucht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "grădină", back: "der Garten", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "grădini", back: "die Gärten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "a închiria", back: "vermieten", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "a închiriat", back: "haben vermietet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "apartament", back: "das Apartment", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "apartamente", back: "die Apartments", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "cameră / spațiu", back: "der Raum", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "camere / spații", back: "die Räume", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "etaj", back: "der Stock", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "aproximativ", back: "circa", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "privat", back: "privat", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "maro", back: "braun", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "albastru", back: "blau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "roșu", back: "rot", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "galben", back: "gelb", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "culori", back: "Farben", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "de (de la)", back: "ab", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "imediat", back: "sofort", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "maxim", back: "maximal", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "apel telefonic", back: "der Anruf", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "apeluri telefonice", back: "die Anrufe", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "mobilat", back: "möbliert", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "televizor", back: "das TV", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "televizoare", back: "die TVs", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "garaj", back: "die Garage", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "garaje", back: "die Garagen", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "metru pătrat", back: "der Quadratmeter", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "metri pătrați", back: "die Quadratmeter", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "numai", back: "nur", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "chirie", back: "die Miete", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "chirii", back: "die Mieten", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "a plăti", back: "bezahlen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "a plătit", back: "haben bezahlt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a vinde", back: "verkaufen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "a vândut", back: "haben verkauft", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "ceva", back: "etwas", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "calculator", back: "der Computer", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "calculatoare", back: "die Computer", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "birou", back: "der Schreibtisch", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "birouri", back: "die Schreibtische", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "azi", back: "heute", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "care ...?", back: "welche …?", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "deci", back: "also", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "aproximativ", back: "ungefähr", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "metru", back: "der Meter", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "metri", back: "die Meter", lesson: "A1.4" },
{ front: "lung", back: "lang", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "exact", back: "genau", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "a vedea", back: "sehen", lesson: "A1.4" },	{ front: "a văzut", back: "haben gesehen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "înalt", back: "hoch", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "mâine", back: "morgen", lesson: "A1.4" },	
{ front: "a face", back: "machen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a făcut", back: "haben gemacht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "prezentare", back: "die Präsentation", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "prezentări", back: "die Präsentationen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "a lua micul dejun", back: "frühstücken", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a luat micul dejun", back: "haben gefrühstückt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a face cumpărături", back: "einkaufen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a făcut cumpărături", back: "haben eingekauft", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a auzi", back: "hören", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a auzit", back: "haben gehört", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a găti", back: "kochen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a gătit", back: "haben gekocht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a merge la plimbare", back: "spazieren gehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a mers la plimbare", back: "sein spaziert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a face curat", back: "aufräumen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a făcut curat", back: "haben aufgeräumt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a se scula", back: "aufstehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "s-a sculat", back: "sein aufgestanden", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a merge", back: "gehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a mers", back: "sein gegangen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "sau", back: "oder", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "obosit", back: "müde", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "a suna", back: "anrufen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a sunat", back: "haben angerufen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "devreme", back: "früh", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "supermarket", back: "der Supermarkt", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "supermarketuri", back: "die Supermärkte", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "a se uita la TV", back: "fernsehen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "s-a uitat la TV", back: "haben ferngesehen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "cu", back: "mit", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "a lucra", back: "arbeiten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a lucrat", back: "haben gearbeitet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "mult timp", back: "lange", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "a juca", back: "spielen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a jucat", back: "haben gespielt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a mânca", back: "essen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a mâncat", back: "haben gegessen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "cu plăcere", back: "gern", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "târziu", back: "spät", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "deja", back: "schon", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "abia", back: "erst", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "cartier", back: "das Viertel", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "cartiere", back: "die Viertel", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "înainte de", back: "vor", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "după", back: "nach", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "jumătate", back: "halb", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "ceas", back: "die Uhr", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "ceasuri", back: "die Uhren", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "scurt", back: "kurz", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "imediat", back: "gleich", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "curs intensiv", back: "der Intensivkurs", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "cursuri intensive", back: "die Intensivkurse", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "a începe", back: "anfangen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a început", back: "haben angefangen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "la", back: "am", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "luni", back: "der Montag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "luni (plural: zile de luni)", back: "die Montage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "vineri", back: "der Freitag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "vineri (plural: zile de vineri)", back: "die Freitage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "joi", back: "der Donnerstag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "joi (plural: zile de joi)", back: "die Donnerstage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "miercuri", back: "der Mittwoch", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "miercuri (plural)", back: "die Mittwoche", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "marți", back: "der Dienstag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "marți (plural)", back: "die Dienstage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "când", back: "wann", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "la (ora)", back: "um", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "a se termina", back: "enden", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "s-a terminat", back: "haben geendet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "de la ... până la ...", back: "von ... bis ...", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "petrecere", back: "die Party", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "petreceri", back: "die Partys", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "timp", back: "die Zeit", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "timpuri", back: "die Zeiten", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "fotbal", back: "der Fußball", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "sâmbătă", back: "der Samstag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "sâmbete", back: "die Samstage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "duminică", back: "der Sonntag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "duminici", back: "die Sonntage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "tema pentru acasă", back: "die Hausaufgabe", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "teme pentru acasă", back: "die Hausaufgaben", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "mamă", back: "die Mama", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "mame", back: "die Mamas", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "a dormi", back: "schlafen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a dormit", back: "haben geschlafen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "weekend", back: "das Wochenende", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "weekenduri", back: "die Wochenenden", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "următor", back: "nächst-", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "săptămână", back: "die Woche", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "săptămâni", back: "die Wochen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "prânz", back: "der Mittag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "prânzuri", back: "die Mittage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "dimineață", back: "der Morgen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "dimineți", back: "die Morgen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "seară", back: "der Abend", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "seri", back: "die Abende", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "după-amiază", back: "der Nachmittag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "după-amiezi", back: "die Nachmittage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "dimineața (timpul înainte de prânz)", back: "der Vormittag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "dimineți (plural)", back: "die Vormittage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "noapte", back: "die Nacht", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "nopți", back: "die Nächte", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "cinema", back: "das Kino", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "cinematografe", back: "die Kinos", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "sport", back: "der Sport", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "a bea", back: "trinken", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a băut", back: "haben getrunken", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "pizza", back: "die Pizza", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "pizze", back: "die Pizzen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "a chatui", back: "chatten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a chatuit", back: "haben gechattet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "deschis", back: "geöffnet", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "întâlnire / programare", back: "der Termin", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "întâlniri / programări", back: "die Termine", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "grădiniță", back: "der Kindergarten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "grădinițe", back: "die Kindergärten", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "magazin", back: "das Geschäft", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "magazine", back: "die Geschäfte", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "bibliotecă", back: "die Bibliothek", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "biblioteci", back: "die Bibliotheken", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "închis", back: "geschlossen", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "a deschide", back: "öffnen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a deschis", back: "haben geöffnet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a închide", back: "schließen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a închis", back: "haben geschlossen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "cabinet medical", back: "die Praxis", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "cabinete medicale", back: "die Praxen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "zi", back: "der Tag", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "zile", back: "die Tage", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "fiecare", back: "jed-", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "grădiniță (de copii mici)", back: "die Kita", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "grădinițe", back: "die Kitas", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "a aduce", back: "bringen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a adus", back: "haben gebracht", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a ridica / a lua", back: "abholen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a ridicat / a luat", back: "haben abgeholt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "mai mult", back: "mehr", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "exemplu", back: "das Beispiel", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "exemple", back: "die Beispiele", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "de exemplu", back: "zum Beispiel", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "din nou", back: "wieder", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "prieten", back: "der Freund", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "prieteni", back: "die Freunde", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "prietenă", back: "die Freundin", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "prietene", back: "die Freundinnen", lesson: "A1.5" },
{ front: "a întreba", back: "fragen", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a întrebat", back: "haben gefragt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a răspunde", back: "antworten", lesson: "A1.5" },	{ front: "a răspuns", back: "haben geantwortet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "total", back: "total", lesson: "A1.5" },	
{ front: "excursie", back: "der Ausflug", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "excursii", back: "die Ausflüge", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "mașină", back: "das Auto", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "mașini", back: "die Autos", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "a face drumeții", back: "wandern", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a făcut drumeții", back: "sein gewandert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "picnic", back: "das Picknick", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "picnicuri", back: "die Picknicks", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "chitară", back: "die Gitarre", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "chitare", back: "die Gitarren", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "a telefona", back: "telefonieren", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a telefonat", back: "haben telefoniert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "vreme", back: "das Wetter", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "soare", back: "die Sonne", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "a străluci", back: "scheinen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a strălucit", back: "haben geschienen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a ploua", back: "regnen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a plouat", back: "haben geregnet", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "mult", back: "viel-", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "nor", back: "die Wolke", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "nori", back: "die Wolken", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "a porni (a începe)", back: "los (losgehen)", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "a uita", back: "vergessen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a uitat", back: "haben vergessen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "sete", back: "der Durst", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "grad (temperatură)", back: "das Grad", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "cald", back: "warm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "vântos", back: "windig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "frig", back: "kalt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "a ninge", back: "schneien", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a nins", back: "haben geschneit", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "înnorat", back: "bewölkt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "prognoză meteo", back: "der Wetterbericht", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "prognoze meteo", back: "die Wetterberichte", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "mijloc", back: "die Mitte", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "peste tot", back: "überall", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "temperatură", back: "die Temperatur", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "temperaturi", back: "die Temperaturen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "a crește (temperatură)", back: "steigen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a crescut", back: "sein gestiegen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "însorit", back: "sonnig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "ușor", back: "leicht", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "a rămâne", back: "bleiben", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a rămas", back: "sein geblieben", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "ploaie", back: "der Regen", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "zăpadă", back: "der Schnee", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "plus", back: "plus", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "minus", back: "minus", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "radio", back: "das Radio", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "radiouri", back: "die Radios", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "internet", back: "das Internet", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "vară", back: "der Sommer", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "veri", back: "die Sommer", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "fierbinte", back: "heiß", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "primăvară", back: "der Frühling", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "primăveri", back: "die Frühlinge", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "toamnă", back: "der Herbst", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "toamne", back: "die Herbste", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "rău", back: "schlecht", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "iarnă", back: "der Winter", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "ierni", back: "die Winter", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "vânt", back: "der Wind", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "vânturi", back: "die Winde", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "plăcut", back: "angenehm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "meniu", back: "die Speisekarte", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "meniuri", back: "die Speisekarten", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "hamburger", back: "der Hamburger", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "hamburgeri", back: "die Hamburger", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "mâncare", back: "die Speise", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "mâncăruri", back: "die Speisen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "cartofi prăjiți", back: "die Pommes frites", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "porție", back: "die Portion", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "porții", back: "die Portionen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "ketchup", back: "der Ketchup", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "ketchup-uri", back: "die Ketchups", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "salată", back: "der Salat", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "salate", back: "die Salate", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "șuncă", back: "der Schinken", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "șunci", back: "die Schinken", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "băutură", back: "das Getränk", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "băuturi", back: "die Getränke", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "cola", back: "die Cola", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "cola-uri", back: "die Colas", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "totuși", back: "doch", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "mai degrabă", back: "lieber", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "a lua", back: "nehmen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a luat", back: "haben genommen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "de ce", back: "warum", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "câine", back: "der Hund", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "câini", back: "die Hunde", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "înghețată", back: "das Eis", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "a dansa", back: "tanzen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a dansat", back: "haben getanzt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a înota", back: "schwimmen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a înotat", back: "sein geschwommen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a întâlni", back: "treffen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a întâlnit", back: "haben getroffen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "bicicletă", back: "das Fahrrad", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "biciclete", back: "die Fahrräder", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "a conduce / a merge cu", back: "fahren", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a condus / a mers", back: "sein gefahren", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a face grătar", back: "grillen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a făcut grătar", back: "haben gegrillt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "timp liber", back: "die Freizeit", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "hobby", back: "das Hobby", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "hobby-uri", back: "die Hobbys", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "a citi", back: "lesen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a citit", back: "haben gelesen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "roman polițist", back: "der Krimi", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "romane polițiste", back: "die Krimis", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "preferat", back: "Lieblings-", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "film", back: "der Film", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "filme", back: "die Filme", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "important", back: "wichtig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "grătar", back: "der Grill", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "grătare", back: "die Grills", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "a aduna", back: "sammeln", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a adunat", back: "haben gesammelt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "meserie / profesie", back: "der Beruf", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "meserii / profesii", back: "die Berufe", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "fotografie", back: "das Foto", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "fotografii", back: "die Fotos", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "în mod special", back: "besonders", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "a fotografia", back: "fotografieren", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a fotografiat", back: "haben fotografiert", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "distracție", back: "der Spaß", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "smartphone", back: "das Smartphone", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "smartphone-uri", back: "die Smartphones", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "prost", back: "dumm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "des", back: "oft", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "a însemna / a gândi", back: "meinen", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "a însemnat / a gândit", back: "haben gemeint", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "zar", back: "der Würfel", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "zaruri", back: "die Würfel", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "joc", back: "das Spiel", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "jocuri", back: "die Spiele", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "din păcate", back: "leider", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "problem", back: "das Problem", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "probleme", back: "die Probleme", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "mereu", back: "immer", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "poate", back: "vielleicht", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "simplu", back: "einfach", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "rapid", back: "schnell", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "soare", back: "die Sonne", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "sori", back: "die Sonnen", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "Este însorit.", back: "Es ist sonnig.", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "ploaie", back: "der Regen", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "Plouă.", back: "Es regnet.", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "nor", back: "die Wolke", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "nori", back: "die Wolken", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "Este înnorat.", back: "es ist bewölkt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "zăpadă", back: "der Schnee", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "Ninge.", back: "es schneit", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "vânt", back: "der Wind", lesson: "A1.6" },	{ front: "vânturi", back: "die Winde", lesson: "A1.6" },
{ front: "Este vântos.", back: "es ist windig", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "Este frig.", back: "es ist kalt", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "Este cald.", back: "es ist warm", lesson: "A1.6" },	
{ front: "prima", back: "prima", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "echipa", back: "das Team", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "echipe", back: "die Teams", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a trezi", back: "wecken", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a trezit", back: "haben geweckt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "micul dejun", back: "das Frühstück", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "mic dejunuri", back: "die Frühstücke", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "gata", back: "fertig", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "a pleca, a începe", back: "los sein", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "a scrie", back: "schreiben", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a scris", back: "haben geschrieben", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "matematica", back: "die Mathematik", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "test", back: "der Test", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "teste", back: "die Tests", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "punctual", back: "pünktlich", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "în niciun/cert caz", back: "auf keinen/jeden Fall", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "a avea gust", back: "schmecken", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a avut gust", back: "haben geschmeckt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "spre casă", back: "nach Hause", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "școală", back: "die Schule", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "școli", back: "die Schulen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a putea", back: "können", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a putut", back: "haben gekonnt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "bolnav", back: "krank", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "doctor", back: "der Arzt", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "doctori", back: "die Ärzte", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "doctoriță", back: "die Ärztin", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "doctorițe", back: "die Ärztinnen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a coace", back: "backen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a copt", back: "haben gebacken", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a cânta", back: "singen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a cântat", back: "haben gesungen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a călări", back: "reiten", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a călărit", back: "sein geritten", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "pian", back: "das Klavier", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "piane", back: "die Klaviere", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a picta", back: "malen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a pictat", back: "haben gemalt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "schi", back: "der Ski", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "schiuri", back: "die Skier", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "tenis (a juca)", back: "das Tennis (spielen)", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "a vrea", back: "wollen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a vrut", back: "haben gewollt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "în sfârșit", back: "endlich", lesson: "A1.7" },	
{ front: "cântec", back: "das Lied", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "cântece", back: "die Lieder", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a exersa", back: "üben", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a exersat", back: "haben geübt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "text", back: "der Text", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "texte", back: "die Texte", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "exercițiu", back: "die Übung", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "exerciții", back: "die Übungen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "scrisoare", back: "der Brief", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "scrisori", back: "die Briefe", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "dictare", back: "das Diktat", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "dictări", back: "die Diktate", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "carte", back: "das Buch", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "cărți", back: "die Bücher", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a cânta la chitară", back: "Gitarre spielen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a cântat la chitară", back: "haben Gitarre gespielt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a merge cu bicicleta", back: "Fahrrad fahren", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a mers cu bicicleta", back: "sein Fahrrad gefahren", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a întâlni prieteni", back: "Freunde treffen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a întâlnit prieteni", back: "haben getroffen", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a merge cu schiurile", back: "Ski fahren", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a mers cu schiurile", back: "sein Ski gefahren", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "a juca tenis", back: "Tennis spielen", lesson: "A1.7" },	{ front: "a jucat tenis", back: "haben Tennis gespielt", lesson: "A1.7" },
{ front: "poveste", back: "die Geschichte", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "povești", back: "die Geschichten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "spital", back: "das Krankenhaus", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "spitale", back: "die Krankenhäuser", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "interviu", back: "das Interview", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "interviuri", back: "die Interviews", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "ziar", back: "die Zeitung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "ziare", back: "die Zeitungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "televiziune", back: "das Fernsehen", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "formare profesională", back: "die Ausbildung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "formări profesionale", back: "die Ausbildungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "șef", back: "der Chef", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "șefi", back: "die Chefs", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "șefă", back: "die Chefin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "șefe", back: "die Chefinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "pacient", back: "der Patient", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "pacienți", back: "die Patienten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "pacientă", back: "die Patientin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "paciente", back: "die Patientinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "administrator (bloc)", back: "der Hausmeister", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "administratori (bloc)", back: "die Hausmeister", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "administrator (feminin)", back: "die Hausmeisterin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "administratoare (feminin)", back: "die Hausmeisterinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "jurnalist", back: "der Journalist", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "jurnaliști", back: "die Journalisten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "jurnalistă", back: "die Journalistin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "jurnaliste", back: "die Journalistinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "temă", back: "das Thema", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "teme", back: "die Themen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "mecatronist", back: "der Mechatroniker", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "mecatroniști", back: "die Mechatroniker", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "mecatronistă", back: "die Mechatronikerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "mecatroniște", back: "die Mechatronikerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "bărbat de casă", back: "der Hausmann", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "bărbați de casă", back: "die Hausmänner", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "femeie de casă", back: "die Hausfrau", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "femei de casă", back: "die Hausfrauen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "polițist", back: "der Polizist", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "polițiști", back: "die Polizisten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "polițistă", back: "die Polizistin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "polițiste", back: "die Polizistinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "îngrijitor (spital)", back: "der Krankenpfleger", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "asistente medicale", back: "die Krankenschwestern", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "asistentă medicală", back: "die Krankenschwester", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "asistente medicale", back: "die Krankenschwestern", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "profesional", back: "beruflich", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "elev", back: "der Schüler", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "elevi", back: "die Schüler", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "elevă", back: "die Schülerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "eleve", back: "die Schülerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "student", back: "der Student", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "studente", back: "die Studentinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "studentă", back: "die Studentin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "studente", back: "die Studentinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "a studia", back: "studieren", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "a studiat", back: "haben studiert", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "job", back: "der Job", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "joburi", back: "die Jobs", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "loc de muncă", back: "die Stelle", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "locuri de muncă", back: "die Stellen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "independent", back: "selbstständig", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "angajat", back: "berufstätig", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "șomer", back: "arbeitslos", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "momentan", back: "zurzeit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "șofer de taxi", back: "der Taxifahrer", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "șoferi de taxi", back: "die Taxifahrer", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "șoferiță de taxi", back: "die Taxifahrerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "șoferițe de taxi", back: "die Taxifahrerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "a dura", back: "dauern", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "a durat", back: "haben gedauert", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "de când", back: "seit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "cerere de angajare", back: "die Bewerbung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "cereri de angajare", back: "die Bewerbungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "stagiu", back: "das Praktikum", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "stagii", back: "die Praktika", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "departament", back: "die Abteilung", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "departamente", back: "die Abteilungen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "conducător", back: "der Leiter", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "conducători", back: "die Leiter", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "conducătoare", back: "die Leiterin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "conducătoare", back: "die Leiterinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "onorat", back: "geehrt", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "economie", back: "die Wirtschaft", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "diplomă", back: "das Diplom", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "diplome", back: "die Diplome", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "chiar acum", back: "gerade", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "birou", back: "das Büro", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "birouri", back: "die Büros", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "informație", back: "die Information", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "informații", back: "die Informationen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "salut", back: "der Gruß", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "saluturi", back: "die Grüße", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "a se căsători", back: "heiraten", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "s-a căsătorit", back: "haben geheiratet", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "de fapt", back: "eigentlich", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "mai târziu", back: "später", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "ghid turistic", back: "der Reiseführer", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "ghizi turistici", back: "die Reiseführer", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "ghid turistică", back: "die Reiseführerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "ghizi turistice", back: "die Reiseführerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "turist", back: "der Tourist", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "turiști", back: "die Touristen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "turistă", back: "die Touristin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "turiste", back: "die Touristinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "a arăta", back: "zeigen", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "a arătat", back: "haben gezeigt", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "experiență profesională", back: "die Berufserfahrung", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "cafenea", back: "das Café", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "cafenele", back: "die Cafés", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "stres", back: "der Stress", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "uneori", back: "manchmal", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "chelner", back: "der Kellner", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "chelneri", back: "die Kellner", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "chelneriță", back: "die Kellnerin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "chelnerițe", back: "die Kellnerinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "restaurant", back: "das Restaurant", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "restaurante", back: "die Restaurants", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "arhitect", back: "der Architekt", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "arhitecți", back: "die Architekten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "arhitectă", back: "die Architektin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "arhitecte", back: "die Architektinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "bucătar", back: "der Koch", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "bucătari", back: "die Köche", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "bucătăreasă", back: "die Köchin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "bucătărese", back: "die Köchinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "muncitor", back: "der Arbeiter", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "muncitori", back: "die Arbeiter", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "muncitoare", back: "die Arbeiterin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "muncitoare", back: "die Arbeiterinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "puțin", back: "wenig", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "coleg", back: "der Kollege", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "colegi", back: "die Kollegen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "colegă", back: "die Kollegin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "colege", back: "die Kolleginnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "străinătate", back: "das Ausland", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "alt", back: "ander-", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "loc de muncă", back: "der Arbeitsplatz", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "locuri de muncă", back: "die Arbeitsplätze", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "vis", back: "der Traum", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "vise", back: "die Träume", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "de vis", back: "traum-", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "pe timpul zilei", back: "tagsüber", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "de trei ori", back: "dreimal", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "a primi", back: "bekommen", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "a primit", back: "haben bekommen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "secretar", back: "der Sekretär", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "secretari", back: "die Sekretäre", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "secretară", back: "die Sekretärin", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "secretare", back: "die Sekretärinnen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "universitate", back: "die Universität", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "universități", back: "die Universitäten", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "pe durată limitată", back: "befristet", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "normă întreagă", back: "die Vollzeit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "normă redusă", back: "die Teilzeit", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "tot timpul zilei", back: "ganztags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "jumătate de zi", back: "halbtags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "dimineața", back: "vormittags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "după-amiază", back: "nachmittags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "meditație (școală)", back: "die Nachhilfe", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "lunea", back: "montags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "joia", back: "donnerstags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "senior", back: "der Senior", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "seniori", back: "die Senioren", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "de seniori", back: "senioren-", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "ajutor temporar", back: "die Aushilfe", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "ajutoare temporare", back: "die Aushilfen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "urgent", back: "dringend", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "serviciu", back: "der Service", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "seara", back: "abends", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "marțea", back: "dienstags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "miercurea", back: "mittwochs", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "vinerea", back: "freitags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "duminica", back: "sonntags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "a plăti", back: "zahlen", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "a plătit", back: "haben gezahlt", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "pe", back: "pro", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "oră", back: "die Stunde", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "ore", back: "die Stunden", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "cerere", back: "die Nachfrage", lesson: "A1.8" },	{ front: "cereri", back: "die Nachfragen", lesson: "A1.8" },
{ front: "liber", back: "frei", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "câte", back: "jeweils", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "sâmbăta", back: "samstags", lesson: "A1.8" },	
{ front: "permis de conducere", back: "der Führerschein", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "permise de conducere", back: "die Führerscheine", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "bilet", back: "das Ticket", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "bilete", back: "die Tickets", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "instituție, birou", back: "das Amt", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "instituții, birouri", back: "die Ämter", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "valabil", back: "gültig", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "a închiria", back: "mieten", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a închiriat", back: "haben gemietet", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "străin", back: "ausländisch", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "european", back: "europäisch", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "Uniunea Europeană", back: "die Europäische Union", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "tânăr", back: "jung", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "călătorie", back: "die Fahrt", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "călătorii", back: "die Fahrten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "bilet de călătorie", back: "die Fahrkarte", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "bilete de călătorie", back: "die Fahrkarten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "cerere", back: "der Antrag", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "cereri", back: "die Anträge", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a trebui", back: "müssen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a trebuit", back: "haben gemusst", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a completa", back: "ausfüllen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a completat", back: "haben ausgefüllt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "carte de identitate", back: "der Ausweis", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "cărți de identitate", back: "die Ausweise", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a aduce cu sine", back: "mitbringen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a adus cu sine", back: "haben mitgebracht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "hârtie", back: "das Papier", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "hârtii", back: "die Papiere", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a semna", back: "unterschreiben", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a semnat", back: "haben unterschrieben", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "numerar", back: "bar", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "automat", back: "der Automat", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "automate", back: "die Automaten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a funcționa", back: "funktionieren", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a funcționat", back: "haben funktioniert", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "țintă, destinație", back: "das Ziel", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "ținte, destinații", back: "die Ziele", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a alege", back: "wählen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a ales", back: "haben gewählt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "adult", back: "der Erwachsene / die Erwachsene", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "adulți", back: "die Erwachsenen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a selecta", back: "auswählen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a selectat", back: "haben ausgewählt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "cineva / omul", back: "man", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "mai întâi", back: "zuerst", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "după aceea", back: "danach", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "apoi", back: "dann", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "sfârșit", back: "der Schluss", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "încet", back: "leise", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "a explica", back: "erklären", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a explicat", back: "haben erklärt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "tare", back: "laut", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "a stinge", back: "ausmachen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a stins", back: "haben ausgemacht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a asculta", back: "zuhören", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a ascultat", back: "haben zugehört", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a se ridica", back: "aufstehen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "s-a ridicat", back: "sein aufgestanden", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a aștepta", back: "warten", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a așteptat", back: "haben gewartet", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "taxă", back: "die Gebühr", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "taxe", back: "die Gebühren", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "casierie", back: "die Kasse", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "casierii", back: "die Kassen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a râde", back: "lachen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a râs", back: "haben gelacht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "moment", back: "der Moment", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "momente", back: "die Momente", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a solicita", back: "beantragen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a solicitat", back: "haben beantragt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a avea voie", back: "dürfen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a avut voie", back: "haben gedurft", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "atenție", back: "Achtung", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "țigară", back: "die Zigarette", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "țigări", back: "die Zigaretten", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a fuma", back: "rauchen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a fumat", back: "haben geraucht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "încet", back: "langsam", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "parcare", back: "der Parkplatz", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "parcări", back: "die Parkplätze", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a parca", back: "parken", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a parcat", back: "haben geparkt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "permis", back: "erlaubt", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "interzis", back: "verboten", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "bagaj", back: "das Gepäck", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "a preda", back: "abgeben", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a predat", back: "haben abgegeben", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a lua cu sine", back: "mitnehmen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a luat cu sine", back: "haben mitgenommen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "singur", back: "allein", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "autoritate", back: "die Behörde", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "autorități", back: "die Behörden", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "persoană", back: "die Person", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "persoane", back: "die Personen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "nume de naștere", back: "der Geburtsname", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "nume de naștere", back: "die Geburtsnamen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "sex", back: "das Geschlecht", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "sexe", back: "die Geschlechter", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "străin", back: "der Ausländer", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "străini", back: "die Ausländer", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "străină", back: "die Ausländerin", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "străine", back: "die Ausländerinnen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a locui separat", back: "getrennt leben", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "masculin", back: "männlich", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "feminin", back: "weiblich", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "membru de familie", back: "der Angehörige / die Angehörige", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "membri de familie", back: "die Angehörigen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a însemna", back: "bedeuten", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a însemnat", back: "haben bedeutet", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a repeta", back: "wiederholen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a repetat", back: "haben wiederholt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a înțelege", back: "verstehen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a înțeles", back: "haben verstanden", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "școală de limbi străine", back: "die Sprachenschule", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "școli de limbi străine", back: "die Sprachenschulen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a vizita / a frecventa", back: "besuchen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a vizitat / a frecventat", back: "haben besucht", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a ajuta", back: "helfen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a ajutat", back: "haben geholfen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "informație", back: "die Auskunft", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "informații", back: "die Auskünfte", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "permisiune", back: "die Erlaubnis", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "declarație", back: "die Erklärung", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "declarații", back: "die Erklärungen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "document", back: "das Dokument", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "documente", back: "die Dokumente", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "bani", back: "das Geld", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "suficient", back: "genug", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "venit", back: "das Einkommen", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "călătorie", back: "die Reise", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "călătorii", back: "die Reisen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "asigurare", back: "die Versicherung", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "asigurări", back: "die Versicherungen", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "ambasadă", back: "die Botschaft", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "ambasade", back: "die Botschaften", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "viză", back: "das Visum", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "vize", back: "die Visa", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a aduce", back: "holen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a adus", back: "haben geholt", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "angajat", back: "der Mitarbeiter", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "angajată", back: "die Mitarbeiterin", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "funcționar", back: "der Beamte", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "funcționară", back: "die Beamtin", lesson: "A1.9" },	
{ front: "a câștiga (bani)", back: "verdienen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a câștigat", back: "haben verdient", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "pașaport", back: "der Pass", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "pașapoarte", back: "die Pässe", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "a călători", back: "reisen", lesson: "A1.9" },	{ front: "a călătorit", back: "sein gereist", lesson: "A1.9" },
{ front: "club", back: "der Klub", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "cluburi", back: "die Klubs", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "urgență (secția de urgențe)", back: "die Notaufnahme", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "urgențe", back: "die Notaufnahmen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "domeniu, zonă", back: "der Bereich", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "domenii, zone", back: "die Bereiche", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "tabletă", back: "die Tablette", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "tablete", back: "die Tabletten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "ochi", back: "das Auge", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "ochi", back: "die Augen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "a durea", back: "weh tun", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "a durut", back: "haben wehgetan", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "accident", back: "der Unfall", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "accidente", back: "die Unfälle", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "doctor", back: "der Doktor", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "doctori", back: "die Doktoren", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "durere", back: "der Schmerz", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "dureri", back: "die Schmerzen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "a trebui (modal)", back: "sollen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "a trebuit", back: "haben gesollt", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "amândoi", back: "beide", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "amuzant", back: "lustig", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "grav, rău", back: "schlimm", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "a da", back: "geben", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "a dat", back: "haben gegeben", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "idee", back: "die Idee", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "idei", back: "die Ideen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "picior", back: "das Bein", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "picioare", back: "die Beine", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "păr", back: "das Haar", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "părți", back: "die Haare", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "ureche", back: "das Ohr", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "urechi", back: "die Ohren", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "braț", back: "der Arm", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "brațe", back: "die Arme", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "burtă", back: "der Bauch", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "burți", back: "die Bäuche", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "deget", back: "der Finger", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "degete", back: "die Finger", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "picior (talpă)", back: "der Fuß", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "picioare", back: "die Füße", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "gât", back: "der Hals", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "gâturi", back: "die Hälse", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "cap", back: "der Kopf", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "capete", back: "die Köpfe", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "spate", back: "der Rücken", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "piept", back: "die Brust", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "piepturi", back: "die Brüste", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "mână", back: "die Hand", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "mâini", back: "die Hände", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "nas", back: "die Nase", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "nasuri", back: "die Nasen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "gură", back: "der Mund", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "guri", back: "die Münder", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "a fi", back: "sein", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "ei / ele", back: "ihr", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "dinte", back: "der Zahn", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "dinți", back: "die Zähne", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "a informa", back: "informieren", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "a informat", back: "haben informiert", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "al nostru, a noastră", back: "unser", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "a cădea (a nu avea loc)", back: "ausfallen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "a căzut / nu a avut loc", back: "ist ausgefallen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "mesaj, știre", back: "die Nachricht", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "mesaje, știri", back: "die Nachrichten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "sărut", back: "der Kuss", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "săruturi", back: "die Küsse", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "al vostru, a voastră", back: "euer", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "sănătos", back: "gesund", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "sperăm că, cu speranță", back: "hoffentlich", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "cunoscut / cunoscută", back: "der Bekannte / die Bekannte", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "cunoscuți", back: "die Bekannten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "pas", back: "der Schritt", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "pași", back: "die Schritte", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "câțiva", back: "ein paar", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "medicină, medicament", back: "die Medizin", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "liniștit", back: "ruhig", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "farmacie", back: "die Apotheke", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "farmacii", back: "die Apotheken", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "febră", back: "das Fieber", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "tuse", back: "der Husten", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "unguent", back: "die Salbe", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "unguente", back: "die Salben", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "a folosi", back: "verwenden", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "a folosit", back: "haben verwendet", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "sănătate", back: "die Gesundheit", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "răceală (nas înfundat)", back: "der Schnupfen", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "a face", back: "tun", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "a făcut", back: "haben getan", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "expeditor", back: "der Absender", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "expeditori", back: "die Absender", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "loc", back: "der Ort", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "locuri", back: "die Orte", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "destinatar", back: "der Empfänger", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "destinatari", back: "die Empfänger", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "formulă de adresare", back: "die Anrede", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "formule de adresare", back: "die Anreden", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "dată", back: "das Datum", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "date", back: "die Daten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "semnătură", back: "die Unterschrift", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "semnături", back: "die Unterschriften", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "a trimite", back: "schicken", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "a trimis", back: "haben geschickt", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "oră de consultație", back: "die Sprechstunde", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "ore de consultație", back: "die Sprechstunden", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "urgență", back: "der Notfall", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "urgențe", back: "die Notfälle", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "în apropiere", back: "in der Nähe", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "minut", back: "die Minute", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "minute", back: "die Minuten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "în regulă", back: "in Ordnung", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "a trece pe la", back: "vorbeikommen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "a trecut pe la", back: "ist vorbeigekommen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "card de asigurat", back: "die Versichertenkarte", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "carduri de asigurați", back: "die Versichertenkarten", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "podea, sol", back: "der Boden", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "podele, soluri", back: "die Böden", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "a zace, a se afla", back: "liegen", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "a zăcut / aflat", back: "haben gelegen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "medic de urgență", back: "der Notarzt", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "medici de urgență", back: "die Notärzte", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "puternic", back: "stark", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "ajutor", back: "die Hilfe", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "brusc", back: "plötzlich", lesson: "A1.10" },	
{ front: "a se întâmpla", back: "passieren", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "s-a întâmplat", back: "ist passiert", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "medicament", back: "das Medikament", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "medicamente", back: "die Medikamente", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "motocicletă", back: "das Motorrad", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "motociclete", back: "die Motorräder", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "accidentare, rană", back: "die Verletzung", lesson: "A1.10" },	{ front: "accidentări, răni", back: "die Verletzungen", lesson: "A1.10" },
{ front: "atelier, service auto", back: "die Werkstatt", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "ateliere, service-uri auto", back: "die Werkstätten", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "cheie", back: "der Schlüssel", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "chei", back: "die Schlüssel", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "autostradă", back: "die Autobahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "autostrăzi", back: "die Autobahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "pod", back: "die Brücke", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "poduri", back: "die Brücken", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "dreapta", back: "rechts", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "drept înainte", back: "geradeaus", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "stânga", back: "links", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "drum, cale", back: "der Weg", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "drumuri", back: "die Wege", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "gară", back: "der Bahnhof", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "gări", back: "die Bahnhöfe", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "măcelărie", back: "die Metzgerei", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "măcelării", back: "die Metzgereien", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "poștă", back: "die Post", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "hotel", back: "das Hotel", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "hoteluri", back: "die Hotels", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "muzeu", back: "das Museum", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "muzee", back: "die Museen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "semafor", back: "die Ampel", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "semafoare", back: "die Ampeln", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "benzinărie", back: "die Tankstelle", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "benzinării", back: "die Tankstellen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "plan al orașului", back: "der Stadtplan", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "planuri ale orașului", back: "die Stadtpläne", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "străin", back: "fremd", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "a zbura", back: "fliegen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "a zburat", back: "ist geflogen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "avion", back: "das Flugzeug", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "avioane", back: "die Flugzeuge", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "tramvai", back: "die Straßenbahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "tramvaie", back: "die Straßenbahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "tren", back: "der Zug", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "trenuri", back: "die Züge", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "metrou", back: "die U-Bahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "metrouri", back: "die U-Bahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "autobuz", back: "der Bus", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "autobuze", back: "die Busse", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "tren suburban", back: "die S-Bahn", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "trenuri suburbane", back: "die S-Bahnen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "încotro, unde", back: "wohin", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "stație", back: "die Station", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "stații", back: "die Stationen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "camion", back: "der Lkw", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "camioane", back: "die Lkws", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "chioșc", back: "der Kiosk", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "chioșcuri", back: "die Kioske", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "stație de autobuz/tramvai", back: "die Haltestelle", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "stații de autobuz/tramvai", back: "die Haltestellen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "librărie", back: "die Buchhandlung", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "librării", back: "die Buchhandlungen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "a sta (jos)", back: "sitzen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "a stat", back: "haben gesessen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "bibliotecă", back: "die Bücherei", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "biblioteci", back: "die Büchereien", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "copac", back: "der Baum", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "copaci", back: "die Bäume", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "bancă (și bancă stradală)", back: "die Bank", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "bănci", back: "die Banken", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "lângă, pe", back: "an", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "pe", back: "auf", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "în spatele", back: "hinter", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "lângă", back: "neben", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "peste", back: "über", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "sub", back: "unter", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "între", back: "zwischen", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "zonă pietonală", back: "die Fußgängerzone", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "zone pietonale", back: "die Fußgängerzonen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "concert", back: "das Konzert", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "concerte", back: "die Konzerte", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "a împrumuta", back: "ausleihen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "a împrumutat", back: "haben ausgeliehen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "a copia", back: "kopieren", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "a copiat", back: "haben kopiert", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "acolo în față", back: "(da) vorne", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "acolo pe partea cealaltă", back: "(da) drüben", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "colț", back: "die Ecke", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "colțuri", back: "die Ecken", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "acolo în spate", back: "(da) hinten", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "a pleca (vehicul)", back: "abfahren", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "a plecat", back: "ist abgefahren", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "peron, linie ferată", back: "das Gleis", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "peroane, linii ferate", back: "die Gleise", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "a urca într-un vehicul", back: "einsteigen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "a urcat", back: "ist eingestiegen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "întârziere", back: "die Verspätung", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "întârzieri", back: "die Verspätungen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "a ajunge", back: "ankommen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "a ajuns", back: "ist angekommen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "a schimba (vehicul)", back: "umsteigen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "a schimbat vehiculul", back: "ist umgestiegen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "a coborî (din vehicul)", back: "aussteigen", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "a coborât", back: "ist ausgestiegen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "plecare", back: "die Abfahrt", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "plecări", back: "die Abfahrten", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "sosire", back: "die Ankunft", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "sosiri", back: "die Ankünfte", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "legătură (transport)", back: "der Anschluss", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "legături", back: "die Anschlüsse", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "peron", back: "der Bahnsteig", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "peroane", back: "die Bahnsteige", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "direct", back: "direkt", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "anunț (audio)", back: "die Durchsage", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "anunțuri", back: "die Durchsagen", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "ghișeu", back: "der Schalter", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "ghișee", back: "die Schalter", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "dus-întors", back: "hin und zurück", lesson: "A1.11" },	
{ front: "orar (transport)", back: "der Fahrplan", lesson: "A1.11" },	{ front: "orare", back: "die Fahrpläne", lesson: "A1.11" },
{ front: "geantă", back: "die Tasche", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "genți", back: "die Taschen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "pungă", back: "die Tüte", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "pungi", back: "die Tüten", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "factură", back: "die Rechnung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "facturi", back: "die Rechnungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "stricat", back: "kaputt", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "a repara", back: "reparieren", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au reparat", back: "haben repariert", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "acru", back: "sauer", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "nepoliticos", back: "unfreundlich", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "normal", back: "normal", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "țară natală", back: "das Heimatland", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "țări natale", back: "die Heimatländer", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "antrenament", back: "Training", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "haine", back: "die Kleider", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "a coase", back: "nähen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au cusut", back: "haben genäht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "reparație", back: "die Reparatur", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "reparații", back: "die Reparaturen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a face duș", back: "duschen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au făcut duș", back: "haben geduscht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "afirmație", back: "die Aussage", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "afirmații", back: "die Aussagen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "tehnician", back: "der Techniker", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "tehnicieni", back: "die Techniker", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "încălzire", back: "die Heizung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "încălziri", back: "die Heizungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "imprimantă", back: "der Drucker", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "imprimante", back: "die Drucker", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "model", back: "das Modell", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "modele", back: "die Modelle", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "garanție", back: "die Garantie", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "garanții", back: "die Garantien", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "trecut", back: "vorbei-", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "a aduce (cuiva)", back: "vorbeibringen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au adus", back: "haben vorbeigebracht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a porni", back: "anmachen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au pornit", back: "haben angemacht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "ușă", back: "die Tür", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "uși", back: "die Türen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a închide", back: "zumachen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au închis", back: "haben zugemacht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "fereastră", back: "das Fenster", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "ferestre", back: "die Fenster", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a deschide", back: "aufmachen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au deschis", back: "haben aufgemacht", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "hârtie", back: "das Papier", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "hârtii", back: "die Papiere", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "lumină", back: "das Licht", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "lumini", back: "die Lichter", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "mașină de spălat vase", back: "die Spülmaschine", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "mașini de spălat vase", back: "die Spülmaschinen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a recomanda", back: "empfehlen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au recomandat", back: "haben empfohlen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a rezerva", back: "reservieren", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au rezervat", back: "haben reserviert", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "recepție", back: "die Rezeption", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "recepții", back: "die Rezeptionen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "anunț", back: "die Ansage", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "anunțuri", back: "die Ansagen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a apăsa", back: "drücken", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au apăsat", back: "haben gedrückt", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a se înregistra", back: "anmelden", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "s-au înregistrat", back: "haben angemeldet", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a conecta", back: "verbinden", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au conectat", back: "haben verbunden", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a lăsa (mesaj)", back: "hinterlassen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au lăsat", back: "haben hinterlassen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a returna apel", back: "zurückrufen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au returnat apel", back: "haben zurückgerufen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a arăta", back: "aussehen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "au arătat", back: "haben ausgesehen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "vacanță", back: "der Urlaub", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "vacanțe", back: "die Urlaube", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "afară", back: "draußen", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "plecat", back: "weg", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "aparat de cafea", back: "die Kaffeemaschine", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "aparate de cafea", back: "die Kaffeemaschinen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "frizer", back: "der Friseur", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "frizeri", back: "die Friseure", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "frizeriță", back: "die Friseurin", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "frizerițe", back: "die Friseurinnen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a comanda", back: "bestellen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "a comandat", back: "hat bestellt", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "ofertă", back: "das Angebot", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "oferte", back: "die Angebote", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a oferi", back: "anbieten", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "a oferit", back: "hat angeboten", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "adolescent / adolescentă", back: "der Jugendliche / die Jugendliche", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "adolescenți", back: "die Jugendlichen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "instrucțiuni de utilizare", back: "die Gebrauchsanweisung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "instrucțiuni de utilizare", back: "die Gebrauchsanweisungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "curățenie", back: "die Reinigung", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "curățenii", back: "die Reinigungen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "ștecher", back: "der Stecker", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "ștechere", back: "die Stecker", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "priză", back: "die Steckdose", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "prize", back: "die Steckdosen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "a trage", back: "ziehen", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "a tras", back: "hat gezogen", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "sus", back: "oben", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "oțet", back: "der Essig", lesson: "A1.12" },	
{ front: "tastă", back: "die Taste", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "taste", back: "die Tasten", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "secundă", back: "die Sekunde", lesson: "A1.12" },	{ front: "secunde", back: "die Sekunden", lesson: "A1.12" },
{ front: "geacă", back: "die Jacke", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "geci", back: "die Jacken", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "palton", back: "der Mantel", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "paltoane", back: "die Mäntel", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "subțire", back: "dünn", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "a potrivi", back: "passen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "a potrivit", back: "hat gepasst", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "larg", back: "weit", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "îmbrăcăminte", back: "die Kleidung", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "bluză", back: "die Bluse", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "bluze", back: "die Blusen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "tricou", back: "das T-Shirt", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "tricouri", back: "die T-Shirts", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "pantof", back: "der Schuh", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "pantofi", back: "die Schuhe", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "pantaloni", back: "die Hose", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "pantaloni", back: "die Hosen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "fustă", back: "der Rock", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "fuste", back: "die Röcke", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "rochie", back: "das Kleid", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "rochii", back: "die Kleider", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "cizme", back: "der Stiefel", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "cizme", back: "die Stiefel", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "pulover", back: "der Pullover", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "pulovere", back: "die Pullover", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "șosetă", back: "die Socke", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "șosete", back: "die Socken", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "ciorap", back: "der Strumpf", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "ciorapi", back: "die Strümpfe", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "blugi", back: "die Jeans", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "blugi", back: "die Jeans", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "batic", back: "das Tuch", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "baticuri", back: "die Tücher", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "cămașă", back: "das Hemd", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "cămăși", back: "die Hemden", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "costum", back: "der Anzug", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "costume", back: "die Anzüge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "ochelari", back: "die Brille", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "ochelari", back: "die Brillen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "plictisitor", back: "langweilig", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "umbrelă (de ploaie)", back: "der (Regen-)Schirm", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "umbrele (de ploaie)", back: "die (Regen-)Schirme", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "ieftin", back: "günstig", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "perfect", back: "perfekt", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "a sta", back: "stehen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "a stat", back: "hat gestanden", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "cârnat prăjit", back: "die Bratwurst", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "cârnați prăjiți", back: "die Bratwürste", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "peisaj", back: "die Landschaft", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "peisaje", back: "die Landschaften", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "munte", back: "der Berg", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "munți", back: "die Berge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "sat", back: "das Dorf", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "sate", back: "die Dörfer", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "pădure", back: "der Wald", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "păduri", back: "die Wälder", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "Marea Nordului", back: "die Nordsee", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "plajă", back: "der Strand", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "plaje", back: "die Strände", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "mare", back: "das Meer", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "mări", back: "die Meere", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "port", back: "der Hafen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "porturi", back: "die Häfen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "niciodată", back: "nie", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "mai bine", back: "besser", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "cel mai bine", back: "am besten", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "înapoi", back: "rückwärts", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "înainte", back: "vorwärts", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "prezent", back: "dabei", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "greu", back: "schwer", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "muzician", back: "der Musiker", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "muzicieni", back: "die Musiker", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "muziciană", back: "die Musikerin", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "muziciene", back: "die Musikerinnen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "a se antrena", back: "trainieren", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "s-au antrenat", back: "hat trainiert", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "a merge cu bicicleta", back: "rad fahren", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "a mers cu bicicleta", back: "ist rad gefahren", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "record", back: "der Rekord", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "recorduri", back: "die Rekorde", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "cel mai mult", back: "am liebsten", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "cel mai mult", back: "am meisten", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "mulțumit", back: "zufrieden", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "glumă", back: "der Witz", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "glume", back: "die Witze", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "acesta/aceasta", back: "dies-", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "care", back: "welch-", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "valiză", back: "der Koffer", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "valize", back: "die Koffer", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "a aparține", back: "gehören", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "a aparținut", back: "hat gehört", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "a plăcea", back: "mögen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "a plăcut", back: "hat gemocht", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "zi lucrătoare", back: "der Wochentag", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "zile lucrătoare", back: "die Wochentage", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "parter", back: "das Erdgeschoss", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "partere", back: "die Erdgeschosse", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "etaj superior", back: "das Obergeschoss", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "etaje superioare", back: "die Obergeschosse", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "subsol", back: "das Untergeschoss", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "subsoluri", back: "die Untergeschosse", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "ieșire", back: "der Ausgang", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "ieșiri", back: "die Ausgänge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "farmacie (cosmetică)", back: "die Drogerie", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "farmacii (cosmetice)", back: "die Drogerien", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "cosmetice", back: "die Kosmetik", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "bijuterii", back: "der Schmuck", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "veselă", back: "das Geschirr", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "pahar", back: "das Glas", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "pahare", back: "die Gläser", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "modă", back: "die Mode", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "mode", back: "die Moden", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "intrare", back: "der Eingang", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "intrări", back: "die Eingänge", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "a scuza", back: "entschuldigen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "a scuzat", back: "hat entschuldigt", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "a ști", back: "wissen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "a știut", back: "hat gewusst", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "săpun", back: "die Seife", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "săpunuri", back: "die Seifen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "periuță de dinți", back: "die Zahnbürste", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "periuțe de dinți", back: "die Zahnbürsten", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "pastă de dinți", back: "die Zahnpasta", lesson: "A1.13" },	
{ front: "mărime", back: "die Größe", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "mărimi", back: "die Größen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "a îmbrăca", back: "anziehen", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "a îmbrăcat", back: "hat angezogen", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "a proba", back: "anprobieren", lesson: "A1.13" },	{ front: "a probat", back: "hat anprobiert", lesson: "A1.13" },
{ front: "ziua de naștere", back: "der Geburtstag", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "zile de naștere", back: "die Geburtstage", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "anvelopă", back: "der Reifen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "anvelope", back: "die Reifen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a povesti", back: "erzählen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a povestit", back: "hat erzählt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a sărbători", back: "feiern", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a sărbătorit", back: "hat gefeiert", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "rămas bun", back: "der Abschied", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "rămas bune", back: "die Abschiede", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "curând", back: "bald", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "a începe", back: "beginnen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a început", back: "hat begonnen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "loc de muncă", back: "die Arbeitsstelle", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "locuri de muncă", back: "die Arbeitsstellen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "noroc", back: "das Glück", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "bucurie", back: "die Freude", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "a-și dori", back: "(sich) wünschen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "și-a dorit", back: "hat gewünscht", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a felicita", back: "gratulieren", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a felicitat", back: "hat gratuliert", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "felicitare", back: "der Glückwunsch", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "felicitări", back: "die Glückwünsche", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a crede", back: "glauben", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a crezut", back: "hat geglaubt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a vizita", back: "besuchen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a vizitat", back: "hat besucht", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "noiembrie", back: "der November", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "ianuarie", back: "der Januar", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "întâi", back: "erste", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "al doilea", back: "zweite", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "al treilea", back: "dritte", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "februarie", back: "der Februar", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "martie", back: "der März", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "aprilie", back: "der April", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "mai", back: "der Mai", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "iunie", back: "der Juni", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "iulie", back: "der Juli", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "august", back: "der August", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "septembrie", back: "der September", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "octombrie", back: "der Oktober", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "decembrie", back: "der Dezember", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "floare", back: "die Blume", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "flori", back: "die Blumen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "carnaval", back: "der Karneval", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "ultimul", back: "letzt-", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "a participa", back: "mitmachen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a participat", back: "hat mitgemacht", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "zi de sărbătoare", back: "der Feiertag", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "zile de sărbătoare", back: "die Feiertage", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "cadou", back: "das Geschenk", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "cadouri", back: "die Geschenke", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a se iubi", back: "(sich) lieben", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "s-a iubit", back: "hat geliebt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "minunat", back: "wunderbar", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "desert", back: "der Nachtisch", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "deserturi", back: "die Nachtische", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a curăța", back: "putzen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a curățat", back: "hat geputzt", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "laptop", back: "der Laptop", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "laptopuri", back: "die Laptops", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "murdar", back: "schmutzig", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "a spăla", back: "waschen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a spălat", back: "hat gewaschen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "bunic", back: "der Großvater", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "bunici", back: "die Großväter", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "bunică", back: "die Großmutter", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "bunici", back: "die Großmütter", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "petrecere", back: "die Feier", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "petreceri", back: "die Feiern", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a organiza", back: "organisieren", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a organizat", back: "hat organisiert", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a informa", back: "Bescheid geben", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a informat", back: "hat Bescheid gegeben", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "invitație", back: "die Einladung", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "invitații", back: "die Einladungen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "zbor", back: "der Flug", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "zboruri", back: "die Flüge", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a deveni", back: "werden", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a devenit", back: "ist geworden", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a invita", back: "einladen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a invitat", back: "hat eingeladen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a se bucura", back: "sich freuen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "s-a bucurat", back: "hat sich gefreut", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "sărbătoare", back: "das Fest", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "sărbători", back: "die Feste", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "călduros", back: "herzlich", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "oaspete", back: "das Gast", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "oaspeți", back: "die Gäste", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "motiv", back: "der Grund", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "motive", back: "die Gründe", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "răspuns", back: "die Antwort", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "răspunsuri", back: "die Antworten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "a cere", back: "bitten", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a cerut", back: "hat gebeten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "Crăciun", back: "das Weihnachten", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "Paște", back: "das Ostern", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "Revelion", back: "das Silvester", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "Anul Nou", back: "das Neujahr", lesson: "A1.14" },	
{ front: "a câștiga", back: "gewinnen", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "a câștigat", back: "hat gewonnen", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "rude (masc./fem.)", back: "der Verwandte / die Verwandte", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "rude", back: "die Verwandten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "carte", back: "die Karte", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "cărți", back: "die Karten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "nuntă", back: "die Hochzeit", lesson: "A1.14" },	{ front: "nunți", back: "die Hochzeiten", lesson: "A1.14" },
{ front: "fericit", back: "glücklich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "a privi", back: "ansehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a privit", back: "hat angesehen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "vecin", back: "der Nachbar", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "vecini", back: "die Nachbarn", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "vecină", back: "die Nachbarin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "vecine", back: "die Nachbarinnen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "cumpărătură", back: "der Einkauf", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "cumpărături", back: "die Einkäufe", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a reuși", back: "klappen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a reușit", back: "hat geklappt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "centru", back: "das Zentrum", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "centre", back: "die Zentren", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "sentiment", back: "das Gefühl", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "sentimente", back: "die Gefühle", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "început", back: "der Anfang", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "începuturi", back: "die Anfänge", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a simți lipsa", back: "vermissen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a simțit lipsa", back: "hat vermisst", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "pentru că", back: "weil", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "om", back: "der Mensch", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "oameni", back: "die Menschen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "angajator", back: "der Arbeitgeber", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "angajatori", back: "die Arbeitgeber", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "angajatoare", back: "die Arbeitgeberin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "angajatoare", back: "die Arbeitgeberinnen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a se muta", back: "umziehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "s-a mutat", back: "ist umgezogen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a se cunoaște", back: "(sich) kennenlernen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "s-a cunoscut", back: "hat kennengelernt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "ieri", back: "gestern", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "mutare", back: "der Umzug", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "mutări", back: "die Umzüge", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "lucruri", back: "die Sachen", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "a despacheta", back: "auspacken", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a despachetat", back: "hat ausgepackt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a adormi", back: "einschlafen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a adormit", back: "ist eingeschlafen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "ceas deșteptător", back: "der Wecker", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "ceasuri deșteptătoare", back: "die Wecker", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a-și aminti", back: "(sich) merken", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "și-a amintit", back: "hat gemerkt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "în cele din urmă", back: "schließlich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "chiar", back: "sogar", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "zi de muncă", back: "der Arbeitstag", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "zile de muncă", back: "die Arbeitstage", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a suna", back: "klingen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a sunat", back: "hat geklungen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a experimenta", back: "erleben", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a experimentat", back: "hat erlebt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "pană", back: "die Panne", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "pene", back: "die Pannen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "viața de zi cu zi", back: "der Alltag", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "a pierde (ocazie)", back: "verpassen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a pierdut", back: "hat verpasst", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a observa", back: "bemerken", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a observat", back: "hat bemerkt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a afla", back: "erfahren", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a aflat", back: "hat erfahren", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a-și imagina / a se prezenta", back: "(sich) vorstellen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "și-a imaginat / s-a prezentat", back: "hat vorgestellt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "portofel", back: "die Geldbörse", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "portofele", back: "die Geldbörsen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a pierde", back: "verlieren", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a pierdut", back: "hat verloren", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "ghinion", back: "das Pech", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "card de credit", back: "die Kreditkarte", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "carduri de credit", back: "die Kreditkarten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a împinge / a da cu capul", back: "stoßen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a împins / a dat cu capul", back: "hat/ist gestoßen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "stânjenitor", back: "peinlich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "unchiu", back: "der Onkel", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "unchi", back: "die Onkel", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "mătușă", back: "die Tante", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "mătuși", back: "die Tanten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "văr", back: "der Cousin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "veri", back: "die Cousins", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "verișoară", back: "die Cousine", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "verișoare", back: "die Cousinen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "nepot", back: "der Neffe", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "nepoți", back: "die Neffen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "nepoată", back: "die Nichte", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "nepoate", back: "die Nichten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "simpatic", back: "sympathisch", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "membru", back: "das Mitglied", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "membri", back: "die Mitglieder", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "locuință comună (WG)", back: "die Wohngemeinschaft", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "locuințe comune", back: "die Wohngemeinschaften", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "probabil", back: "wahrscheinlich", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "acoperiș", back: "das Dach", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "acoperișuri", back: "die Dächer", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "până acum", back: "bisher", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "diferit", back: "verschieden", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "cartier", back: "das Viertel", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "cartiere", back: "die Viertel", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "chiriaș", back: "der Mieter", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "chiriași", back: "die Mieter", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "chiriașă", back: "die Mieterin", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "chiriașe", back: "die Mieterinnen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a se muta (în casă)", back: "einziehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "s-a mutat", back: "ist eingezogen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "dată / ocazie", back: "das Mal", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "date / ocazii", back: "die Male", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "ciudat", back: "komisch", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "cineva", back: "jemand", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "a ajunge", back: "reichen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a ajuns", back: "hat gereicht", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a împărți", back: "teilen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a împărțit", back: "hat geteilt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "a se muta (din casă)", back: "ausziehen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "s-a mutat", back: "ist ausgezogen", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "loc", back: "der Platz", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "locuri", back: "die Plätze", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "fiecare", back: "jeder", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "a folosi", back: "benutzen", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "a folosit", back: "hat benutzt", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "împreună", back: "gemeinsam", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "altfel", back: "sonst", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "acum", back: "nun", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "de obicei", back: "normalerweise", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "însărcinată", back: "schwanger", lesson: "A2.1" },	
{ front: "socru", back: "der Schwiegervater", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "socri", back: "die Schwiegerväter", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "soacră", back: "die Schwiegermutter", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "soacre", back: "die Schwiegermütter", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "gospodărie", back: "der Haushalt", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "gospodării", back: "die Haushalte", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "pensie", back: "die Rente", lesson: "A2.1" },	{ front: "pensii", back: "die Renten", lesson: "A2.1" },
{ front: "energia", back: "die Energie", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "însuși", back: "selbst", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "a schimba", back: "wechseln", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a schimbat", back: "hat gewechselt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "plafon / pătură", back: "die Decke", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "plafoane / pătură", back: "die Decken", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a atârna / a fi atârnat", back: "hängen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a atârnat / a fost atârnat", back: "hat gehängt / hat gehangen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "mulțumire", back: "der Dank", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "nimic", back: "nichts", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "cantitate", back: "die Menge", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "cantități", back: "die Mengen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "pix", back: "der Kugelschreiber", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "pixuri", back: "die Kugelschreiber", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a băga", back: "stecken", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a băgat", back: "hat gesteckt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "lacăt", back: "das Schloss", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "lacăte", back: "die Schlösser", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a sta", back: "stehen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a stat", back: "hat gestanden", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "imagine / tablou", back: "das Bild", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "imagini / tablouri", back: "die Bilder", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "perete", back: "die Wand", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "pereți", back: "die Wände", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "pisică", back: "die Katze", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "pisici", back: "die Katzen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a pune (orizontal)", back: "legen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a pus", back: "hat gelegt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "liniște", back: "die Ruhe", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "panou / indicator", back: "das Schild", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "panouri / indicatori", back: "die Schilder", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a deranja", back: "stören", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a deranjat", back: "hat gestört", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a pune (vertical)", back: "stellen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a pus", back: "hat gestellt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "creion / stilou", back: "der Stift", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "creioane / stilouri", back: "die Stifte", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a construi", back: "bauen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a construit", back: "hat gebaut", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "acolo", back: "dahin", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "plantă", back: "die Pflanze", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "plante", back: "die Pflanzen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "către acolo", back: "dorthin", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "precauție", back: "die Vorsicht", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "a cădea jos", back: "runterfallen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a căzut", back: "ist gefallen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "înăuntru", back: "rein", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "gunoi", back: "der Müll", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "afară", back: "raus", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "a intra", back: "reinkommen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a intrat", back: "ist reingekommen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "comunicare", back: "die Mitteilung", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "comunicări", back: "die Mitteilungen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "locuitor", back: "der Bewohner", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "locuitori", back: "die Bewohner", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "locuitoare", back: "die Bewohnerin", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "locuitoare", back: "die Bewohnerinnen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a separa", back: "trennen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a separat", back: "hat getrennt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "bio-", back: "bio-", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "deșeu", back: "der Abfall", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "deșeuri", back: "die Abfälle", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "plastic", back: "das Plastik", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "a respecta / a ține cont", back: "beachten", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a respectat", back: "hat beachtet", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "colectare gunoi", back: "die Müllabfuhr", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "colectări gunoi", back: "die Müllabfuhren", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "tomberon de gunoi", back: "die Mülltonne", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "tombere de gunoi", back: "die Mülltonnen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a opri / a lăsa (mașina)", back: "abstellen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a oprit / a lăsat", back: "hat abgestellt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "intrare (în garaj)", back: "die Einfahrt", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "intrări (în garaj)", back: "die Einfahrten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "curte", back: "der Hof", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "curți", back: "die Höfe", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a rezilia", back: "kündigen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a reziliat", back: "hat gekündigt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "contract", back: "der Vertrag", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "contracte", back: "die Verträge", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a spera", back: "hoffen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a sperat", back: "hat gehofft", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "înțelegere", back: "das Verständnis", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "a încheia", back: "abschließen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a încheiat", back: "hat abgeschlossen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "scăzut", back: "niedrig", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "costuri", back: "die Kosten", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "a crește", back: "(sich) erhöhen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a crescut", back: "hat erhöht", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a îndepărta", back: "entfernen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a îndepărtat", back: "hat entfernt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "obiect", back: "der Gegenstand", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "obiecte", back: "die Gegenstände", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a încălzi", back: "heizen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a încălzit", back: "hat geheizt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "cărucior pentru copii", back: "der Kinderwagen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "cărucioare pentru copii", back: "die Kinderwagen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "lift", back: "der Aufzug", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "lifturi", back: "die Aufzüge", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "scară", back: "die Treppe", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "scări", back: "die Treppen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "cutie poștală", back: "der Briefkasten", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "cutii poștale", back: "die Briefkästen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "soluție", back: "die Lösung", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "soluții", back: "die Lösungen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "destul de", back: "ziemlich", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "a avea dreptate", back: "recht haben", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a avut dreptate", back: "hat recht gehabt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "întrebare", back: "die Frage", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "întrebări", back: "die Fragen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "rugăminte", back: "die Bitte", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "rugăminți", back: "die Bitten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "intenție", back: "die Absicht", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "intenții", back: "die Absichten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "schimb (la muncă)", back: "die Schicht", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "schimburi", back: "die Schichten", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a lăsa", back: "lassen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a lăsat", back: "hat gelassen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a arunca", back: "werfen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a aruncat", back: "hat geworfen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a avea grijă", back: "aufpassen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a avut grijă", back: "hat aufgepasst", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a uda", back: "gießen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a udat", back: "hat gegossen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "cu adevărat", back: "wirklich", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "a suna (clopoțelul)", back: "klingeln", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a sunat", back: "hat geklingelt", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a discuta", back: "besprechen", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a discutat", back: "hat besprochen", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "a hrăni", back: "füttern", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "a hrănit", back: "hat gefüttert", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "meșter", back: "der Handwerker", lesson: "A2.2" },	{ front: "meșteri", back: "die Handwerker", lesson: "A2.2" },
{ front: "gunoi biodegradabil", back: "der Biomüll", lesson: "A2.2" },	
{ front: "desert", back: "die Nachspeise", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "deserturi", back: "die Nachspeisen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "miere", back: "der Honig", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "de obicei", back: "meistens", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "rar", back: "selten", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "a fi corect / a corespunde", back: "stimmen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "a fost corect / a corespuns", back: "hat gestimmt", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "în drum / pe drum", back: "unterwegs", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "masă", back: "die Mahlzeit", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "mese", back: "die Mahlzeiten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "la prânz", back: "mittags", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "dimineața", back: "morgens", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "ceașcă", back: "die Tasse", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "cești", back: "die Tassen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "sigur", back: "bestimmt", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "mâncare", back: "das Essen", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "prânz", back: "das Mittagessen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "prânzuri", back: "die Mittagessen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "cantină", back: "die Kantine", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "cantine", back: "die Kantinen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "aproape", back: "fast", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "vegetarian", back: "vegetarisch", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "fel de mâncare", back: "das Gericht", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "feluri de mâncare", back: "die Gerichte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "obicei", back: "die Gewohnheit", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "obiceiuri", back: "die Gewohnheiten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "a prelua", back: "übernehmen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "a preluat", back: "hat übernommen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "gem", back: "die Marmelade", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "gemuri", back: "die Marmeladen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "german", back: "deutsch", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "porc", back: "das Schwein", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "porci", back: "die Schweine", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "alcool", back: "der Alkohol", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "de două ori", back: "zweimal", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "lingură", back: "der Löffel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "linguri", back: "die Löffel", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "cuțit", back: "das Messer", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "cuțite", back: "die Messer", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "farfurie", back: "der Teller", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "farfurii", back: "die Teller", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "furculiță", back: "die Gabel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "furculițe", back: "die Gabeln", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "cvartet", back: "das Quartett", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "cvartete", back: "die Quartette", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "oală", back: "der Topf", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "oale", back: "die Töpfe", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "cană", back: "die Kanne", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "căni", back: "die Kannen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "castron", back: "die Schüssel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "castroane", back: "die Schüsseln", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "tigaie", back: "die Pfanne", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "tigăi", back: "die Pfannen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "apetit", back: "der Appetit", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "a mirosi", back: "riechen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "a mirosit", back: "hat gerochen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "a se dezbrăca", back: "(sich) ausziehen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "s-a dezbrăcat", back: "hat ausgezogen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "plin", back: "voll", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "ok", back: "okay", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "înainte", back: "vorher", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "politicos", back: "höflich", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "dietă", back: "die Diät", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "diete", back: "die Diäten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "sătul", back: "satt", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "diferit", back: "anders", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "exact așa", back: "genauso", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "a surprinde", back: "überraschen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "a surprins", back: "hat überrascht", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "ciudat", back: "seltsam", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "iute / ascuțit", back: "scharf", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "dulce", back: "süß", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "sărat", back: "salzig", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "gras", back: "fett", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "a conduce", back: "leiten", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "a condus", back: "hat geleitet", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "proaspăt", back: "frisch", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "rotund", back: "rund", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "diferit", back: "unterschiedlich", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "fel / tip", back: "die Art", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "feluri / tipuri", back: "die Arten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "musli", back: "das Müsli", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "musliuri", back: "die Müslis", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "fruct", back: "die Frucht", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "fructe", back: "die Früchte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "aperitiv", back: "die Vorspeise", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "aperitive", back: "die Vorspeisen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "principal", back: "Haupt-", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "procent", back: "das Prozent", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "procente", back: "die Prozente", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "piață", back: "der Markt", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "piețe", back: "die Märkte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "regional", back: "regional", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "produs", back: "das Produkt", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "produse", back: "die Produkte", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "împrejurimi", back: "die Umgebung", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "împrejurimi", back: "die Umgebungen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "friptură", back: "das Steak", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "fripturi", back: "die Steaks", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "fabrică", back: "die Fabrik", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "fabrici", back: "die Fabriken", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "împotriva", back: "gegen", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "a planifica", back: "planen", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "a planificat", back: "hat geplant", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "zilnic", back: "täglich", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "șnițel", back: "das Schnitzel", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "șnițele", back: "die Schnitzel", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "supă", back: "die Suppe", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "supe", back: "die Suppen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "bucată", back: "das Stück", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "bucăți", back: "die Stücke", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "lămâie", back: "die Zitrone", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "lămâi", back: "die Zitronen", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "curat", back: "sauber", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "vită", back: "das Rind", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "vite", back: "die Rinder", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "friptură", back: "der Braten", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "fripturi", back: "die Braten", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "ocupat", back: "besetzt", lesson: "A2.3" },	
{ front: "bacșiș", back: "das Trinkgeld", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "bacșișuri", back: "die Trinkgelder", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "pahar", back: "das Glas", lesson: "A2.3" },	{ front: "pahare", back: "die Gläser", lesson: "A2.3" },
{ front: "rezervare", back: "die Reservierung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "rezervări", back: "die Reservierungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "confirmare", back: "die Bestätigung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "confirmări", back: "die Bestätigungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a nota", back: "notieren", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a notat", back: "hat notiert", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "online / pe internet", back: "online", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "dificil", back: "schwierig", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "discuție / întâlnire", back: "die Besprechung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "discuții / întâlniri", back: "die Besprechungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "adică / anume", back: "nämlich", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "amabil / prietenos", back: "freundlich", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "deștept", back: "klug", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "greșeală", back: "der Fehler", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "greșeli", back: "die Fehler", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "dacă / atunci când", back: "wenn", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "sigur", back: "sicher", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "material", back: "das Material", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "materiale", back: "die Materialien", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "participant", back: "der Teilnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "participanți", back: "die Teilnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "participantă", back: "die Teilnehmerin", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "participante", back: "die Teilnehmerinnen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "sfat", back: "der Tipp", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "sfaturi", back: "die Tipps", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "regulat", back: "regelmäßig", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "a ține cont de / a acorda atenție la", back: "achten auf", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a ținut cont de / a acordat atenție la", back: "hat geachtet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "bilet / buletin", back: "der Zettel", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "bilete / buletine", back: "die Zettel", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "magazin universal / magazin mare", back: "das Kaufhaus", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "magazine universale / magazine mari", back: "die Kaufhäuser", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a folosi", back: "nutzen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a folosit", back: "hat genutzt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "platformă", back: "die Plattform", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "platforme", back: "die Plattformen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "forum", back: "das Forum", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "forumuri", back: "die Foren", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "agenție", back: "die Agentur", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "agenții", back: "die Agenturen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "muncă temporară", back: "die Zeitarbeit", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "munci temporare", back: "die Zeitarbeiten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "ucenic / ucenică", back: "der Auszubildende / die Auszubildende", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "ucenici / ucenice", back: "die Auszubildenden", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a opri / a stinge", back: "aus·schalten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a oprit / a stins", back: "hat ausgeschaltet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "sindicat", back: "die Gewerkschaft", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "sindicate", back: "die Gewerkschaften", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "siguranță", back: "die Sicherheit", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "protecție", back: "der Schutz", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "întreprindere / firmă", back: "der Betrieb", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "întreprinderi / firme", back: "die Betriebe", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "adunare / reuniune", back: "die Versammlung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "adunări / reuniuni", back: "die Versammlungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "termen", back: "die Frist", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "termene", back: "die Fristen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "perfecționare / formare continuă", back: "die Weiterbildung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "perfecționări", back: "die Weiterbildungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "interes", back: "das Interesse", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "a ieși la pensie", back: "in Rente gehen", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "viață", back: "das Leben", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "pensionar", back: "der Rentner", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "pensionari", back: "die Rentner", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "pensionară", back: "die Rentnerin", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "pensionare", back: "die Rentnerinnen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "eveniment", back: "die Veranstaltung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "evenimente", back: "die Veranstaltungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a se adresa / a aplica (o regulă)", back: "wenden", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "s‑a adresat / a aplicat", back: "hat gewandt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a avea loc", back: "statt·finden", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a avut loc", back: "hat stattgefunden", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "consiliul de întreprindere", back: "der Betriebsrat", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "consilii de întreprindere", back: "die Betriebsräte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a raporta / a relata", back: "berichten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a raportat / a relatat", back: "hat berichtet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a sfătui / a consilia", back: "beraten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a sfătuit / a consiliat", back: "hat beraten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "tarif", back: "der Tarif", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "tarife", back: "die Tarife", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "drept", back: "das Recht", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "drepturi", back: "die Rechte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "reziliere / notificare", back: "die Kündigung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "rezilieri / notificări", back: "die Kündigungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "concediere / destituire", back: "die Entlassung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "concedieri / destituiri", back: "die Entlassungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "reglementare / prevedere", back: "die Vorschrift", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "reglementări", back: "die Vorschriften", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "fără", back: "ohne", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "a concedia / a elibera", back: "entlassen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a concediat / a eliberat", back: "hat entlassen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a proteja", back: "schützen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a protejat", back: "hat geschützt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "(a) mulțumi", back: "(sich) bedanken", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a mulțumit / s‑a mulțumit", back: "hat bedankt", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a organiza / a realiza", back: "aus·richten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a organizat / a realizat", back: "hat ausgerichtet", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "export", back: "der Export", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "exporturi", back: "die Exporte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a încerca", back: "versuchen", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a încercat", back: "hat versucht", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "nimeni", back: "niemand", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "sfârșitul zilei de muncă", back: "der Feierabend", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "sfârșiturile zilei de muncă", back: "die Feierabende", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "import", back: "der Import", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "importuri", back: "die Importe", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "salariat", back: "der Arbeitnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "salariați", back: "die Arbeitnehmer", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "salariată", back: "die Arbeitnehmerin", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "salariate", back: "die Arbeitnehmerinnen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "în medie", back: "durchschnittlich", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "idee / bănuială", back: "die Ahnung", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "idei / bănuieli", back: "die Ahnungen", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "zi națională", back: "der Nationalfeiertag", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "zile naționale", back: "die Nationalfeiertage", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "ore suplimentare", back: "die Überstunde", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "ore suplimentare", back: "die Überstunden", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "salariu", back: "der Lohn", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "salarii", back: "die Löhne", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "a oferi", back: "bieten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a oferit", back: "hat geboten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "regulă", back: "die Regel", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "reguli", back: "die Regeln", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "industrie", back: "die Industrie", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "medie", back: "der Durchschnitt", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "medii", back: "die Durchschnitte", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "cei mai mulți", back: "die meisten", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "în total / per total", back: "insgesamt", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "a valora / a conta", back: "gelten", lesson: "A2.4" },	{ front: "a valorat / a contat", back: "hat gegolten", lesson: "A2.4" },
{ front: "cel puțin", back: "mindestens", lesson: "A2.4" },	
{ front: "(a) se mișca", back: "(sich) bewegen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a mișcat / s‑a mișcat", back: "hat bewegt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se interesa de", back: "(sich) interessieren für", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a interesat de", back: "hat interessiert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "dansă", back: "der Tanz", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "danse", back: "die Tänze", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "baschet", back: "der Basketball", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "(a) se simți", back: "(sich) fühlen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a simțit", back: "hat gefühlt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "prea puțin", back: "zu wenig", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "video", back: "das Video", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "videoclipuri", back: "die Videos", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "a cădea", back: "hinfallen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a căzut", back: "ist hingefallen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "dorință", back: "die Lust", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "club / asociație", back: "der Verein", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "cluburi / asociații", back: "die Vereine", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "încercare", back: "der Versuch", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "încercări", back: "die Versuche", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "maestru", back: "der Meister", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "maeștri", back: "die Meister", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "sport", back: "die Sportart", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "sporturi", back: "die Sportarten", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "relaxare", back: "die Entspannung", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "alimentație", back: "die Ernährung", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "mișcare", back: "die Bewegung", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "mișcări", back: "die Bewegungen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "în formă", back: "fit", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "plimbare", back: "der Spaziergang", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "plimbări", back: "die Spaziergänge", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se întâlni (cu)", back: "(sich) verabreden mit", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a întâlnit cu", back: "hat verabredet", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se odihni", back: "(sich) aus·ruhen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a odihnit", back: "hat ausgeruht", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se hrăni", back: "(sich) ernähren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a hrănit", back: "hat ernährt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se supăra (pe / din cauza)", back: "(sich) ärgern (über)", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a supărat", back: "hat geärgert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se machia", back: "(sich) schminken", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a machiat", back: "hat geschminkt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se rade", back: "(sich) rasieren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a ras", back: "hat rasiert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se schimba / se îmbrăca", back: "(sich) um·ziehen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a schimbat / s‑a îmbrăcat", back: "hat umgezogen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se pieptăna", back: "(sich) kämmen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a pieptănat", back: "hat gekämmt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se spăla", back: "(sich) waschen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a spălat", back: "hat gewaschen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se grăbi", back: "(sich) beeilen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a grăbit", back: "hat beeilt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se concentra (pe)", back: "(sich) konzentrieren (auf)", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a concentrat pe", back: "hat konzentriert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se plânge (de)", back: "(sich) beschweren (über)", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a plâns de", back: "hat beschwert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "deloc / în general", back: "überhaupt", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "revistă", back: "die Zeitschrift", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "reviste", back: "die Zeitschriften", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "istorie", back: "die Geschichte", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "teatru", back: "das Theater", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "teatre", back: "die Theater", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "știri", back: "die Nachrichten", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "campionat mondial", back: "die Weltmeisterschaft", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "campionate mondiale", back: "die Weltmeisterschaften", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "prognoză meteo", back: "die Wettervorhersage", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "prognoze meteo", back: "die Wettervorhersagen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "echipă", back: "die Mannschaft", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "echipe", back: "die Mannschaften", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "vizită", back: "der Besuch", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "vizite", back: "die Besuche", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se îngriji (de)", back: "(sich) kümmern um", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a îngrijit de", back: "hat gekümmert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) visa la", back: "träumen von", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a visat la", back: "hat geträumt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "frică", back: "die Angst", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "frici", back: "die Ängste", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "sincer", back: "ehrlich", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "aur", back: "das Gold", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "sezon", back: "die Saison", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "sezoane", back: "die Saisons", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a)-și aminti de", back: "(sich) erinnern an", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "și-a amintit de", back: "hat erinnert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se gândi la", back: "denken an", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a gândit la", back: "hat gedacht", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "vacanță", back: "die Ferien", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "gimnastică", back: "die Gymnastik", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "tenis de masă", back: "das Tischtennis", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "volei", back: "der Volleyball", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "condiție fizică / fitness", back: "die Fitness", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "contribuție", back: "der Beitrag", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "contribuții", back: "die Beiträge", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "a se cifra", back: "betragen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a cifrat", back: "hat betragen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "grup", back: "die Gruppe", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "grupuri", back: "die Gruppen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "reducere", back: "die Ermäßigung", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "reduceri", back: "die Ermäßigungen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "gratuit", back: "kostenlos", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "ucenic", back: "der Azubi", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "ucenici", back: "die Azubis", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "suplimentar / în plus", back: "zusätzlich", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "activ", back: "aktiv", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a alerga lejer", back: "joggen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a alergat lejer", back: "ist gejoggt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "(a) se ține", back: "(sich) halten", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "s‑a ținut", back: "hat gehalten", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "frecvent", back: "häufig", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "cauză", back: "die Ursache", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "cauze", back: "die Ursachen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "boală", back: "die Krankheit", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "boli", back: "die Krankheiten", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "ecran", back: "der Bildschirm", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "ecrane", back: "die Bildschirme", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "corp", back: "der Körper", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "corpuri", back: "die Körper", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "în plus / de asemenea", back: "außerdem", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "aer", back: "die Luft", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "investigație / examinare", back: "die Untersuchung", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "investigații / examinări", back: "die Untersuchungen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "a reuși / a face", back: "schaffen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a reușit / a făcut", back: "hat geschafft", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "ieftin / avantajos", back: "preiswert", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a alerga", back: "laufen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a alergat", back: "ist gelaufen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "tendință", back: "der Trend", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "tendințe", back: "die Trends", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "loc de joacă", back: "der Spielplatz", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "locuri de joacă", back: "die Spielplätze", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "extra", back: "extra", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "flexibil", back: "flexibel", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "mediu", back: "die Umwelt", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "casă de asigurări de sănătate", back: "die Krankenkasse", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "case de asigurări", back: "die Krankenkassen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "îndrăgit", back: "beliebt", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "traseu / distanță", back: "die Strecke", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "trasee / distanțe", back: "die Strecken", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "clar", back: "klar", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a exagera", back: "übertreiben", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a exagerat", back: "hat übertrieben", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "firesc / evident", back: "selbstverständlich", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a juca tenis", back: "tennis spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a schia", back: "ski fahren", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a juca baschet", back: "basketball spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a face gimnastică", back: "gymnastik machen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a juca tenis de masă", back: "tischtennis spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a juca volei", back: "volleyball spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a face antrenament de fitness", back: "fitnesstraining machen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a juca hochei pe gheață", back: "eishockey spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a înota", back: "schwimmen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a înotat", back: "ist geschwommen", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "a merge pe bicicletă", back: "fahrrad fahren", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a mers pe bicicletă", back: "ist gefahren", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "a juca fotbal", back: "fußball spielen", lesson: "A2.5" },	
{ front: "a face drumeții", back: "wandern", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a făcut drumeții", back: "ist gewandert", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "a dansa", back: "tanzen", lesson: "A2.5" },	{ front: "a dansat", back: "hat getanzt", lesson: "A2.5" },
{ front: "certificat / notă școlară", back: "das Zeugnis", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "certificate / note școlare", back: "die Zeugnisse", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "materie / disciplină", back: "das Fach", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "materii / discipline", back: "die Fächer", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "notă", back: "die Note", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "note", back: "die Noten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "liceu (cu profil academic)", back: "das Gymnasium", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "licee academice", back: "die Gymnasien", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "referat / prezentare", back: "das Referat", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "referate / prezentări", back: "die Referate", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "bacalaureat", back: "das Abitur", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "absolvire / diplomă", back: "der Abschluss", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "absolviri / diplome", back: "die Abschlüsse", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "examen / test", back: "die Prüfung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "examene / teste", back: "die Prüfungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "leneș / leneșă", back: "faul", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "îngrozitor / teribil", back: "schrecklich", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "harnic / silitor", back: "fleißig", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "inteligent / inteligentă", back: "intelligent", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "a se certa", back: "streiten", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "s‑a certat", back: "hat gestritten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "că / ca", back: "dass", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "a îmbunătăți", back: "verbessern", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "a îmbunătățit", back: "hat verbessert", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "comportament", back: "das Verhalten", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "strict / sever", back: "streng", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "dorință", back: "der Wunsch", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "dorințe", back: "die Wünsche", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "plan", back: "der Plan", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "planuri", back: "die Pläne", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "astronaut", back: "der Astronaut", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "astronauți", back: "die Astronauten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "astronaută", back: "die Astronautin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "astronauțe", back: "die Astronautinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "mai devreme / mai înainte", back: "vorhin", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "mijlociu / median", back: "mittler-", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "activitate", back: "die Aktivität", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "activități", back: "die Aktivitäten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "sistem", back: "das System", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "sisteme", back: "die Systeme", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "facultate / colegiu tehnic", back: "die (Fach-)Hochschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "facultăți / colegii tehnici", back: "die (Fach-)Hochschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "universitate", back: "die Universität", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "universități", back: "die Universitäten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "școală comprehensive", back: "die Gesamtschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "școli comprehensive", back: "die Gesamtschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "școală medie (cu profil practic)", back: "die Realschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "școli medii practice", back: "die Realschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "școală generală", back: "die Hauptschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "școli generale", back: "die Hauptschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "școală gimnazială", back: "die Mittelschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "școli gimnaziale", back: "die Mittelschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "școală profesională", back: "die Berufsschule", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "școli profesionale", back: "die Berufsschulen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "voluntar / voluntară", back: "freiwillig", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "creșă", back: "die Krippe", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "creșe", back: "die Krippen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "fizică", back: "die Physik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "educație socială / științe sociale", back: "die Sozialkunde", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "biologie", back: "die Biologie", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "chimie", back: "die Chemie", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "geografie", back: "die Geografie", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "artă", back: "die Kunst", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "istorie", back: "die Geschichte", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "a urî", back: "hassen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "a urât", back: "hat gehasst", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "primăvară", back: "das Frühjahr", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "început", back: "der Beginn", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "teorie", back: "die Theorie", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "teorii", back: "die Theorien", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "introducere", back: "die Einführung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "introduceri", back: "die Einführungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "a salva (pe computer)", back: "speichern", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "a salvat", back: "hat gespeichert", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "migrant", back: "der Migrant", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "migranți", back: "die Migranten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "migrantă", back: "die Migrantin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "migrante", back: "die Migrantinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "social", back: "sozial", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "prelegere / discurs", back: "der Vortrag", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "prelegeri / discursuri", back: "die Vorträge", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "a aplica (pentru un post etc.)", back: "(sich) bewerben", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "s‑a aplicat", back: "hat beworben", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "a prezenta", back: "präsentieren", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "a prezentat", back: "hat präsentiert", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "expert", back: "der Experte", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "experți", back: "die Experten", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "expertă", back: "die Expertin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "experte", back: "die Expertinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "pregătire", back: "die Vorbereitung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "pregătiri", back: "die Vorbereitungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "certificat", back: "das Zertifikat", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "certificate", back: "die Zertifikate", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "sprijin / finanțare", back: "die Förderung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "sprijine / finanțări", back: "die Förderungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "posibil", back: "möglich", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "consiliere / consultanță", back: "die Beratung", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "consilieri / consultanțe", back: "die Beratungen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "a se răni", back: "sich verletzen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "s‑a rănit", back: "hat verletzt", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "a sângera", back: "bluten", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "a sângerat", back: "hat geblutet", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "studiu / învățământ superior", back: "das Studium", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "programul zilnic", back: "der Tagesablauf", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "programe zilnice", back: "die Tagesabläufe", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "a promova / a exista", back: "bestehen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "a promovat / a existat", back: "hat bestanden", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "context migrator / background migrator", back: "der Migrationshintergrund", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "mândru / mândră", back: "stolz", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "electric", back: "elektrisch", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "tehnică / tehnologie", back: "die Technik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "contact", back: "der Kontakt", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "contacte", back: "die Kontakte", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "a recunoaște", back: "anerkennen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "a recunoscut", back: "hat anerkannt", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "a verifica / a examina", back: "prüfen", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "a verificat / a examinat", back: "hat geprüft", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "complicat", back: "kompliziert", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "brutar / brutări", back: "der Bäcker", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "brutari / brutări", back: "die Bäcker", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "brutară", back: "die Bäckerin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "brutare", back: "die Bäckerinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "actor", back: "der Schauspieler", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "actori", back: "die Schauspieler", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "actriță", back: "die Schauspielerin", lesson: "A2.6" },	{ front: "actrițe", back: "die Schauspielerinnen", lesson: "A2.6" },
{ front: "muzică", back: "die Musik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "matematică", back: "die Mathematik", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "sport", back: "der Sport", lesson: "A2.6" },	
{ front: "necunoscut", back: "unbekannt", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "a pregăti", back: "vorbereiten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a pregătit", back: "hat vorbereitet", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "a confecționa / a meșteri", back: "basteln", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a confecționat / a meșterit", back: "hat gebastelt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "a decide", back: "entscheiden", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a decis", back: "hat entschieden", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "a dărui", back: "schenken", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a dăruit", back: "hat geschenkt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "bebeluș", back: "das Baby", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "bebeluși", back: "die Babys", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "colier / lanț", back: "die Kette", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "coliere / lanțuri", back: "die Ketten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "a ghici / a sfătui", back: "raten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a ghicit / a sfătuit", back: "hat geraten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "păpușă", back: "die Puppe", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "păpuși", back: "die Puppen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "DVD", back: "die DVD", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "DVD-uri", back: "die DVDs", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "parfum", back: "das Parfüm", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "parfumuri", back: "die Parfüms", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "cremă", back: "die Creme", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "creme", back: "die Cremes", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "portofel", back: "der Geldbeutel", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "portofele", back: "die Geldbeutel", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "a încerca", back: "probieren", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a încercat", back: "hat probiert", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "făinăție / tăiței", back: "die Nudel", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "tăiței", back: "die Nudeln", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "a livra", back: "liefern", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a livrat", back: "hat geliefert", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "de încredere / fiabil", back: "zuverlässig", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "special / deosebit", back: "Sonder-", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "a numi", back: "nennen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a numit", back: "hat genannt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "cutie", back: "die Schachtel", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "cutii", back: "die Schachteln", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "a imprima (pe hârtie)", back: "ausdrucken", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a imprimat", back: "hat ausgedruckt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "timbru", back: "die Briefmarke", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "timbre", back: "die Briefmarken", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "oameni", back: "die Leute", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "biserică", back: "die Kirche", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "biserici", back: "die Kirchen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "cununie", back: "die Trauung", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "cununii", back: "die Trauungen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "nebun / extrem", back: "wahnsinnig", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "dispoziție / atmosferă", back: "die Stimmung", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "prost / tâmpit", back: "blöd", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "a saluta", back: "grüßen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a salutat", back: "hat gegrüßt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "minunat", back: "wunderschön", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "a plânge", back: "weinen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a plâns", back: "hat geweint", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "tipic", back: "typisch", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "tortă", back: "die Torte", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "torturi", back: "die Torten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "apropo / de altfel", back: "übrigens", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "a păși / a calca", back: "treten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a pășit / a călcat", back: "ist getreten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "probabil / bine", back: "wohl", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "nervos", back: "nervös", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "cel puțin", back: "wenigstens", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "treaz", back: "wach", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "sălbatic / turbulent", back: "wild", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "a purta", back: "tragen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a purtat", back: "hat getragen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "personal / personal", back: "persönlich", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "inimă", back: "das Herz", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "inimi", back: "die Herzen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "moarte", back: "der Tod", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "a cheltui / a emite", back: "ausgeben", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a cheltuit / a emis", back: "hat ausgegeben", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "patrie / casă natală", back: "die Heimat", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "per / prin", back: "per", lesson: "A2.7" },	
{ front: "SMS", back: "die SMS", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "SMS-uri", back: "die SMS", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "a se întreține (conversații)", back: "sich unterhalten", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "s‑a întreținut", back: "hat unterhalten", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "a decora", back: "dekorieren", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a decorat", back: "hat dekoriert", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "divertisment / întreținere", back: "die Unterhaltung", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "divertismente / întrețineri", back: "die Unterhaltungen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "a convinge", back: "überzeugen", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "a convins", back: "hat überzeugt", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "pralină", back: "die Praline", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "praline", back: "die Pralinen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "ciocolată", back: "die Schokolade", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "ciocolate", back: "die Schokoladen", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "carte", back: "das Buch", lesson: "A2.7" },	{ front: "cărți", back: "die Bücher", lesson: "A2.7" },
{ front: "lemn", back: "das Holz", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "lemne", back: "die Hölzer", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "ciocan", back: "der Hammer", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "ciocane", back: "die Hämmer", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "unealtă / sculă", back: "das Werkzeug", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "unelte / scule", back: "die Werkzeuge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "a participa la joacă / a juca împreună", back: "mitspielen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "a participat / a jucat împreună", back: "hat mitgespielt", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "discotecă", back: "die Disko / die Diskothek", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "discoteci", back: "die Diskos / die Diskotheken", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "a ieși (la distracție)", back: "ausgehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "a ieșit", back: "ist ausgegangen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "a petrece (timp)", back: "verbringen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "a petrecut", back: "hat verbracht", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "rufe / haine de spălat", back: "die Wäsche", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a întreprinde", back: "unternehmen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "a întreprins", back: "hat unternommen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "lucru / obiect", back: "das Ding", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "lucruri / obiecte", back: "die Dinge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "lac", back: "der See", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "lacuri", back: "die Seen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "totuși / cu toate acestea", back: "trotzdem", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "tur cu bicicleta", back: "die Radtour", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "tururi cu bicicleta", back: "die Radtouren", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "târg de vechituri / piață de vechituri", back: "der Flohmarkt", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "târguri de vechituri", back: "die Flohmärkte", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "a fi răcit", back: "erkältet sein", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "constant / mereu", back: "ständig", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "propunere", back: "der Vorschlag", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "propuneri", back: "die Vorschläge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "tur în circuit / excursie panoramică", back: "die Rundfahrt", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "tururi panoramice / excursii", back: "die Rundfahrten", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "de acord", back: "einverstanden", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "pozitiv", back: "positiv", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a reacționa", back: "reagieren", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "a reacționat", back: "hat reagiert", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "negativ", back: "negativ", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "bară / local", back: "die Bar", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "baruri", back: "die Bars", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "cultură", back: "die Kultur", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "natură", back: "die Natur", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "operă", back: "die Oper", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "opere", back: "die Opern", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "punct de întâlnire", back: "der Treffpunkt", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "puncte de întâlnire", back: "die Treffpunkte", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "primărie / casa municipală", back: "das Rathaus", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "primării", back: "die Rathäuser", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "participare", back: "die Teilnahme", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a apărea / a se prezenta", back: "auftreten", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "a apărut / s‑a prezentat", back: "ist aufgetreten", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "jazz", back: "der Jazz", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "cale ferată / tren", back: "die Bahn", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "căi ferate / trenuri", back: "die Bahnen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "deschis", back: "offen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "instituție de educație pentru adulți", back: "die Volkshochschule", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "instituții educaționale pentru adulți", back: "die Volkshochschulen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "politică", back: "die Politik", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "fotografie", back: "die Fotografie", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "necesar / obligatoriu", back: "erforderlich", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "intrare liberă", back: "Eintritt frei", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "nici o înscriere nu este necesară", back: "keine Anmeldung erforderlich", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "semestru", back: "das Semester", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "semestre", back: "die Semester", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "drumeție", back: "die Wanderung", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "drumeții", back: "die Wanderungen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "program", back: "das Programm", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "programe", back: "die Programme", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "fan / susținător", back: "der Fan", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "fani", back: "die Fans", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "artist", back: "der Künstler", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "artiști", back: "die Künstler", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "artistă", back: "die Künstlerin", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "artiste", back: "die Künstlerinnen", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "Europa", back: "Europa", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "jucărie", back: "das Spielzeug", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "jucării", back: "die Spielzeuge", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "CD / disc", back: "die CD", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "CD-uri", back: "die CDs", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "în zilele de lucru", back: "wochentags", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "bilet de intrare", back: "die Eintrittskarte", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "bilete de intrare", back: "die Eintrittskarten", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "post de radio / stație", back: "der Sender", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "posturi / stații", back: "die Sender", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "a face o drumeție", back: "eine Wanderung machen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a face", back: "machen", lesson: "A2.8" },	{ front: "a făcut", back: "hat gemacht", lesson: "A2.8" },
{ front: "a merge la operă", back: "in die Oper gehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a merge într-un bar", back: "in eine Bar", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a face un tur panoramic", back: "eine Rundfahrt machen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "un tur cu bicicleta", back: "eine Radtour", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a merge la un târg de vechituri", back: "auf einen Flohmarkt gehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a merge la discotecă", back: "in die Disko gehen", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a merge la lac", back: "an den See fahren", lesson: "A2.8" },	
{ front: "a amenaja / a instala", back: "einrichten", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "a amenajat / a instalat", back: "hat eingerichtet", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "poster", back: "das Poster", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "postere", back: "die Poster", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "lumânare", back: "die Kerze", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "lumânări", back: "die Kerzen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "urât / oribil", back: "scheußlich", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "colorat", back: "bunt", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "a privi", back: "gucken", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "a privit", back: "hat geguckt", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "portofel de piele / borsetă", back: "die Brieftasche", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "portofele de piele / borsete", back: "die Brieftaschen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "brichetă", back: "das Feuerzeug", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "brichete", back: "die Feuerzeuge", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "cameră", back: "die Kamera", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "camere", back: "die Kameras", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "bikini", back: "der Bikini", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "costume de baie (bikini)", back: "die Bikinis", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "practic", back: "praktisch", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "drăguț / frumos", back: "hübsch", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "gros / de grosime", back: "dick", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "placă / disc", back: "die Platte", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "plăci / discuri", back: "die Platten", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "înălțime", back: "die Höhe", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "înălțimi", back: "die Höhen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "stare", back: "der Zustand", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "stări", back: "die Zustände", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "calitate", back: "die Qualität", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "calități", back: "die Qualitäten", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "tacâmuri", back: "das Besteck", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "tacâmuri", back: "die Bestecke", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "metal", back: "das Metall", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "metale", back: "die Metalle", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "material / țesătură", back: "der Stoff", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "materiale / țesături", back: "die Stoffe", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "rucsac", back: "der Rucksack", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "rucsaci", back: "die Rucksäcke", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "pălărie", back: "der Hut", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "pălării", back: "die Hüte", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "dragoste", back: "die Liebe", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "roman", back: "der Roman", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "romane", back: "die Romane", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "palpitant / interesant", back: "spannend", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "decât / ca", back: "als", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "stadion", back: "das Stadion", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "stadioane", back: "die Stadien", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "calculator / PC", back: "der PC", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "PC-uri", back: "die PCs", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "budincă", back: "der Pudding", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "budinci", back: "die Puddings", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "vitrină", back: "das Schaufenster", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "vitrine", back: "die Schaufenster", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "a propune", back: "vorschlagen", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "a propus", back: "hat vorgeschlagen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "îndepărtat / la distanță", back: "entfernt", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "statistică", back: "die Statistik", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "statistici", back: "die Statistiken", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "aliment / produs alimentar", back: "das Nahrungsmittel", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "alimente / produse alimentare", back: "die Nahrungsmittel", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "gaz", back: "das Gas", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "gaze", back: "die Gase", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "credit", back: "der Kredit", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "credite", back: "die Kredite", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "a înregistra / a primi / a absorbi", back: "aufnehmen", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "a înregistrat / a primit / a absorbit", back: "hat aufgenommen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "a economisi / a strânge", back: "sparen", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "a economisit / a strâns", back: "hat gespart", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "unii / unele", back: "manch-", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "amintire", back: "die Erinnerung", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "amintiri", back: "die Erinnerungen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "gând", back: "der Gedanke", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "gânduri", back: "die Gedanken", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "valoros", back: "wertvoll", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "pe atunci", back: "damals", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "drag / dragă", back: "lieb", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "de aceea", back: "deshalb", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "înăuntru / acolo", back: "drin", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "ciocan", back: "der Hammer", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "ciocane", back: "die Hämmer", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "lemn", back: "das Holz", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "lemne", back: "die Hölzer", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "lampă", back: "die Lampe", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "lampi", back: "die Lampen", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "pahar / sticlă", back: "das Glas", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "pahare / sticle", back: "die Gläser", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "tacâmuri", back: "das Besteck", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "tacâmuri", back: "die Bestecke", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "metal", back: "das Metall", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "metale", back: "die Metalle", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "castron (pentru salată)", back: "die (Salat‑) Schüssel", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "castroane (pentru salată)", back: "die (Salat-) Schüsseln", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "plastic", back: "das Plastik", lesson: "A2.9" },	
{ front: "bilet de intrare", back: "die Eintrittskarte", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "bilete de intrare", back: "die Eintrittskarten", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "hârtie", back: "das Papier", lesson: "A2.9" },	{ front: "hârtii", back: "die Papiere", lesson: "A2.9" },
{ front: "colet / pachet", back: "das Paket", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "colete / pachete", back: "die Pakete", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "plic", back: "der Briefumschlag", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "plicuri", back: "die Briefumschläge", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "carte poștală", back: "die Postkarte", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "cărți poștale", back: "die Postkarten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "foarfecă", back: "die Schere", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "foarfece", back: "die Scheren", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "a trimite", back: "verschicken", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "a trimis", back: "hat verschickt", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "a expedia", back: "versenden", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "a expediat", back: "hat versendet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "ordonat / îngrijit", back: "ordentlich", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "expediere / colet", back: "die Sendung", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "expedieri / colete", back: "die Sendungen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "a transporta", back: "transportieren", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "a transportat", back: "hat transportiert", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "tare", back: "hart", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "a cântări", back: "wiegen", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "a cântărit", back: "hat gewogen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "a ambala", back: "verpacken", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "a ambalat", back: "hat verpackt", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "navă / vas", back: "das Schiff", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "nave / vase", back: "die Schiffe", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "recoltă", back: "die Ernte", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "recolte", back: "die Ernten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "copt / matur", back: "reif", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "moale", back: "weich", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "imaginație", back: "die Fantasie", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "imaginații", back: "die Fantasien", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "ce fel de / ce tip de", back: "was für ein‑", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "posibilitate", back: "die Möglichkeit", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "posibilități", back: "die Möglichkeiten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "pentru că / deci", back: "denn", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "scrisoare recomandată", back: "das Einschreiben", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "a trimite", back: "senden", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "a trimis", back: "hat gesendet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "pachețel", back: "das Päckchen", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "pachetele", back: "die Päckchen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "vamă / taxă vamală", back: "der Zoll", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "taxe vamale", back: "die Zölle", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "valoros", back: "wert", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "neapărat", back: "unbedingt", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "grijă", back: "die Sorge", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "griji", back: "die Sorgen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "a îngheța", back: "frieren", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "a înghețat", back: "hat gefroren", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "cale ferată / tren", back: "die Eisenbahn", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "căi ferate / trenuri", back: "die Eisenbahnen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "frunză / foaie", back: "das Blatt", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "frunze / foi", back: "die Blätter", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "urs", back: "der Bär", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "urși", back: "die Bären", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "monedă", back: "die Münze", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "monede", back: "die Münzen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "rață", back: "die Ente", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "rațe", back: "die Enten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "suvenir", back: "das Souvenir", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "suveniruri", back: "die Souvenirs", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "animal", back: "das Tier", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "animale", back: "die Tiere", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "pasăre", back: "der Vogel", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "păsări", back: "die Vögel", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "ne‑ (prefix)", back: "un‑", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "punct", back: "der Punkt", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "puncte", back: "die Punkte", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "elefant", back: "der Elefant", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "elefanți", back: "die Elefanten", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "trandafir", back: "die Rose", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "trandafiri", back: "die Rosen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "stea", back: "der Stern", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "stele", back: "die Sterne", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "cer", back: "der Himmel", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "ceruri", back: "die Himmel", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "portocaliu / orange (ca adjectiv/substantiv)", back: "orange", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "rețea", back: "das Netzwerk", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "rețele", back: "die Netzwerke", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "a testa", back: "testen", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "a testat", back: "hat getestet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "cunoaștere", back: "das Wissen", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "quiz / chestionar", back: "das Quiz", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "quizuri", back: "die Quiz", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "telefon mobil / celular", back: "das Mobiltelefon", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "telefoane mobile", back: "die Mobiltelefone", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "mail / poștă electronică", back: "die Mail", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "e-mailuri", back: "die Mails", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "la nivel mondial / global", back: "weltweit", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "cutie poștală electronică / inbox", back: "die Mailbox", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "cutii poștale electronice", back: "die Mailboxen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "succes", back: "der Erfolg", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "succese", back: "die Erfolge", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "cârciumă / local", back: "die Kneipe", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "cârciumi / localuri", back: "die Kneipen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "a se anunța / a raporta", back: "melden (sich)", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "s‑a anunțat / s‑a raportat", back: "hat sich gemeldet", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "consiliul părinților / comitet părinți", back: "der Elternbeirat", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "consilii ale părinților", back: "die Elternbeiräte", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "gripă", back: "die Grippe", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "vaccinare", back: "die Impfung", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "vaccinări", back: "die Impfungen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "consulat", back: "das Konsulat", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "consulate", back: "die Konsulate", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "general / generalizat", back: "allgemein", lesson: "A2.10" },	
{ front: "scrisoare", back: "der Brief", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "scrisori", back: "die Briefe", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "cutie poștală", back: "der Briefkasten", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "cutii poștale", back: "die Briefkästen", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "e-mail / poștă electronică", back: "die E‑Mail", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "e-mailuri", back: "die E-Mails", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "telefon mobil / celular", back: "das Handy", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "telefoane mobile", back: "die Handys", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "chat / discuție online", back: "der Chat", lesson: "A2.10" },	{ front: "chat-uri", back: "die Chats", lesson: "A2.10" },
{ front: "grădină zoologică", back: "der Zoo", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "grădini zoologice", back: "die Zoos", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "tigru", back: "der Tiger", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "tigri", back: "die Tiger", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "zebră", back: "das Zebra", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "zebre", back: "die Zebras", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a privi", back: "anschauen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a privit", back: "hat angeschaut", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a pleca cu vehiculul", back: "wegfahren", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a plecat", back: "ist weggefahren", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a sări", back: "springen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a sărit", back: "ist gesprungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a alimenta (cu carburant)", back: "tanken", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a alimentat", back: "hat getankt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "de-a lungul", back: "entlang", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "pe lângă", back: "vorbei … an", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "vis-a-vis / în față de", back: "gegenüber", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "direcție", back: "die Richtung", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "direcții", back: "die Richtungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "râu", back: "der Fluss", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "râuri", back: "die Flüsse", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "intersecție", back: "die Kreuzung", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "intersecții", back: "die Kreuzungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a coti / a vira", back: "abbiegen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a cotit", back: "ist abgebogen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "ieșire (de pe autostradă)", back: "die Ausfahrt", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "ieșiri", back: "die Ausfahrten", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "copiator", back: "der Kopierer", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "copiatoare", back: "die Kopierer", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "cafenea", back: "die Cafeteria", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "cafenele", back: "die Cafeterien", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "ambuteiaj", back: "der Stau", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "ambuteiaje", back: "die Staus", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "trotuar", back: "der Bürgersteig", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "trotuare", back: "die Bürgersteige", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a cădea", back: "stürzen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a căzut", back: "ist gestürzt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "biciclist", back: "der Radfahrer", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "bicicliști", back: "die Radfahrer", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "genunchi", back: "das Knie", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "genunchi", back: "die Knie", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a lipi", back: "kleben", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a lipit", back: "hat geklebt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "plasture", back: "das Pflaster", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "plasturi", back: "die Pflaster", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "roată / bicicletă", back: "das Rad", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "roți / biciclete", back: "die Räder", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "dragă / preferat", back: "der Liebling", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "dragi / preferați", back: "die Lieblinge", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a se opri", back: "stehen bleiben", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "s-a oprit", back: "ist stehen geblieben", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "benzină", back: "das Benzin", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "baterie", back: "die Batterie", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "baterii", back: "die Batterien", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "gol", back: "leer", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "la timp", back: "rechtzeitig", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "trafic", back: "der Verkehr", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "șantier", back: "die Baustelle", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "șantiere", back: "die Baustellen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "bandă (de circulație) / urmă", back: "die Spur", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "benzi / urme", back: "die Spuren", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a depăși", back: "überholen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a depășit", back: "hat überholt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "carosabil", back: "die Fahrbahn", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "carosabile", back: "die Fahrbahnen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "atent / cu grijă", back: "vorsichtig", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "din cauza", back: "wegen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "gheață", back: "das Eis", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "ceață", back: "der Nebel", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "cețuri", back: "die Nebel", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "furtună", back: "der Sturm", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "furtuni", back: "die Stürme", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "furtună cu descărcări electrice", back: "das Gewitter", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "furtuni", back: "die Gewitter", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "cețos", back: "neblig", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "haos", back: "das Chaos", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a se îngrijora / a se ocupa de", back: "sorgen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "s-a îngrijorat / a avut grijă", back: "hat gesorgt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "situație", back: "die Situation", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "situații", back: "die Situationen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "complet", back: "komplett", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "timp de ore întregi", back: "stundenlang", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "automobil / mașină", back: "der Wagen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "automobile / mașini", back: "die Wagen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "regiune", back: "die Region", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "regiuni", back: "die Regionen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "căldură", back: "die Hitze", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "piesă / parte", back: "das Teil", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "piese / părți", back: "die Teile", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "puternic / viguros", back: "kräftig", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a evita", back: "vermeiden", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a evitat", back: "hat vermieden", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "pericol", back: "die Gefahr", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "pericole", back: "die Gefahren", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "cetățean", back: "der Bürger", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "cetățeni", back: "die Bürger", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "cetățeancă", back: "die Bürgerin", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "cetățene", back: "die Bürgerinnen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "vedere / perspectivă", back: "die Aussicht", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "vederi / perspective", back: "die Aussichten", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a promite", back: "versprechen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a promis", back: "hat versprochen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "de vară / estival", back: "sommerlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "dens / închis", back: "dicht", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a împiedica", back: "verhindern", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a împiedicat", back: "hat verhindert", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "decolare / start", back: "der Start", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "decolări / starturi", back: "die Starts", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "aterizare", back: "die Landung", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "aterizări", back: "die Landungen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "aeroport", back: "der Flughafen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "aeroporturi", back: "die Flughäfen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a decola / a porni", back: "starten", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a decolat / a pornit", back: "ist gestartet", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a ateriza", back: "landen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a aterizat", back: "ist gelandet", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "probabil / preconizat", back: "voraussichtlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "decolare (zbor)", back: "der Abflug", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "decolări", back: "die Abflüge", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "periculos", back: "gefährlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a atrage atenția / a ieși în evidență", back: "auffallen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a ieșit în evidență", back: "ist aufgefallen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "moped", back: "das Moped", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "mopede", back: "die Mopeds", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "mijloc de transport", back: "das Verkehrsmittel", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "mijloace de transport", back: "die Verkehrsmittel", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a claxona", back: "hupen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a claxonat", back: "hat gehupt", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a frâna", back: "bremsen", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a frânat", back: "hat gebremst", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "pieton", back: "der Fußgänger", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "pietoni", back: "die Fußgänger", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "pietoniță", back: "die Fußgängerin", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "pietonițe", back: "die Fußgängerinnen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "amendă (rutieră)", back: "der Strafzettel", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "amenzi", back: "die Strafzettel", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "pedeapsă / amendă", back: "die Strafe", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "pedepse / amenzi", back: "die Strafen", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "obositor / solicitant", back: "anstrengend", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "groaznic / teribil", back: "furchtbar", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "public", back: "öffentlich", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "a vorbi", back: "reden", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "a vorbit", back: "hat geredet", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "diferență", back: "der Unterschied", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "diferențe", back: "die Unterschiede", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "țară", back: "das Land", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "viteză / ritm", back: "das Tempo", lesson: "A2.11" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.11" },
{ front: "Marea Baltică", back: "die Ostsee", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "alegere", back: "die Wahl", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "a vizita / a inspecta", back: "besichtigen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a vizitat / a inspectat", back: "hat besichtigt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "în schimb / contra", back: "dagegen", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "entuziasmat / fascinat", back: "begeistert", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "cazare", back: "die Unterkunft", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "cazări", back: "die Unterkünfte", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "vis", back: "der Traum", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "vise", back: "die Träume", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "coastă", back: "die Küste", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "coaste", back: "die Küsten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "insulă", back: "die Insel", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "insule", back: "die Inseln", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "masiv montan / munți", back: "das Gebirge", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "Luxemburg", back: "Luxemburg", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "a face baie", back: "baden", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a făcut baie", back: "hat gebadet", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "nisip", back: "der Sand", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "mai departe / în continuare", back: "weiter", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "răcoros / rece", back: "kühl", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "fermă", back: "der Bauernhof", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "ferme", back: "die Bauernhöfe", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "vacă", back: "die Kuh", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "vaci", back: "die Kühe", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "cal", back: "das Pferd", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "cai", back: "die Pferde", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "oaie", back: "das Schaf", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "oi", back: "die Schafe", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "barcă", back: "das Boot", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "bărci", back: "die Boote", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "festival", back: "das Festival", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "festivaluri", back: "die Festivals", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "atracție turistică", back: "die Sehenswürdigkeit", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "atracții turistice", back: "die Sehenswürdigkeiten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "mai ales / în special", back: "vor allem", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "adevărat / autentic", back: "echt", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "pensiune", back: "die Pension", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "pensiuni", back: "die Pensionen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "privire / vedere", back: "der Blick", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "priviri / vederi", back: "die Blicke", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "cameră single", back: "das Einzelzimmer", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "cameră dublă", back: "das Doppelzimmer", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "toaletă / WC", back: "das WC", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "toalete / WC-uri", back: "die WCs", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "demipensiune", back: "die Halbpension", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "camping / campare", back: "das Camping", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "tur / excursie", back: "die Tour", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "tururi / excursii", back: "die Touren", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "vale", back: "das Tal", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "văi", back: "die Täler", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "pajiște", back: "die Wiese", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "pajiști", back: "die Wiesen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "romantic", back: "romantisch", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "poziție / amplasament", back: "die Lage", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "poziții / amplasamente", back: "die Lagen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "castel / palat", back: "das Schloss", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "castele / palate", back: "die Schlösser", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "istoric", back: "historisch", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "numeros / numeroși", back: "zahlreich", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "cazare peste noapte", back: "die Übernachtung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "cazări peste noapte", back: "die Übernachtungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "celebru / faimos", back: "berühmt", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "catedrală", back: "der Dom", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "catedrale", back: "die Dome", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "hostel / casă de tineret", back: "die Jugendherberge", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "hosteluri / case de tineret", back: "die Jugendherbergen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "inclus", back: "inklusive", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "ședere / sejur", back: "der Aufenthalt", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "sejururi / șederi", back: "die Aufenthalte", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a rezerva", back: "buchen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a rezervat", back: "hat gebucht", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "agenție de turism", back: "das Reisebüro", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "agenții de turism", back: "die Reisebüros", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "specialist", back: "der Spezialist", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "specialiști", back: "die Spezialisten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "angajat", back: "der Angestellte", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "angajați", back: "die Angestellten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "angajată", back: "die Angestellte", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "angajate", back: "die Angestellten", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "legătură / conexiune", back: "die Verbindung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "legături / conexiuni", back: "die Verbindungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "desigur / evident", back: "natürlich", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "a naviga pe internet / a face surf", back: "surfen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a navigat / a surfat", back: "ist gesurft", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "ghidaj / conducere", back: "die Führung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "ghidaje / conduceri", back: "die Führungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "centrul vechi (al orașului)", back: "die Altstadt", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "centre vechi", back: "die Altstädte", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "expoziție", back: "die Ausstellung", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "expoziții", back: "die Ausstellungen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "cunoscut", back: "bekannt", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "nicăieri", back: "nirgends", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "a împacheta", back: "einpacken", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a împachetat", back: "hat eingepackt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a se pune de acord", back: "einigen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "s-a pus de acord", back: "hat geeinigt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a petrece noaptea", back: "übernachten", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a petrecut noaptea", back: "hat übernachtet", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a fi împotrivă", back: "dagegen sein", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a fost împotrivă", back: "ist dagegen gewesen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a fi pentru", back: "dafür sein", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a fost pentru", back: "ist dafür gewesen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a accepta", back: "annehmen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a acceptat", back: "hat angenommen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a refuza", back: "ablehnen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a refuzat", back: "hat abgelehnt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a lenevi", back: "faulenzen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a lenevit", back: "hat gefaulenzt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "destinație turistică", back: "das Reiseziel", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "destinații", back: "die Reiseziele", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "activități", back: "die Aktivitäten", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "a vizita atracții turistiche", back: "Sehenswürdigkeiten ansehen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a vizitat atracții turistice", back: "hat Sehenswürdigkeiten angesehen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a vizita centrul vechi", back: "die Altstadt besichtigen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a vizitat centrul vechi", back: "hat die Altstadt besichtigt", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a vizita o expoziție", back: "eine Ausstellung ansehen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a vizitat o expoziție", back: "hat eine Ausstellung angesehen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "a face tur ghidat al orașului", back: "eine Stadtführung machen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a făcut tur ghidat al orașului", back: "hat eine Stadtführung gemacht", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "la agenția de turism", back: "im Reisebüro", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "a rezerva o călătorie", back: "eine Reise buchen", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "a rezervat o călătorie", back: "hat eine Reise gebucht", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "informație / răspuns", back: "die Auskunft", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "călătorie / voiaj", back: "die Reise", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "călătorii / voiaje", back: "die Reisen", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "birou", back: "das Büro", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "birouri", back: "die Büros", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "înghețată / gheață", back: "das Eis", lesson: "A2.12" },	
{ front: "ou", back: "das Ei", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "ouă", back: "die Eier", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "suma (de plată)", back: "der Betrag", lesson: "A2.12" },	{ front: "sumele", back: "die Beträge", lesson: "A2.12" },
{ front: "cont", back: "das Konto", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "conturi", back: "die Konten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a deschide (un cont)", back: "eröffnen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a deschis", back: "hat eröffnet", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a răspunde (la ceva)", back: "beantworten", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a răspuns", back: "hat beantwortet", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a procura / a face rost", back: "besorgen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a procurat", back: "hat besorgt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a amâna / a muta", back: "verschieben", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a amânat / a mutat", back: "hat verschoben", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "card bancar (EC)", back: "die EC-Karte", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "carduri bancare", back: "die EC-Karten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a retrage (bani)", back: "abheben", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a retras", back: "hat abgehoben", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a primi (colocvial)", back: "kriegen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a primit", back: "hat gekriegt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "bancomat", back: "der Geldautomat", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "bancomate", back: "die Geldautomaten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "cont curent", back: "das Girokonto", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "conturi curente", back: "die Girokonten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "dacă (conjuncție)", back: "ob", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "numerar / bani lichizi", back: "das Bargeld", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "sumă", back: "die Summe", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "sume", back: "die Summen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "ci (conjuncție adversativă)", back: "sondern", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "lunar", back: "monatlich", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "dobânzi", back: "die Zinsen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a accepta", back: "akzeptieren", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a acceptat", back: "hat akzeptiert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "bani de buzunar", back: "das Taschengeld", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a rezolva / a duce la capăt", back: "erledigen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a rezolvat", back: "hat erledigt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a controla", back: "kontrollieren", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a controlat", back: "hat kontrolliert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "control", back: "die Kontrolle", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "controale", back: "die Kontrollen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a se strica", back: "kaputtgehen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "s-a stricat", back: "ist kaputtgegangen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a recunoaște", back: "erkennen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a recunoscut", back: "hat erkannt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "producător", back: "der Hersteller", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "producători", back: "die Hersteller", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "ulei", back: "das Öl", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "frână", back: "die Bremse", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "frâne", back: "die Bremsen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a verifica", back: "überprüfen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a verificat", back: "hat überprüft", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a renova", back: "renovieren", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a renovat", back: "hat renoviert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a schimba", back: "ändern", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a schimbat", back: "hat geändert", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a se tăia", back: "schneiden (sich)", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "s-a tăiat", back: "hat sich geschnitten", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a depune (bani)", back: "einzahlen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a depus", back: "hat eingezahlt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "broșură", back: "die Broschüre", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "broșuri", back: "die Broschüren", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "salariu", back: "das Gehalt", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "salarii", back: "die Gehälter", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "dovadă de salariu", back: "der Gehaltsnachweis", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "dovezi de salariu", back: "die Gehaltsnachweise", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a tasta", back: "tippen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a tastat", back: "hat getippt", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a transfera (bani)", back: "überweisen", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a transferat", back: "hat überwiesen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "meniu", back: "das Menü", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "meniuri", back: "die Menüs", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "chelner", back: "der Ober", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "chelneri", back: "die Ober", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "poliția", back: "die Polizei", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "supărat / rău", back: "böse", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "–", back: "–", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "dispoziție", back: "die Laune", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "dispoziții", back: "die Launen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "creștere (ex. de salariu)", back: "die Erhöhung", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "creșteri", back: "die Erhöhungen", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "extras de cont", back: "der Kontoauszug", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "extrase de cont", back: "die Kontoauszüge", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "a retrage bani", back: "Geld abheben", lesson: "A2.13" },	{ front: "a retras bani", back: "hat abgehoben", lesson: "A2.13" },
{ front: "sondaj", back: "die Umfrage", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "sondaje", back: "die Umfragen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "abia", back: "kaum", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "viitor", back: "die Zukunft", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "decizie", back: "die Entscheidung", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "decizii", back: "die Entscheidungen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "a muri", back: "sterben", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "a murit", back: "ist gestorben", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "copilărie", back: "die Kindheit", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "copilării", back: "die Kindheiten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "alături (lângă)", back: "nebenan", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "a se îndrăgosti", back: "sich verlieben", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "s-a îndrăgostit", back: "hat sich verliebt", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "prostii, tâmpenii", back: "der Quatsch", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "ucenicie", back: "die Lehre", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "ucenicii", back: "die Lehren", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "întâmplător", back: "zufällig", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "local (restaurant)", back: "das Lokal", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "localuri", back: "die Lokale", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "de când", back: "seitdem", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "unic / singur", back: "einzig-", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "opus, contrariul", back: "das Gegenteil", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "opuse, contrariile", back: "die Gegenteile", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "egal, indiferent", back: "egal", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "ceartă", back: "der Streit", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "certuri", back: "die Streite", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "cuplu", back: "das Paar", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "cupluri", back: "die Paare", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "educație", back: "die Erziehung", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "opinie", back: "die Meinung", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "opinii", back: "die Meinungen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "sfat", back: "der Ratschlag", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "sfaturi", back: "die Ratschläge", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "șoarece", back: "die Maus", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "șoareci", back: "die Mäuse", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "mai degrabă", back: "eher", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "popular", back: "populär", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "fumător", back: "der Raucher", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "fumători", back: "die Raucher", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "fumătoare", back: "die Raucherin", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "fumătoare", back: "die Raucherinnen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "basm", back: "das Märchen", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "basme", back: "die Märchen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "a aborda, a vorbi cu", back: "ansprechen", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "a abordat, a vorbit cu", back: "hat angesprochen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "a mulțumi", back: "danken", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "a mulțumit", back: "hat gedankt", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "idee, gând", back: "der Einfall", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "idei, gânduri", back: "die Einfälle", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "lume", back: "die Welt", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "lumi", back: "die Welten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "animal de companie", back: "das Haustier", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "animale de companie", back: "die Haustiere", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "serios", back: "ernst", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "confortabil", back: "bequem", lesson: "A2.14" },	
{ front: "copilărie", back: "die Kindheit", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "copilării", back: "die Kindheiten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "cuplu", back: "das Paar", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "cupluri", back: "die Paare", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "decizie", back: "die Entscheidung", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "decizii", back: "die Entscheidungen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "sondaj", back: "die Umfrage", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "sondaje", back: "die Umfragen", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "lume", back: "die Welt", lesson: "A2.14" },	{ front: "lumi", back: "die Welten", lesson: "A2.14" },
{ front: "experiență", back: "das Erlebnis", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "experiențe", back: "die Erlebnisse", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "articol", back: "der Artikel", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "a fi", back: "sein", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a fost plecat", back: "sein weg gewesen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "religie", back: "die Religion", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "religii", back: "die Religionen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "surpriză", back: "die Überraschung", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "surprize", back: "die Überraschungen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "nebun", back: "verrückt", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "câștig", back: "der Gewinn", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "câștiguri", back: "die Gewinne", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "impozit", back: "die Steuer", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "voce", back: "die Stimme", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "voci", back: "die Stimmen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a se așeza", back: "sich setzen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "s-a așezat", back: "hat sich gesetzt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "curajos", back: "mutig", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "raport", back: "die Meldung", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "rapoarte", back: "die Meldungen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "titlu", back: "die Überschrift", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "titluri", back: "die Überschriften", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "în timpul", back: "während", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "a dispărea", back: "verschwinden", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a dispărut", back: "ist verschwunden", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "mai mulți", back: "mehrer-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "zadarnic", back: "vergeblich", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "a urca", back: "steigen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a urcat", back: "ist gestiegen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a se mira", back: "sich wundern", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "s-a mirat", back: "hat sich gewundert", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "într-adevăr", back: "zwar", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "curaj", back: "der Mut", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "amândoi", back: "beid-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "a atinge", back: "erreichen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a atins", back: "hat erreicht", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "adânc", back: "tief", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "a confunda", back: "verwechseln", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a confundat", back: "hat verwechselt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "mijloc", back: "das Mittel", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "unit", back: "einig-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "a se afla", back: "sich befinden", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "s-a aflat", back: "hat sich befunden", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a reflecta", back: "nachdenken", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a reflectat", back: "hat nachgedacht", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "informație", back: "die Angabe", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "informații", back: "die Angaben", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a salva", back: "retten", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a salvat", back: "hat gerettet", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a fi suficient", back: "ausreichen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a fost suficient", back: "hat ausgereicht", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "supărare", back: "der Ärger", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "a urma", back: "folgen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a urmat", back: "ist gefolgt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "cel puțin", back: "zumindest", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "a anula", back: "absagen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a anulat", back: "hat abgesagt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a striga", back: "rufen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a strigat", back: "hat gerufen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a bloca", back: "absperren", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a blocat", back: "hat abgesperrt", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a aresta", back: "festnehmen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a arestat", back: "hat festgenommen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "beat", back: "betrunken", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "hoț", back: "der Einbrecher", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "emoționant", back: "aufregend", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "amuzant", back: "witzig", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "scuter", back: "der Motorroller", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "a fi", back: "sein", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a fost îndrăgostit", back: "ist verliebt gewesen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a rupe", back: "brechen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a rupt", back: "ist/hat gebrochen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "antrenor", back: "der Trainer", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "antrenoare", back: "die Trainerin", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "antrenoare", back: "die Trainerinnen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "câmp", back: "das Feld", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "câmpuri", back: "die Felder", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "al tuturor", back: "aller-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "poartă", back: "das Tor", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "porți", back: "die Tore", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a fugi", back: "fliehen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a fugit", back: "ist geflohen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "cel mai bun", back: "best-", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "oficiu de stare civilă", back: "das Standesamt", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "oficii de stare civilă", back: "die Standesämter", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a trage", back: "schießen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a tras", back: "hat geschossen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "pagubă", back: "der Schaden", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "pagube", back: "die Schäden", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "perdea", back: "der Vorhang", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "perdele", back: "die Vorhänge", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "imediat", back: "augenblicklich", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "a mușca", back: "beißen", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "a mușcat", back: "hat gebissen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "a se speria", back: "erschrecken", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "s-a speriat", back: "ist erschrocken", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "contact", back: "der Kontakt", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "contacte", back: "die Kontakte", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "date", back: "die Daten", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "conversație", back: "das Gespräch", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "conversații", back: "die Gespräche", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "raport", back: "der Bericht", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "rapoarte", back: "die Berichte", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "miezul nopții", back: "die Mitternacht", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "piatră", back: "der Stein", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "pietre", back: "die Steine", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "leu", back: "der Löwe", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "lei", back: "die Löwen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "raport", back: "die Meldung", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "rapoarte", back: "die Meldungen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "titlu", back: "die Überschrift", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "titluri", back: "die Überschriften", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "articol", back: "der Artikel", lesson: "B1.1" },	
{ front: "raport", back: "der Bericht", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "rapoarte", back: "die Berichte", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "interviu", back: "das Interview", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "interviuri", back: "die Interviews", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "informație", back: "die Information", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "informații", back: "die Informationen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "anunț", back: "die Anzeige", lesson: "B1.1" },	{ front: "anunțuri", back: "die Anzeigen", lesson: "B1.1" },
{ front: "serial", back: "die Serie", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "seriale", back: "die Serien", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "episodiu", back: "die Folge", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "episoade", back: "die Folgen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "caracter", back: "der Charakter", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "caractere", back: "die Charaktere", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "deși", back: "obwohl", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "continuu", back: "dauernd", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "învins", back: "der Verlierer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "învinși", back: "die Verlierer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "tip", back: "der Typ", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "tipuri", back: "die Typen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "optimist", back: "optimistisch", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "figură", back: "die Figur", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "figuri", back: "die Figuren", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "incredibil", back: "unglaublich", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "a inventa", back: "erfinden", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a inventat", back: "hat erfunden", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "operație", back: "die Operation", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "operații", back: "die Operationen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "sânge", back: "das Blut", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "criminal", back: "Kriminal", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "a publica", back: "veröffentlichen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a publicat", back: "hat veröffentlicht", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "caz", back: "der Fall", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "cazuri", back: "die Fälle", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "vocabular de învățare", back: "der Lernwortschatz", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "de azi", back: "heutig", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "a acționa", back: "handeln", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a acționat", back: "hat gehandelt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "trecut", back: "die Vergangenheit", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "cântăreață", back: "die Sängerin", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "cântărețe", back: "die Sängerinnen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "trupă", back: "die Band", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "trupe", back: "die Bands", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "a apărea", back: "entstehen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a apărut", back: "ist entstanden", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "electronic", back: "elektronisch", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "a produce", back: "produzieren", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a produs", back: "hat produziert", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "metropolă", back: "die Großstadt", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "metropole", back: "die Großstädte", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "între timp", back: "inzwischen", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "la început", back: "anfangs", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "așa-numit", back: "sogenannt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "cântec", back: "der Song", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "cântece", back: "die Songs", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "hit", back: "der Hit", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "hituri", back: "die Hits", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "complet", back: "völlig", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "umor", back: "der Humor", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "cotidian", back: "alltäglich", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "violență", back: "die Gewalt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "a critica", back: "kritisieren", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a criticat", back: "hat kritisiert", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "vedetă", back: "der Star", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "vedete", back: "die Stars", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "scenă", back: "die Szene", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "de succes", back: "erfolgreich", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "a se ocupa", back: "sich beschäftigen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "s-a ocupat", back: "hat sich beschäftigt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "șomaj", back: "die Arbeitslosigkeit", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "depozit", back: "das Lager", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "depozite", back: "die Lager", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "relație", back: "das Verhältnis", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "relații", back: "die Verhältnisse", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "a reuși", back: "gelingen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a reușit", back: "ist gelungen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "sfat", back: "der Rat", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "în final", back: "zuletzt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "a părăsi", back: "verlassen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a părăsit", back: "hat verlassen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "a însoți", back: "begleiten", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a însoțit", back: "hat begleitet", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "cutie", back: "die Kiste", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "cutii", back: "die Kisten", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "mal", back: "das Ufer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "maluri", back: "die Ufer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "a spăla", back: "spülen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a spălat", back: "hat gespült", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "în exterior", back: "außen", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "în interior", back: "innen", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "a întâlni", back: "begegnen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a întâlnit", back: "ist begegnet", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "aventură", back: "das Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "aventuri", back: "die Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "a se îndeplini", back: "sich erfüllen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "s-a îndeplinit", back: "hat sich erfüllt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "pentru asta", back: "dafür", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "a fi de acord", back: "zustimmen", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "a fost de acord", back: "hat zugestimmt", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "media", back: "die Medien", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "media", back: "die Medien", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "radiodifuziune", back: "der Rundfunk", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "aproape", back: "knapp", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "dublu", back: "doppelt", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "relativ", back: "relativ", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "serial", back: "die Serie", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "seriale", back: "die Serien", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "episodiu", back: "die Folge", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "episoade", back: "die Folgen", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "figură", back: "die Figur", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "figuri", back: "die Figuren", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "caracter", back: "der Charakter", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "caractere", back: "die Charaktere", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "criminal", back: "Kriminal", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "radiodifuziune", back: "der Rundfunk", lesson: "B1.2" },	
{ front: "aventură", back: "das Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "aventuri", back: "die Abenteuer", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "cinematograf", back: "das Kino", lesson: "B1.2" },	{ front: "cinematografe", back: "die Kinos", lesson: "B1.2" },
{ front: "stomac", back: "der Magen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "stomacuri", back: "die Mägen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a convinge", back: "überreden", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a convins", back: "hat überredet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a conveni", back: "vereinbaren", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a convenit", back: "hat vereinbart", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "mijloc", back: "das Mittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "mijloace", back: "die Mittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "somn", back: "der Schlaf", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "factor", back: "der Faktor", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "factori", back: "die Faktoren", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "noaptea", back: "nachts", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "bază", back: "die Grundlage", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "baze", back: "die Grundlagen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "suficient", back: "ausreichend", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "a respecta", back: "achten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a respectat", back: "hat geachtet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "grăsime", back: "das Fett", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "grăsimi", back: "die Fette", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "ideal", back: "ideal", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "de asemenea", back: "ebenfalls", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "a respira", back: "atmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a respirat", back: "hat geatmet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "plat", back: "flach", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "efect", back: "die Wirkung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "efecte", back: "die Wirkungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "mai des", back: "öfter", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "putere", back: "die Kraft", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "puteri", back: "die Kräfte", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "simultan", back: "gleichzeitig", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "epuizat", back: "erschöpft", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "rezultat", back: "das Ergebnis", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "rezultate", back: "die Ergebnisse", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a ocoli", back: "umgehen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a ocolit", back: "ist umgegangen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a se trezi", back: "aufwachen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "te-ai trezit", back: "bist aufgewacht", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "lipsă", back: "der Mangel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "lipsuri", back: "die Mängel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "extrem", back: "extrem", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "a măsura", back: "messen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a măsurat", back: "hat gemessen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a slăbi / a scădea", back: "abnehmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a slăbit / a scăzut", back: "hat abgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "greutate", back: "das Gewicht", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "a examina", back: "untersuchen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a examinat", back: "hat untersucht", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "coș de gunoi", back: "der Abfalleimer", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "coșuri de gunoi", back: "die Abfalleimer", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "îmbunătățire", back: "die Verbesserung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "îmbunătățiri", back: "die Verbesserungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "administrare (medicament)", back: "die Einnahme", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "astfel", back: "solch", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "specialist", back: "der Fachmann", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "specialiști", back: "die Fachmänner", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "umăr", back: "die Schulter", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "umeri", back: "die Schultern", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "inițial", back: "zunächst", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "a presupune", back: "vermuten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a presupus", back: "hat vermutet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "tulburare", back: "die Störung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "tulburări", back: "die Störungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "analgezic", back: "das Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "analgezice", back: "die Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a conduce", back: "führen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a condus", back: "hat geführt", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a prescrie", back: "verschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a prescris", back: "hat verschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a primi", back: "erhalten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a primit", back: "hat erhalten", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a scădea", back: "abnehmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a scăzut", back: "hat abgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "bine", back: "das Wohl", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "degeaba", back: "umsonst", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "a participa", back: "teilnehmen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a participat", back: "hat teilgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "performanță", back: "die Leistung", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "performanțe", back: "die Leistungen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a vaccina", back: "impfen", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a vaccinat", back: "hat geimpft", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a practica (sport)", back: "treiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a practicat", back: "hat getrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "jumătate", back: "die Hälfte", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "jumătăți", back: "die Hälften", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "sfert", back: "das Viertel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "sferturi", back: "die Viertel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "treime", back: "das Drittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "treimi", back: "die Drittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "fundamental", back: "grundsätzlich", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "fruct", back: "die Frucht", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "fructe", back: "die Früchte", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a renunța", back: "verzichten", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a renunțat", back: "hat verzichtet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "brânză de vaci", back: "der Quark", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "vitamin", back: "das Vitamin", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "vitamine", back: "die Vitamine", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a raporta boala", back: "krankmelden", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a raportat boala", back: "hat krankgemeldet", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a da concediu medical", back: "krankschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a dat concediu medical", back: "hat krankgeschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "conferință", back: "die Konferenz", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "conferințe", back: "die Konferenzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "blocnotes", back: "der Schreibblock", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "blocnotes", back: "die Schreibblöcke", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "laborator", back: "das Labor", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "laboratoare", back: "die Labors / die Labore", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "bandaj", back: "der Verband", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "bandaje", back: "die Verbände", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "seringă", back: "die Spritze", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "seringi", back: "die Spritzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a examina (pe cineva/ceva)", back: "untersuchen (jemanden/etwas)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a examinat", back: "hat untersucht", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a vaccina (pe cineva)", back: "impfen (jemanden)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a vaccinat", back: "hat geimpft", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "medicament", back: "das Medikament", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "medicamente", back: "die Medikamente", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a prescrie", back: "verschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a prescris", back: "hat verschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "pe cineva", back: "jemanden", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "a da concediu medical", back: "krankschreiben", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a dat concediu medical", back: "hat krankgeschrieben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "seringă", back: "die Spritze", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "seringi", back: "die Spritzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "bandaj", back: "der Verband", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "bandaje", back: "die Verbände", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "analgezic", back: "das Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "analgezice", back: "die Schmerzmittel", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "unguent", back: "die Salbe", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "unguente", back: "die Salben", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "durere", back: "der Schmerz", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "dureri", back: "die Schmerzen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "răceală (nasală)", back: "der Schnupfen", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "a măsura (tensiunea arterială)", back: "messen (den Blutdruck)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a măsurat", back: "hat gemessen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a preleva (sânge)", back: "abnehmen (Blut)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a prelevat", back: "hat abgenommen", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "a verifica (greutatea)", back: "prüfen (das Gewicht)", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "a verificat", back: "hat geprüft", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "burtă", back: "der Bauch", lesson: "B1.3" },	{ front: "burți", back: "die Bäuche", lesson: "B1.3" },
{ front: "febră", back: "das Fieber", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "tuse", back: "der Husten", lesson: "B1.3" },	
{ front: "despre ce / despre care", back: "worüber", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "grabă", back: "die Eile", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "pivniță", back: "der Keller", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "pivnițe", back: "die Keller", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "acolo / deoarece", back: "da", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "propoziție", back: "der Satz", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "propoziții", back: "die Sätze", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "acolo (varianta prescurtată)", back: "da(r)-", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "deloc / chiar", back: "gar", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "oricum / în orice caz", back: "jedenfalls", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "a zâmbi", back: "lächeln", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a zâmbit", back: "hat gelächelt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "pur și simplu / doar", back: "halt", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "clar", back: "deutlich", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "atât de mult", back: "so viel", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "a intenționa", back: "vorhaben", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a intenționat", back: "hat vorgehabt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "adevăr", back: "die Wahrheit", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "adevăruri", back: "die Wahrheiten", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "a minți", back: "lügen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a mințit", back: "hat gelogen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "a termina", back: "beenden", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a terminat", back: "hat beendet", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "loc de ucenicie", back: "der Ausbildungsplatz", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "locuri de ucenicie", back: "die Ausbildungsplätze", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "a alege / a selecta", back: "aussuchen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a ales / a selectat", back: "hat ausgesucht", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "președinte / președintă", back: "der Präsident / die Präsidentin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "președinți / președinte", back: "die Präsidenten / die Präsidentinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "portofel", back: "das Portemonnaie", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "portofele", back: "die Portemonnaies", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "fluent", back: "fließend", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "din cauza asta / de aceea", back: "deswegen", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "cândva", back: "irgendwann", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "a traduce", back: "übersetzen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a tradus", back: "hat übersetzt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "de aceea / prin urmare", back: "daher", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "limba maternă", back: "die Muttersprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "limbi materne", back: "die Muttersprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "pronunție", back: "die Aussprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "de aceea / prin urmare", back: "darum", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "a nota", back: "aufschreiben", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a notat", back: "hat aufgeschrieben", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "expresie", back: "der Ausdruck", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "expresii", back: "die Ausdrücke", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "încă o dată", back: "noch mal", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "mecanic", back: "der Mechaniker", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "mecanici", back: "die Mechaniker", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "mecanică", back: "die Mechanikerin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "mecanice", back: "die Mechanikerinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "repetiție", back: "die Wiederholung", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "repetiții", back: "die Wiederholungen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "cantină", back: "die Mensa", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "cantine", back: "die Mensen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "curs de integrare", back: "der Integrationskurs", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "cursuri de integrare", back: "die Integrationskurse", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "proveniență", back: "die Herkunft", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "proveniențe", back: "die Herkünfte", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "a se ascunde", back: "sich verstecken", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "s-a ascuns", back: "hat sich versteckt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "cool", back: "cool", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "limba greacă", back: "das Griechisch", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "grec", back: "der Grieche", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "greci", back: "die Griechen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "grecoaică", back: "die Griechin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "grecoaice", back: "die Griechinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "dezordonat", back: "durcheinander", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "cel târziu", back: "spätestens", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "a alege", back: "wählen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a ales", back: "hat gewählt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "a proveni", back: "stammen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a provenit", back: "hat gestammt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "sos", back: "die Soße", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "sosuri", back: "die Soßen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "încetul cu încetul", back: "allmählich", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "nerv", back: "der Nerv", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "nervi", back: "die Nerven", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "ciudat", back: "merkwürdig", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "corect", back: "korrekt", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "pe de altă parte", back: "andererseits", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "de asemenea", back: "ebenso", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "frunte", back: "die Stirn", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "frunți", back: "die Stirnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "a suferi", back: "leiden", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a suferit", back: "hat gelitten", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "a amesteca", back: "mischen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a amestecat", back: "hat gemischt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "totuși", back: "allerdings", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "a exista / a promova", back: "bestehen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a existat / a promovat", back: "hat bestanden", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "autor", back: "der Autor", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "autori", back: "die Autoren", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "autoare", back: "die Autorin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "autoare", back: "die Autorinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "cunoștințe", back: "die Kenntnisse", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "cunoștințe", back: "die Kenntnisse", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "a compara", back: "vergleichen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a comparat", back: "hat verglichen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "partener", back: "der Partner", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "parteneri", back: "die Partner", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "parteneră", back: "die Partnerin", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "partenere", back: "die Partnerinnen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "a certa", back: "schimpfen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a certat", back: "hat geschimpft", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "scriere", back: "die Schrift", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "scrieri", back: "die Schriften", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "limba maternă", back: "die Muttersprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "limbi materne", back: "die Muttersprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "limbă străină", back: "die Fremdsprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "limbi străine", back: "die Fremdsprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "școală de limbi", back: "die Sprachenschule", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "școli de limbi", back: "die Sprachenschulen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "pronunție", back: "die Aussprache", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "pronunții", back: "die Aussprachen", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "scriere", back: "die Schrift", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "scrieri", back: "die Schriften", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "fluent", back: "fließend", lesson: "B1.4" },	
{ front: "a traduce", back: "übersetzen", lesson: "B1.4" },	{ front: "a tradus", back: "hat übersetzt", lesson: "B1.4" },
{ front: "către / la", back: "zu", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "talent", back: "das Talent", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "talente", back: "die Talente", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "aproximativ / cam", back: "etwa", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "a fi suficient", back: "genügen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "a fost suficient", back: "hat genügt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "a înceta", back: "aufhören", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "a încetat", back: "hat aufgehört", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "comerț", back: "der Handel", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "avantaj", back: "der Vorteil", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "avantaje", back: "die Vorteile", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "a aștepta", back: "erwarten", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "a așteptat", back: "hat erwartet", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "condiție prealabilă", back: "die Voraussetzung", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "condiții prealabile", back: "die Voraussetzungen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "angajat la serviciu (m)", back: "der Serviceangestellte", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "angajați la serviciu", back: "die Serviceangestellten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "angajată la serviciu (f)", back: "die Serviceangestellte", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "angajate la serviciu", back: "die Serviceangestellten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "documente", back: "die Unterlagen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "documente", back: "die Unterlagen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "sarcină", back: "die Aufgabe", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "sarcini", back: "die Aufgaben", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "sprijin", back: "die Unterstützung", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "sprijinuri", back: "die Unterstützungen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "în scris", back: "schriftlich", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "a constata", back: "feststellen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "a constatat", back: "hat festgestellt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "obișnuit", back: "gewohnt", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "obișnuit / uzual", back: "üblich", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "anexă / instalație", back: "die Anlage", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "anexe / instalații", back: "die Anlagen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "CV / curriculum vitae", back: "der Lebenslauf", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "CV-uri / curricula vitae", back: "die Lebensläufe", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "a dezvolta", back: "entwickeln", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "a dezvoltat", back: "hat entwickelt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "a produce", back: "herstellen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "a produs", back: "hat hergestellt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "activitate", back: "die Tätigkeit", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "activități", back: "die Tätigkeiten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "în afara", back: "außerhalb", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "în interior", back: "innerhalb", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "moment", back: "der Zeitpunkt", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "momente", back: "die Zeitpunkte", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "a calcula", back: "rechnen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "a calculat", back: "hat gerechnet", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "oglindă", back: "der Spiegel", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "oglinzi", back: "die Spiegel", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "a se calma", back: "sich beruhigen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "s-a calmat", back: "hat sich beruhigt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "tehnic", back: "technisch", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "responsabil", back: "zuständig", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "împreună", back: "zusammen-", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "responsabilitate", back: "die Verantwortung", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "pictor", back: "der Maler", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "pictori", back: "die Maler", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "pictoriță", back: "die Malerin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "pictorițe", back: "die Malerinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "comandă", back: "der Auftrag", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "comenzi", back: "die Aufträge", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "traducător", back: "der Übersetzer", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "traducători", back: "die Übersetzer", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "traducătoare", back: "die Übersetzerin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "traducătoare", back: "die Übersetzerinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "a se gândi / a reflecta", back: "sich überlegen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "s-a gândit", back: "hat überlegt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "concurență", back: "die Konkurrenz", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "pe lângă asta / în plus", back: "nebenbei", lesson: "B1.5" },	
{ front: "a lucra temporar", back: "jobben", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "a lucrat temporar", back: "hat gejobbt", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "a se descurca", back: "zurechtkommen", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "s-a descurcat", back: "ist zurechtgekommen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "parc zoologic", back: "der Tierpark", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "parcuri zoologice", back: "die Tierparks", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "perfecționare profesională", back: "die Fortbildung", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "perfecționări profesionale", back: "die Fortbildungen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "a reprezenta", back: "vertreten", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "a reprezentat", back: "hat vertreten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "profesor (m)", back: "der Lehrer", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "profesori", back: "die Lehrer", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "profesoară (f)", back: "die Lehrerin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "profesoare", back: "die Lehrerinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "administrator clădire", back: "der Hausmeister", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "administratori clădiri", back: "die Hausmeister", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "administratoare clădire", back: "die Hausmeisterin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "administratoare clădiri", back: "die Hausmeisterinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "doctor (m)", back: "der Arzt", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "doctori", back: "die Ärzte", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "doctoriță (f)", back: "die Ärztin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "doctorițe", back: "die Ärztinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "arhitect (m)", back: "der Architekt", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "arhitecți", back: "die Architekten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "arhitectă (f)", back: "die Architektin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "arhitecte", back: "die Architektinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "frizer (m)", back: "der Friseur", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "frizeri", back: "die Friseure", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "frizeriță (f)", back: "die Friseurin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "frizerițe", back: "die Friseurinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "jurnalist (m)", back: "der Journalist", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "jurnaliști", back: "die Journalisten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "asistent medical (m)", back: "der Krankenpfleger", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "asistenți medicali", back: "die Krankenpfleger", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "jurnalistă (f)", back: "die Journalistin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "jurnaliste", back: "die Journalistinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "asistentă medicală (f)", back: "die Krankenschwester", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "asistente medicale", back: "die Krankenschwestern", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "polițist (m)", back: "der Polizist", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "polițiști", back: "die Polizisten", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "polițistă (f)", back: "die Polizistin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "polițiste", back: "die Polizistinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "vânzător (m)", back: "der Verkäufer", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "vânzători", back: "die Verkäufer", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "vânzătoare (f)", back: "die Verkäuferin", lesson: "B1.5" },	{ front: "vânzătoare", back: "die Verkäuferinnen", lesson: "B1.5" },
{ front: "în loc de", back: "statt", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "inițial / primul", back: "erst-", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "producție", back: "die Produktion", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "producții", back: "die Produktionen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "înlocuire / substitut", back: "der Ersatz", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "sigur / determinat", back: "bestimmt", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "a rezolva", back: "lösen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a rezolvat", back: "hat gelöst", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "secret", back: "das Geheimnis", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "secrete", back: "die Geheimnisse", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "risc", back: "das Risiko", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "riscuri", back: "die Risiken", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "schimbare", back: "die Änderung", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "schimbări", back: "die Änderungen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "sens", back: "der Sinn", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "a merita", back: "sich lohnen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a meritat", back: "hat gelohnt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "anotimp", back: "die Jahreszeit", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "anotimpuri", back: "die Jahreszeiten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a poseda", back: "besitzen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a posedat", back: "hat besessen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a se naște", back: "geboren werden", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "s-a născut", back: "ist geboren worden", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a se hotărî", back: "sich entschließen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "s-a hotărât", back: "hat entschlossen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "dor de casă", back: "das Heimweh", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "competiție", back: "der Wettbewerb", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "competiții", back: "die Wettbewerbe", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "condiment", back: "das Gewürz", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "condimente", back: "die Gewürze", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "între timp", back: "mittlerweile", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "considerație", back: "die Rücksicht", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "considerații", back: "die Rücksichten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "intercultural", back: "interkulturell", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "a întemeia / a fondea", back: "gründen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a întemeiat / a fondat", back: "hat gegründet", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a îngriji / a supraveghea", back: "betreuen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a îngrijit / a supravegheat", back: "hat betreut", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a se obișnui", back: "sich gewöhnen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "s-a obișnuit", back: "hat gewöhnt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a îngriji", back: "pflegen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a îngrijit", back: "hat gepflegt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "ani de zile", back: "jahrelang", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "negustor / comerciant (m)", back: "der Kaufmann", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "negustori / comercianți", back: "die Kaufleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "negustoreasă / comerciantă (f)", back: "die Kauffrau", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "negustorese / comerciante", back: "die Kauffrauen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "experiment", back: "das Experiment", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "experimente", back: "die Experimente", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "financiar", back: "finanziell", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "oameni de afaceri", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "oameni de afaceri", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "exclusiv", back: "ausschließlich", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "ingredient", back: "die Zutat", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "ingrediente", back: "die Zutaten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "cel mult", back: "höchstens", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "studio", back: "das Studio", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "studiouri", back: "die Studios", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "pentru a", back: "um … zu", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "cât mai …", back: "möglichst", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "discurs", back: "die Rede", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "discursuri", back: "die Reden", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "compromis", back: "der Kompromiss", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "compromisuri", back: "die Kompromisse", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "aer condiționat", back: "die Klimaanlage", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "aer condiționat (pl.)", back: "die Klimaanlagen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "software", back: "die Software", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "softuri", back: "die Softwares", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a reveni", back: "wiederkommen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a revenit", back: "ist wiedergekommen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "efort", back: "die Mühe", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "eforturi", back: "die Mühen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "pastă de dinți", back: "die Zahncreme", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "paste de dinți", back: "die Zahncremes", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "detergent", back: "das Waschmittel", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "perie", back: "die Bürste", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "perii", back: "die Bürsten", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a saluta", back: "begrüßen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a salutat", back: "hat begrüßt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a lua rămas bun", back: "sich verabschieden", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a luat rămas bun", back: "hat verabschiedet", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "rol", back: "die Rolle", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "roluri", back: "die Rollen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "pretenție / cerere", back: "der Anspruch", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "pretenții / cereri", back: "die Ansprüche", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a confirma", back: "bestätigen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a confirmat", back: "hat bestätigt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "copie", back: "die Kopie", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "copii", back: "die Kopien", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a deteriora", back: "beschädigen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a deteriorat", back: "hat beschädigt", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "enervant / supărător", back: "ärgerlich", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "manual de utilizare", back: "die Bedienungsanleitung", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "manuale de utilizare", back: "die Bedienungsanleitungen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a schimba (în magazin)", back: "umtauschen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a schimbat (în magazin)", back: "hat umgetauscht", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "totuși", back: "jedoch", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "deja", back: "bereits", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "a cere / a solicita", back: "fordern", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a cerut / a solicitat", back: "hat gefordert", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a dezamăgi", back: "enttäuschen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a dezamăgit", back: "hat enttäuscht", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a solicita / a invita", back: "auffordern", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a solicitat / a invitat", back: "hat aufgefordert", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "întreprindere / firmă", back: "der Betrieb", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "întreprinderi / firme", back: "die Betriebe", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "firmă", back: "die Firma", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "firme", back: "die Firmen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "producție", back: "die Produktion", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "producții", back: "die Produktionen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "comerț", back: "der Handel", lesson: "B1.6" },	
{ front: "risc", back: "das Risiko", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "riscuri", back: "die Risiken", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "oameni de afaceri", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "oameni de afaceri", back: "die Geschäftsleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "negustor / comerciant (m)", back: "der Kaufmann", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "negustori / comercianți", back: "die Kaufleute", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "negustoreasă / comerciantă (f)", back: "die Kauffrau", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "negustorese / comerciante", back: "die Kauffrauen", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "a întemeia / a fondea", back: "gründen", lesson: "B1.6" },	{ front: "a întemeiat / a fondat", back: "hat gegründet", lesson: "B1.6" },
{ front: "instanță / tribunal", back: "das Gericht", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "instanțe", back: "die Gerichte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "proces", back: "der Prozess", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "procese", back: "die Prozesse", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "a arde", back: "brennen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "a ars", back: "hat gebrannt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "zgomot", back: "der Lärm", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "avocat", back: "der Rechtsanwalt", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "avocați", back: "die Rechtsanwälte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "avocată", back: "die Rechtsanwältin", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "avocate", back: "die Rechtsanwältinnen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "teren / proprietate", back: "das Grundstück", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "terenuri / proprietăți", back: "die Grundstücke", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "a suspecta", back: "verdächtigen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "a suspectat", back: "hat verdächtigt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "pace", back: "der Frieden", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "realitate", back: "die Wirklichkeit", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "realități", back: "die Wirklichkeiten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "gazon", back: "der Rasen", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "land federal / land de stat", back: "das Bundesland", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "landuri federale", back: "die Bundesländer", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "unul pe altul / reciproc", back: "-einander", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "avocat", back: "der Anwalt", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "avocați", back: "die Anwälte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "avocată", back: "die Anwältin", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "avocate", back: "die Anwältinnen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "fie … fie", back: "entweder … oder", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "central", back: "zentral", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "obligație", back: "die Pflicht", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "obligații", back: "die Pflichten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "proprietate", back: "das Eigentum", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "proprietari", back: "die Eigentümer", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "a țipa", back: "schreien", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "a țipat", back: "hat geschrien", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "împreună", back: "miteinander", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "gumă de șters", back: "der Radiergummi", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "gume de șters", back: "die Radiergummis", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "creion", back: "der Bleistift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "creioane", back: "die Bleistifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "creion colorat", back: "der Farbstift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "creioane colorate", back: "die Farbstifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "a descoperi", back: "entdecken", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "a descoperit", back: "hat entdeckt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "furios / mânios", back: "wütend", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "puzzle", back: "das Puzzle", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "puzzle-uri", back: "die Puzzles", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "interdicție", back: "das Verbot", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "interdicții", back: "die Verbote", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "doar / numai", back: "bloß", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "aici / spre aici", back: "hierher", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "atent", back: "aufmerksam", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "a stabili / a conveni", back: "abmachen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "a stabilit / a convenit", back: "hat abgemacht", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "de fapt / în realitate", back: "tatsächlich", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "obraznicie / nesimțire", back: "die Frechheit", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "obraznicii / nesimțiri", back: "die Frechheiten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "din punctul meu de vedere / dacă vrei", back: "meinetwegen", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "a aborda / a începe", back: "angehen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "a abordat / a început", back: "ist angegangen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "lift / ascensor", back: "der Lift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "lifturi / ascensoare", back: "die Lifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "terasă", back: "die Terrasse", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "terase", back: "die Terrassen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "orice / oricare", back: "irgend-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "centru oraș / zonă centrală", back: "die Innenstadt", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "centre oraș", back: "die Innenstädte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "stradă transversală", back: "die Querstraße", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "străzi transversale", back: "die Querstraßen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "esențial / semnificativ", back: "wesentlich", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "alternativă", back: "die Alternative", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "alternative", back: "die Alternativen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "margine", back: "der Rand", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "margini", back: "die Ränder", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "link / legătură", back: "der Link", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "linkuri", back: "die Links", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "unde / (prefix relativ)", back: "wo(r)-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "a lipsi", back: "fehlen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "a lipsit", back: "hat gefehlt", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "stat", back: "der Staat", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "state", back: "die Staaten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "de est / estic", back: "Ost-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "de vest / vestic", back: "West-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "zid / perete", back: "die Mauer", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "ziduri / pereți", back: "die Mauern", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "guvern", back: "die Regierung", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "guverne", back: "die Regierungen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "a domni / a conduce", back: "herrschen", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "a domnit / a condus", back: "hat geherrscht", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "treaptă / etapă", back: "die Stufe", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "trepte / etape", back: "die Stufen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "în mijloc / direct", back: "mitten", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "unghiular / colțuros", back: "eckig", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "nordic / situat la nord", back: "nördlich", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "pământ / lume", back: "die Erde", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "lumi / pământuri", back: "die Erden", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "șansă", back: "die Chance", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "șanse", back: "die Chancen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "a mări / a extinde", back: "vergrößern", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "a mărit / a extins", back: "hat vergrößert", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "de mult / demult", back: "längst", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "în ciuda", back: "trotz", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "construcție / edificiu", back: "der Bau", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "construcții / edificii", back: "die Bauten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "autorizație / permisiune", back: "die Genehmigung", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "autorizații / permisiuni", back: "die Genehmigungen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "turism", back: "der Tourismus", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "egal / asemănător", back: "gleich-", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "clădire", back: "das Gebäude", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "acoperiș / tetă", back: "das Dach", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "acoperișuri", back: "die Dächer", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "casă", back: "das Haus", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "case", back: "die Häuser", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "scară", back: "die Treppe", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "scări", back: "die Treppen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "ușă", back: "die Tür", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "uși", back: "die Türen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "fereastră", back: "das Fenster", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "grădină", back: "der Garten", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "grădini", back: "die Gärten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "balcon", back: "der Balkon", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "balcoane", back: "die Balkone", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "fereastră", back: "das Fenster", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "pivniță / subsol", back: "der Keller", lesson: "B1.7" },	
{ front: "lift / ascensor", back: "der Lift", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "lifturi / ascensoare", back: "die Lifte", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "terasă", back: "die Terrasse", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "terase", back: "die Terrassen", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "grădină", back: "der Garten", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "grădini", back: "die Gärten", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "balcon", back: "der Balkon", lesson: "B1.7" },	{ front: "balcoane", back: "die Balkone", lesson: "B1.7" },
{ front: "gazon", back: "der Rasen", lesson: "B1.7" }
 ]
}
